<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804037" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SOCCER-SOUTH AFRICA QUALIFY FOR WORLD CUP FINALS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SOUTH AFRICA QUALIFY FOR WORLD CUP FINALS.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>An early goal from striker Phil Masinga secured South Africa a 1-0 win over Congo on Saturday and a place in next year's World Cup finals.</p>
<p>South Africa needed only to draw to retain top place in group three but Masinga's rasping shot from the edge of the box in the 14th minute made doubly sure for the African champions.</p>
<p>It was a lucky 13th goal in international football for the Italian-based striker but an even bigger achievement for the team, playing only their 52nd international since returning to world soccer after almost 30 years of apartheid-enforced isolation.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a day for all South Africans,&quot; said coach Clive Barker after a tight match in which the Congolese had much of the midfield possession but failed to score the goals they needed to win the group.</p>
<p>&quot;We dedicate this match to all the players of the past who were denied the opportunity to play international football,&quot; an emotional Barker said.</p>
<p>More than 90,000 packed into the 75,000-seater Soccer City stadium for the match, which had been sold-out in midweek.</p>
<p>The result set off a flurry of country-wide celebration, rivalling the scenes after the rugby union team won the World Cup two years ago.</p>
<p>The goal came after a stray pass from Congolese defender Florent Baloki was intercepted by Doctor Khumalo, whose pass set Masinga up for a thundering shot.</p>
<p>But there were many anxious moments for a deafening crowd as Congo responded valiantly but created few clear-cut chances.</p>
<p>&quot;It wasn't a pretty match and we didn't play well, but we are through,&quot; said captain Lucas Radebe, based in England with Leeds United.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>South Africa: 1-Andre Arendse; 2-Sizwe Motaung, 5-Mark Fish, 19-Lucas Radebe, 9-Neil Tovey; 21-Eric Tinkler, 15-Doctor Khumalo, 10-John Moshoeu, 11-Helman Mkhalele (18-John Moeti 56th minute); 17-Shaun Bartlett (14-Mark Williams 60th), 6-Phil Masinga (12-Brendan Augustine 75th min).</p>
<p>Congo: 1-Brice Samba; 2-Brice Mokossi (8-Roch Embingou 46th), 18-Lucien-Fils Ibarra, 9-Roland Buitys, 13-Florent Baloki, 15-Elie Roch Malonga, 4-Jean-Sylvestre Nkeoua, 7-Eric Bantsimba, 14-Rolf Nguie-Mien (6-Olivier Niere 76th), 12-Macchembes Mouhani-ounga, 17-Richard Akiana (11-Charles Imboula 66th).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
