<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804051" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS - BJORKMAN, MOYA MOVE INTO INDIANAPOLIS FINAL.</title>
<headline>TENNIS - BJORKMAN, MOYA MOVE INTO INDIANAPOLIS FINAL.</headline>
<dateline>INDIANAPOLIS 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fatigue played a major role on Saturday as Swede Jonas Bjorkman and Carlos Moya of Spain won semifinal matches in the $1 million RCA Championships against exhausted opponents.</p>
<p>Bjorkman earned his third trophy match of the year as he crushed worn-out Australian Mark Woodforde 6-0 6-2. Woodforde, 31 and the oldest man in the tournament field, didn't have the legs to compete after reaching both singles and doubles semifinals this week.</p>
<p>It was a similar story for fifth-seeded Moya, the Australian Open finals loser to Pete Sampras. The Spaniard needed just 62 minutes to dispatch 10th seeded Wayne Ferreira of South Africa 6-4 6-2.</p>
<p>Ferreira, the 1994 holder, didn't get to bed until after midnight on Friday after winning a third-set tiebreaker against Swede Magnus Larsson 12-10.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't have enough energy to compete,&quot; said Ferreira. &quot;I was more tired mentally than physically. But having to be here so early to play isn't fair. Both myself and Mark struggled because of the scheduling.&quot;</p>
<p>Bjorkman, seeded ninth, will be aiming for this second career crown when he takes on Moya for a $US 150,000 prize on Sunday.</p>
<p>Moya holds a 2-0 lead in the series, having beaten the Swede in 1996 indoors in Marseille and in a five-setter in the fourth round at the Australian Open in January.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm the dark horse in this final,&quot; said Bjorkman, who will rise on Monday into the ATP Tour ranking Top 20 for the first time. &quot;I'm very confident. Getting to that ranking has been one of my goals for the past few months.</p>
<p>&quot;Moya has been improving a lot. I've not been in the position of being a favorite very much.&quot;</p>
<p>Woodforde missed out on the chance to defeat his fourth seeded opponent of the week after knocking out American Chris Woodruff, Chile's Marcelo Rios and crowd-pleaser Andre Agassi.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a struggle to even finish some of my service games,&quot; admitted Woodforde. &quot;I lost a lot of motion just from being tired in my shoulders and my legs. It was tough last night playing the doubles (which he and Todd Woodbridge won).&quot;</p>
<p>Ferreira and Moya traded two breaks in the first three games to get the match back on serve.</p>
<p>The Mallorca-born player, sporting short hair in contrast to his trademark flowing locks after serving for five days in the Spanish military reserve this summer, got up a break against and held the margin to win the opening set in 40 minutes.</p>
<p>Moya broke to begins the second set and controlled the momentum, at one point winning eight of 10 games. &quot;I tried not to let Wayne into the first set,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm having more fun with my tennis now,&quot; said Moya. &quot;Even after the Australian Open it was not as good for me as it was now. My serve and forehand were both working well. I'm happy to be playing the final here.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="INDIANAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
