<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804034" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: TENNIS-SELES WINS 6-0 6-0 TO REACH CANADIAN OPEN SEMIS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SELES WINS 6-0 6-0 TO REACH CANADIAN OPEN SEMIS.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top-seeded Monica Seles outclassed unseeded qualifier Rita Grande of Italy 6-0 6-0 Friday in the quarter-finals of the $926,250 Canadian Open.</p>
<p>&quot;I hit some great shots that even surprised myself,&quot; the third-ranked Seles said after her 42-minute win over the 69th-ranked Grande.</p>
<p>Seles will now play seventh-seeded Conchita Martinez of Spain in Saturday's afternoon semifinal. Martinez advanced with her sixth consecutive win over fourth-seeded Lindsay Davenport, beating the American 6-4 4-6 6-2. The evening semifinal will match fifth-seeded Anke Huber of Germany and 10th-seeded American Mary Joe Fernandez. Huber edged third-seeded Amanda Coetzer of South Africa 2-6 6-1 6-4 while Fernandez prevailed 6-2 6-7 (3-7) 6-4 over unseeded Magdalena Maleeva of Bulgaria.</p>
<p>&quot;I think she had a big win yesterday (over sixth-seeded Mary Pierce of France),&quot; Seles said about Grande, &quot;and it's always hard to come back and play after that.&quot;</p>
<p>Grande saw the humour in the onesided match, smiling and throwing up her hands to show how futile things were against an on-form Seles.</p>
<p>Would Seles ever give a player a game when she is winning by such a onesided margin?</p>
<p>&quot;I just take it point by point,&quot; she answered. &quot;I forget where I was three or four weeks ago but I was winning 6-0 4-0 and I lost a game and the crowd started to clap because they thought I was being nice and giving a game. But I'd never give a game and I don't expect anyone to give me a game in that situation.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;She's very frustrating for me to play,&quot; Davenport said about her sixth straight loss to the ninth-ranked Martinez. &quot;She puts a lot of topspin on her forehand and a lot of slice on her backhand.&quot;</p>
<p>The match was interrupted by heavy downpours for over four hours with Davenport leading 5-4 in the second set. &quot;In the third set, I was a lot more impatient and I made a lot of unforced errors,&quot; the fifth-ranked Davenport said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the last couple of times I got killed (6-1 6-3 and 6-2 6-3) by her so at least I played the right way, aggressively. Maybe the next time it'll be different.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Lindsay played unbelievable in the second set,&quot; Martinez said. &quot;When she hits winners there's not much you can do. But after that I tried to be more aggressive.&quot;</p>
<p>Seles and Martinez have played 12 times, and not once has a match gone three sets. The 23-year-old Seles won the first 11 with Martinez breaking the ice with a 7-6 6-4 victory in Palo Alto, California, three weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very confident now and I feel I'm at my best,&quot; Martinez said.</p>
<p>The 25-year-old Spaniard has been working with a new athletic trainer since March and has lost a considerable amount of weight. She would not reveal the amount but did say she now weighs 135 pounds (61 kg).</p>
<p>&quot;When you're weight is up, you don't go to the scales very often,&quot; she said with a smile. &quot;Now, I'm going every day.&quot;</p>
<p>The eighth-ranked Huber and the sixth-ranked Coetzer waged tough baseline battle on Court Number One after it was relocated from centre court by the rain.</p>
<p>&quot;I was impatient in the first set, and very disappointed in myself,&quot; Huber said. &quot;It was hard to win a point from the baseline against Amanda because she hits with a lot of topspin, and it was very humid and the balls really fluffed up. I had to be patient and be willing to hit 20 balls every rally.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
