<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804081" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Model says Dodi made love to her, romanced Diana.</title>
<headline>Model says Dodi made love to her, romanced Diana.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jilted model Kelly Fisher has claimed millionaire Dodi Al Fayed made love to her by night while romancing Britain's Princess Diana by day.</p>
<p>In early editions of Britain's top-selling Sunday newspaper the News of the World, the 30-year-old American alleged the Egyptian playboy shuttled between her and Diana on a recent Mediterranean holiday.</p>
<p>Fisher said Al Fayed, 41, told her he wanted her to have his baby during passionate moments on a yacht across the bay from the yacht where the princess was staying.</p>
<p>&quot;I was blissfully unaware that the man trying to father my child was setting his sights on Diana,&quot; Fisher, who now plans to sue Al Fayed for breach of promise, was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Fisher told the newspaper that on the mornings after their lovemaking, Al Fayed -- whose father Mohamed owns London's upmarket Harrods department store -- would disappear.</p>
<p>&quot;He'd reappear more than four or five hours later without explanation -- other than that his father needed him. I now know that it was at that time he was romancing Diana,&quot; Fisher said.</p>
<p>British media have indulged in frenzied speculation about a new romance for Diana, ex-wife of heir to the throne Prince Charles, after the publication of fuzzy photographs apparently showing her kissing Al Fayed aboard his father's luxury yacht.</p>
<p>Fisher said she believed Al Fayed wanted to retain her as a lover even if he succeeded in wooing the princess.</p>
<p>&quot;He did not want to end it with me, nor had he any intention of giving up whatever he has with the Princess of Wales. The truth is he wanted us both,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;I was to be his secret sexual relationship -- I believe it is called his 'bit on the side'. It was absolutely repugnant to me.&quot;</p>
<p>Diana flew to Greece on Saturday with a female friend for her third Mediterranean holiday in two months. Her two sons, Princes William and Harry, are with their father on the royal family's vast Balmoral estate in Scotland.</p>
<p>Prince Charles invited cameramen to photograph himself and his teenage sons clambering over rocks near a waterfall, the second &quot;photo opportunity&quot; he has offered in recent days.</p>
<p>Royal aides said the intention was to prevent photographers from spoiling the rest of the family holiday. &quot;We want to work with the media. We will come halfway if you leave them alone,&quot; said the prince's press spokesman Sandy Henney.</p>
<p>The pictures of Charles in a green kilt and the young princes more informally dressed seemed tame compared with those of his ex-wife which were splashed across newspapers last week.</p>
<p>The Sunday Times reported that the prince had gone out of his way to sympathise with another prominent Briton whose marriage is on the rocks -- Foreign Secretary Robin Cook.</p>
<p>It said Charles had written to Cook expressing sympathy at media exposure of his break-up with his wife Margaret after an affair with his parliamentary secretary Gaynor Regan, 10 years his junior.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
