<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804055" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-MATT WILLIAMS SINGLES IN WINNING RUN IN 10TH.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-MATT WILLIAMS SINGLES IN WINNING RUN IN 10TH.</headline>
<dateline>CLEVELAND 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Matt Williams had an apparent</p>
<p>homer taken away in the sixth inning but had the last laugh</p>
<p>when he blooped home the winning run in the bottom of the 10th</p>
<p>to give the Cleveland Indians their third straight victory,</p>
<p>5-4 over the Toronto Blue Jays Friday.</p>
<p>The Indians, who blew a two-run ninth-inning lead, rallied</p>
<p>in the 10th against Tim Crabtree (2-3). Omar Vizquel led off</p>
<p>with a hustling bloop double and took third on a grounder.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw the ball hit on the line and I said to myself,</p>
<p>Don't stop, don't even stop, give it a shot and see if I could</p>
<p>get to second base,&quot; Vizquel said.</p>
<p>Jim Thome and David Justice were intentionally walked to</p>
<p>load the bases and the Jays brought in their infield before</p>
<p>Williams sent an 0-2 pitch into short left to score Vizquel.</p>
<p>&quot;I just wanted to get it in the air and over the infield,&quot;</p>
<p>said Williams. &quot;I swung through the first pitch and he gave me</p>
<p>a good one to hit on the second one, but I hit a foul ball.</p>
<p>The hit was just a wedge shot.&quot;</p>
<p>In the sixth, Williams hit a liner down the left-field</p>
<p>line that was called a two-run homer by third-base umpire Dave</p>
<p>Phillips. Toronto manager Cito Gaston argued with plate umpire</p>
<p>Durwood Merrill, who conferred with Phillips and ruled a foul</p>
<p>ball. Cleveland manager Mike Hargrove argued and was ejected.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't see it,&quot; Williams said. &quot;When I hit first base,</p>
<p>I saw the umpire signal fair ball. When Cito came out of the</p>
<p>dugout, I knew something was amiss. The longer that went on, I</p>
<p>pretty much figured it was foul.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It was a good call by Durwood Merrill,&quot; Gaston said. &quot;It</p>
<p>was the right thing for Phillips to do, to go down and ask</p>
<p>Merrill and get the call right.&quot;</p>
<p>Paul Assenmacher (4-0) allowed one hit in the 10th but got</p>
<p>the win. Jose Mesa lost a 4-2 lead in the ninth, his fourth</p>
<p>blown save in nine chances.</p>
<p>Thome, Jeff Branson and Brian Giles homered for Cleveland.</p>
<p>In Baltimore, the Orioles and Mariners split a</p>
<p>doubleheader, Seattle losing with ace Randy Johnson pitching</p>
<p>but then winning with a rookie.</p>
<p>Johnson (16-4) allowed homers by Jeff Reboulet and Jeffrey</p>
<p>Hammonds to lose the opener 4-3. Scott Kamieniecki (8-5)</p>
<p>allowed one run in seven innings as he won for just the second</p>
<p>time in his last eight starts.</p>
<p>Coming off a five-hitter with 19 strikeouts against the</p>
<p>White Sox, Johnson pitched a four-hitter for his fifth</p>
<p>complete game and struck out 13 against three walks. Johnson</p>
<p>is 1-5 lifetime in Baltimore.</p>
<p>Johnson tied the major-league mark for strikeouts in</p>
<p>consecutive games, set by Cleveland's Luis Tiant in 1968 and</p>
<p>matched by California'a Nolan Ryan in 1974 and the Mets'</p>
<p>Dwight Gooden in 1984.</p>
<p>In the nightcap, Baltimore native Ken Cloude allowed two</p>
<p>hits over six innings in his second major-league start and Ken</p>
<p>Griffey Jr, Jay Buhner and Alex Rodriguez homered as the</p>
<p>Mariners beat the Orioles 8-3.</p>
<p>Cloude (1-1), a 22-year-old right-hander who flirted with</p>
<p>a no-hitter before losing his major-league debut last week,</p>
<p>gave up two runs, striking out two and walking six.</p>
<p>In New York, Dwight Gooden pitched six solid innings and</p>
<p>Bernie Williams broke out of a slump with two hits and two RBI</p>
<p>as the Yankees rolled to a 5-2 victory over the Texas Rangers,</p>
<p>who had their four-game winning streak snapped.</p>
<p>Gooden (6-4) rebounded from his worst outing of the season</p>
<p>to win for the third time in four decisions. He gave up two</p>
<p>runs and four hits.</p>
<p>The Yankees have won three straight, six of their last</p>
<p>seven and 14 of 18 to move within 3 1/2 games of first-place</p>
<p>Baltimore in the American League East.</p>
<p>In Milwaukee, Chuck Finley allowed three runs over seven</p>
<p>innings to tie a franchise record with his 10th straight</p>
<p>victory as the Anaheim Angels moved back into first place in</p>
<p>the A.L. West with a 5-3 victory over the Brewers.</p>
<p>Finley (13-6) scattered eight singles.</p>
<p>Newly acquired Rickey Henderson had a single, three walks,</p>
<p>a stolen base and two runs scored for Anaheim, which moved</p>
<p>one-half game ahead of Seattle.</p>
<p>In Boston, Reggie Jefferson singled home pinch-runner Mike</p>
<p>Benjamin in the bottom of the 10th as the Red Sox dealt the</p>
<p>Minnesota Twins their seventh straight loss, 5-4.</p>
<p>Jim Corsi squandered a two-run lead in the top of the</p>
<p>ninth as the Boston bullpen suffered its 19th blown save in 47</p>
<p>chances.</p>
<p>But Mo Vaughn led off the bottom half with a double off</p>
<p>the &quot;Green Monster&quot; in left field to revive Boston hopes.</p>
<p>Jefferson, just 9-for-44 against left-handers this season,</p>
<p>fouled off two pitches from southpaw Eddie Guardado (0-4)</p>
<p>before singling to center for the game-winner.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Jimmy Haynes allowed four runs over five</p>
<p>innings but benefited from Matt Stairs' three-run homer and a</p>
<p>14-hit attack as the Oakland Athletics cruised to their third</p>
<p>straight win, 11-6 over the White Sox.</p>
<p>In Detroit, Bip Roberts had a two-run single as the Kansas</p>
<p>City Royals scored four unearned runs in the second en route</p>
<p>to a 5-3 victory over the Tigers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CLEVELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
