<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804082" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Pakistani leaders pay tribute to dead singer.</title>
<headline>Pakistani leaders pay tribute to dead singer.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's top classical singer Nusrat Fateh Ali Khan, who mixed traditional mystic music with modern fast beats, died on Saturday in a London hospital, a close British friend said.</p>
<p>Iftikhar Quaisar said Nusrat, 49, died of cardiac arrest after being admitted to hospital a few days earlier suffering from hepatitis.</p>
<p>Pakistan's official APP news agency said the singer was taken to hospital after he suffered &quot;complication of renal failure due to diabetes&quot;. He had left Pakistan for the United States last week for a kidney transplant but stopped over for a few days in London, where his condition deteriorated, APP reported.</p>
<p>Pakistan's President Farooq Leghari and Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif issued condolence statements, calling the singer's death a national loss, according to state television.</p>
<p>Nusrat's body is to be flown back to Pakistan on Sunday for burial, APP said.</p>
<p>The scion of a family known for its attachment to classical music, Nusrat popularised the region's traditional mystic &quot;Qawali&quot; form of music and semi-classical Pakistani music in the West by mixing it with popular modern fast beats.</p>
<p>He composed music for several foreign films, including Hollywood's &quot;Last Temptation of Christ&quot; and India's controversial Hindi film &quot;Bandit Queen&quot;.</p>
<p>Nusrat received France's FNAC award for music, Japan's Fukuoka award and Pakistan's Prime of Performance.</p>
<p>His family had migrated to Pakistan from the town of Jullundur in India's Punjab state at Partition in 1947.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
