<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804027" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-CELTIC CRASH TO HOME DEFEAT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CELTIC CRASH TO HOME DEFEAT.</headline>
<dateline>GLASGOW 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Celtic's disastrous start to the season continued at home on Saturday as they crashed to a 2-1 Scottish premier division defeat to Dunfermline.</p>
<p>Newly-promoted St Johnstone are the early table-toppers after winning 1-0 at Motherwell while the day's only other game saw Hearts beat Aberdeen 4-1. Dundee United play Hibs on Sunday while Rangers' game against Kilmarnock was postponed because of international calls.</p>
<p>Celtic, desperate to prevent Rangers eclipsing their record of nine successive titles, began the season with a 2-1 defeat at Hibernian last week and followed up by losing 2-1 to Austria Tirol in the UEFA Cup in midweek.</p>
<p>Things looked to be improving on Saturday when they went ahead in the 40th minute with an Andreas Thom penalty after Henrik Larsson was fouled by Hamish French.</p>
<p>But the lead lasted just a minute into the second half before David Bingham equalised.</p>
<p>And French fully made amends for his misdemeanour 13 minutes from time by hitting the winner from the spot after Malky Mackay had felled Allan Moore in the box.</p>
<p>The result left Celtic bottom of the premier division and Rangers' pre-season odds of 1-6 to win their 10th successive title are already looking generous.</p>
<p>&quot;We always felt pretty confident we could get a result here,&quot; said Dunfermline coach Bert Paton.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a new-look Celtic side and we didn't really know what to expect but I think that worked in our favour as it can take some time for a new side to settle down.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got some quality players and in the second half they showed that and I can't praise them highly enough,&quot; Paton added.</p>
<p>Hearts hit three goals in six minutes to come from behind and beat Aberdeen at Tynecastle.</p>
<p>Aberdeen went ahead through Mike Newell after 12 minutes but Hearts turned the game round before half time.</p>
<p>A John Robertson penalty levelled the match in the 36th minute, Steve Fulton made it 2-1 two minutes later and Colin Cameron got the third after a further four minutes.</p>
<p>Thomas Flogel completed the rout in the last minute.</p>
<p>Roddy Grant scored the only goal at Motherwell after 65 minutes to put St Johnstone top of the league with four points from two games.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GLASGOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
