<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804086" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - August 23.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - August 23.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some major events to have occurred on August 23 in history.</p>
<p>1305 - William Wallace, Scottish patriot and a leader of the struggle against the English, was hanged, disembowelled, beheaded and quartered in London.</p>
<p>1628 - The 1st Duke of Buckingham, influential but unpopular English statesman, was assassinated at Portsmouth.</p>
<p>1754 - Louis XVI of France born. He ascended the throne in 1774, the last monarch in a line cut short by the 1789 revolution. After declaration of a republic, Louis was guillotined on January 21, 1793.</p>
<p>1785 - Oliver Hazard Perry, U.S. naval officer, born. He became a national hero when he defeated a British squadron in the Battle of Lake Erie during the War of 1812.</p>
<p>1813 - During the Napoleonic Wars, a Prussian force drove back the French at the Battle of Grossbeeren.</p>
<p>1821 - Mexico was declared independent of Spain by the Treaty of Aquala.</p>
<p>1864 - Eleutherios Venizelos, Greek statesman and diplomat, born. He was prime minister five times between 1910 and 1933.</p>
<p>1866 - The Treaty of Prague formally ended the Seven Weeks' War between Austria and Prussian-led German states.</p>
<p>1883 - Jonathan Wainwright, U.S. Army general, born. He was defender of Corregidor and Bataan in the Philippines against Japanese attack during World War Two.</p>
<p>1912 - Gene Kelly, U.S. film actor, choreographer and dancer, born. Starred in films such as &quot;Anchors Aweigh&quot;, &quot;On the Town&quot;, and &quot;Singin' in the Rain&quot;.</p>
<p>1914 - Japan declared war on Germany. On the European battlefield, German troops executed over 600 people in the Belgian town of Dinant, then sacked and burned the town. British forces retreated at the Battle of Mons.</p>
<p>1921 - Feisal I was installed as King of Iraq.</p>
<p>1926 - Rudolph Valentino, American film actor, died aged 31. Idolised by women as the &quot;Great Lover&quot;, he starred in films such as &quot;The Sheik&quot;, &quot;Blood and Sand&quot;, &quot;The Eagle&quot; and &quot;The Son of the Sheik&quot;.</p>
<p>1927 - Two Italian-born anarchists, Nicola Sacco and Bartolomeo Vanzetti, were executed in Massachusetts despite worldwide protests of their innocence.</p>
<p>1939 - Hitler and Stalin signed a non-aggression pact, leaving the way open for Germany to attack Poland.</p>
<p>1942 - The Battle of Stalingrad began. Although German shelling reduced the city to rubble, the Russians fought back and after six months the Germans surrendered.</p>
<p>1944 - King Michael of Romania ordered his forces to cease fire against the Allies and dismissed the pro-Axis premier, Marshal Ion Antonescu.</p>
<p>1960 - Oscar Hammerstein II, American lyricist and theatrical producer, died. He was best known for his collaboration with the composer Richard Rodgers.</p>
<p>1961 - Ranger I, first in a series of successful U.S. lunar probes, was launched from Cape Canaveral, Florida.</p>
<p>1961 - East Germany imposed new curbs on travel between West and East Berlin. In retaliation the Western powers placed tanks and 1,000 troops along the Berlin Wall.</p>
<p>1976 - Arab guerrillas hijacked an Egyptair plane shortly after takeoff from Cairo. The plane landed at Luxor where Egyptian commandos successfully stormed it.</p>
<p>1979 - Bolshoi Ballet star Alexander Godunov sought and received political asylum in the United States.</p>
<p>1980 - The Polish government agreed to negotiate directly with striking Gdansk shipworkers.</p>
<p>1982 - Christian militia leader Bashir Gemayel was elected president of Lebanon.</p>
<p>1989 - Citizens of the Soviet Union's Baltic states marked the 50th anniversary of the Soviet-Nazi pact which led to their incorporation into the Soviet empire by forming a 300-km (180-mile) human chain for freedom.</p>
<p>1990 - Armenia declared independence from Moscow.</p>
<p>1990 - East and West Germany announced that they would unite on October 3, healing four decades of post-World War Two division.</p>
<p>1990 - Iraqi President Saddam Hussein appeared on television with British hostages held at &quot;a vital Iraqi installation&quot; in confrontation following Iraq's invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>1991 - Radical Moscow city leaders took control of the Soviet Communist Party's headquarters, seizing documents and sealing offices, as anti-communism swept the Soviet Union in the wake of a failed hardline coup.</p>
<p>1992 - Some 200 young rightwingers, cheered on by hundreds of spectators, attacked a hostel for foreign refugees in Rostock, eastern Germany and battled police during the night.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
