<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804095" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Calm returns to Kenyan port city after violence.</title>
<headline>Calm returns to Kenyan port city after violence.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>MOMBASA, Kenya 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Calm returned to the Kenyan port city of Mombasa and surrounding areas on Saturday after violence overnight brought the death toll in four days of violence to 25, witnesses and police said.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation in Mombasa has been contained. The worst is over and people are now getting back to their normal lives, but we shall maintain a heavy security presence, at least for the time being,&quot; an intelligence officer told Reuters in Nairobi.</p>
<p>Combined forces of the Kenyan army, navy, police and paramilitary units continued to hunt for unidentified attackers who first struck on Wednesday night in a commando-style raid on a police post at Likoni, south of Mombasa.</p>
<p>The gang disappeared as quickly as it had arrived, melting back into countryside bordering Tanzania. Initial casualties were 13 dead, including six police officers shot at point-blank range in their dilapidated station.</p>
<p>On Saturday, police reported a total of 25 people had died, the most recent in sporadic violence in the tourist village of Mtwapa, 15 km (nine miles) northeast of Mombasa.</p>
<p>Four people were killed there, the latest victims of the violence that has shaken Kenya's political and security establishment to its core.</p>
<p>And the identity and motive of the attackers remains shrouded in mystery, baffling security experts and spreading panic in the heart of the tourism industry -- the backbone of the East African country's economy.</p>
<p>In the squalid wards of Mombasa's Coast hospital, victims of the violence nursed their wounds, some missing hands or ears.</p>
<p>&quot;What am I going to do without my hands?&quot; cried one man, whose lower arms were severed by machete-wiedling attackers.</p>
<p>On the next bed lay a man who had lost three fingers. Six others had suffered severe head injuries.</p>
<p>The hospital is poorly equipped and lacked the facilities to cope with the victims of the wave of violence.</p>
<p>Hospital staff said around 60 percent of the patients were sharing beds. Others had brought their own food to supplement meagre hospital rations -- a common feature of Kenya's poverty-stricken rural areas.</p>
<p>Most of the injured appeared not to be indigenous coastal people, but from the inland Kamba, Luo and Luhya tribes.</p>
<p>Many thought they were being targeted because they came from outside the province. They said the violence was reminiscent of ethnic clashes which marred the run-up to Kenya's 1992 landmark multiparty elections.</p>
<p>In the dilapidated mortuary bodies lay on the floor awaiting collection for burial: there is simply not enough refrigeration space.</p>
<p>The Roman Catholic Church in Likoni has been turned into settlement camp for some 2,000 terrified villagers huddling together for protection, their former homes heaps of debris.</p>
<p>Police said 31 people had been injured in the violence, which triggered a major military operation to hunt down the assailants.</p>
<p>But residents said they still felt insecure.</p>
<p>&quot;The government appears incapable of restoring law and order and most people have fled from their homes,&quot; said Nyagah Murano, a resident of Likoni.</p>
<p>Forty-three people have been arrested since the attack there and hotel shuttle buses were suspended on Friday and tourists told to stay on hotel property until security was restored.</p>
<p>Several slogans painted on walls near Matuga pointed to a political motive exacerbated by tribal and land tensions.</p>
<p>&quot;These are not criminals. These are not thugs. Federalism,&quot; said one. &quot;Federalism. Mainlanders should go to their homes,&quot; said another. &quot;Federalism, justice and land,&quot; said a third.</p>
<p>The violence is the latest blow to the government of President Daniel arap Moi in an election year. His government has come under increasing pressure since May from an opposition-backed alliance demanding democratic reforms before a general election later this year.</p>
<p>Violent police action to break up rallies and opposition protests has rattled investors and tourists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOMBASA, Kenya"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
