<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804017" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY UNION-HALF-POWER ALL BLACKS WIN TRI-NATIONS.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-HALF-POWER ALL BLACKS WIN TRI-NATIONS.</headline>
<dateline>DUNEDIN, New Zealand 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's All Blacks beat Australia 36-24 on Saturday to win their second successive Tri-Nations series and extend their clean sweep this season to eight tests in a row.</p>
<p>But after a bulldozing first half, with 36 points unanswered by the Australian visitors, the seemingly unstoppable All Blacks ran out of steam and only just survived a late Wallaby recovery.</p>
<p>The favourites dropped back to concede four tries, as a stiff breeze down the Carisbrook ground meant all the points were scored in one direction only -- with the wind.</p>
<p>After eight straight wins in their southern hemisphere test season New Zealand have confirmed they are the main contenders for the world crown, but their home finish was a disappointment.</p>
<p>Coach John Hart said the game reflected &quot;the difficult nature of our year&quot;, with the collapse in form in the second half showing that two tests in two weeks could be too much.</p>
<p>Last Saturday a physically-exhausting battle saw the All Blacks crush their arch-rivals South Africa 55-35 in Auckland.</p>
<p>Facing the old enemy from across the Tasman for the 105th time today, the men in black provided all the early highlights, with a scintillating try after a solo run down half the field by fullback Christian Cullen capping a copybook first half.</p>
<p>As the Wallabies sought to emphasise their wide back line, lacking key loose forwards like playmaker John Eales through injury, they found their tactics consistently frustrated by the New Zealanders throughout the first 40 minutes.</p>
<p>But in a classic &quot;game of two halves&quot;, the Wallabies came back with a resounding recovery and their fast handling and clever running brought them four excellent tries from backs Joe Roff, Stephen Larkham (two) and Ben Tune.</p>
<p>Asked about the Australians' change of fortune, flyhalf David Knox said words like &quot;humiliation&quot; were used in the team talk at half time.</p>
<p>&quot;We just had to pull together, but you've got to realise the breeze was very strong,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We scored 24-nil in the second half, which is pretty good against the All Blacks, but not good enough&quot;.</p>
<p>Wallabies' coach Greg Smith dubbed his side's first half performance strange, saying: &quot;It's difficult to understand why we didn't have any intensity&quot;.</p>
<p>But he called his team &quot;very committed people&quot;, and looked forward to them going on to play South Africa next weekend in Pretoria in the final game of the Tri-nations championship.</p>
<p>&quot;They try very hard and they're not about to give up, but we have to work on our skills and I hope we can kick the ball a bit better in the thin air (of the Transvaal)&quot;, he added.</p>
<p>As for the All Blacks, captain Sean Fitzpatrick said the players would be using the next couple of months to regroup for a tour of Ireland, Wales and England in November and December.</p>
<p>&quot;We showed what we we're capable of in that first 40 minutes -- it would have been nice to have done it for 80 -- so maybe in November in the UK we can show them how we play 80 minutes of rugby,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Alongside Cullen, the All Blacks' other outstanding figure was again flyhalf Carlos Spencer, one of a group of Auckland players at the heart of the New Zealand line-up.</p>
<p>He kicked 21 points in the first half, from five penalties and three conversions from tries by Taine Randell, Cullen and scrum half Justin Marshall.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>New Zealand: 15-Christian Cullen; 14-Jeff Wilson, 13-Frank Bunce, 12-Alama Ieremia, 11-Glen Osborne; 10-Carlos Spencer, 9-Justin Marshall (18-Ofisa Tonu'u, 65th minute); 8-Zinzan Brooke, 7-Josh Kronfeld, 6-Taine Randell, 5-Ian Jones (20-Mark Allen), 4-Robin Brooke, 3-Olo Brown, 2-Sean Fitzpatrick (captain), 1-Craig Dowd.</p>
<p>Australia: 15-Stephen Larkham; 14-Ben Tune, 13-Jason Little, 12-James Holbeck, 11-Joe Roff (16-Mitch Hardy, 70th); 10-David Knox, 9-George Gregan; 8-Troy Coker, 7-David Wilson (captain), 6-Fili Finau, 5-John Langford (19-Brett Robinson, 65th), 4-Owen Finegan, 3-Andrew Blades, 2-Michael Foley, 1-Richard Harry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUNEDIN, New Zealand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
