<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804044" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: SOCCER-RUSSIA FACE WORLD X1, MARK CENTENARY IN NEW HOME.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-RUSSIA FACE WORLD X1, MARK CENTENARY IN NEW HOME.</headline>
<byline>Alastair MacDonald</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia is set to celebrate its centenary of soccer and the reopening of one of Europe's finest stadiums with a match on Monday against a World X1 assembled by former England manager Bobby Robson.</p>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin will attend the gala event and may even kick off the first match at the 82,000-seat Luzhniki stadium for almost two years.</p>
<p>Work costing $200,000 has been carried out on the stadium and a retractable roof, which will protect the pitch from Moscow's long snowbound winter, will be completed by next May.</p>
<p>Robson, who led England to the semifinals of the World Cup in 1990 and now Barcelona's director of football, has a wealth of riches to call on.</p>
<p>Internazionale's French international Youri Djorkaeff, Roberto Baggio of Bologna, Argentine striker Gabriel Batistuta, Lothar Matthaeus of Bayern Munich and Barcelona's Josep Guardiola are all expected to play.</p>
<p>The cost of a ticket, $25, is several days' wages for many Muscovites and there are still 60,000 seats to fill in the riverside ground, which in 1982 was the site of one of the worst soccer disasters -- a stampede that killed at least 66 and, by unofficial accounts, up to 340 at a UEFA Cup game.</p>
<p>Soccer attendances have slumped since the collapse of the Soviet Union, hit by economic hardship, a drain of talent to the West and a singular lack of form at international level.</p>
<p>Less than 5,000 turned out for the last game at Luzhniki, a Euro 96 qualifier against Finland. Premier league attendance has crept up to an average of just over 11,000. But Torpedo Moscow, due to take up residence at Luzhniki, seldom see crowds in five figures.</p>
<p>The stadium will be the first in Russia to meet new international standards and Russian officials say UEFA is willing to stage the final of one of its club tournaments at Luzhniki next spring.</p>
<p>The reopening of the stadium is being seen as the start of a fresh challenge for the nation's soccer.</p>
<p>The Soviets became European champions in 1960 despite having dispatched their best player, &quot;Russian Pele&quot; Eduard Streltsov, to the gulag.</p>
<p>But thereafter they earned a reputation as the nearly men of world soccer, losing three European finals and never bettering a 1966 World Cup semifinal appearance.</p>
<p>Humbled at the last World Cup and Euro 96, Russia have shown few signs they or the country's clubs -- none has ever won a European trophy -- will improve on that any time soon.</p>
<p>However, Yeltsin, always more of a tennis and volleyball man himself, may take comfort from knowing that at least private enterprise is booming around Russia's soccer grounds.</p>
<p>Luzhniki makes $100,000 a day from a vast flea market that seethes around the stadium under a huge statue of Lenin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
