<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804018" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-KAFELNIKOV REACHES SEMIS IN NEW HAVEN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-KAFELNIKOV REACHES SEMIS IN NEW HAVEN.</headline>
<dateline>NEW HAVEN, Connecticut 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top seed Yevgeny Kafelnikov, preparing for the U.S. Open, survived against seventh-seeded Tim Henman 5-7 6-3 6-4 Friday in the quarter-finals of the Pilot Pen tennis championship.</p>
<p>&quot;My goal is to play consistent tennis and to win this tournament,&quot; said Kafelnikov. &quot;If I do that, then I'll be ready for the Open.&quot;</p>
<p>The 23-year-old Russian belter reached the semifinals here for the third time in four years. He will face fifth-seeded Czech Petr Korda, who survived four match points to beat unseeded American David Wheaton 4-6 7-6 (9-7) 6-4.</p>
<p>Second seed Sergi Bruguera of Spain was upset by eighth seed Patrick Rafter of Australia 7-5 2-6 6-2, and 11th seed Greg Rusedski of Britain blasted away fourth-seeded Richard Krajicek of the Netherlands 7-6 (7-5) 3-6 6-3 and became just the second player in the history of the game to be recorded serving above 140 miles per hour (225 kph).</p>
<p>Henman was able to convert only two of 12 break-point opportunities against Kafelnikov. &quot;I created some chances, but I didn't take them,&quot; said Henman. &quot;I think I served better than him (17-5 edge in aces) but he outhit me from the baseline.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Tim was very aggressive and he put a lot of pressure on me,&quot; said Kafelnikov. &quot;I made some good shots on important break points, but I still had to be a little lucky.&quot;</p>
<p>Bruguera, however, was not so fortunate. The Spanish clay court artist fell victim to Rafter's heavier artillery.</p>
<p>Rafter dominated the third set, breaking early and taking a 3-0 lead. Bruguera never came close to recovering. Rafter broke a final time in the last game, gaining the last two points with a topspin lob and a backhand passing shot.</p>
<p>&quot;I missed some easy volleys in the first set and if I made them I probably would had won the match in straight sets,&quot; said Bruguera. &quot;I beat him on grass, so I certainly should be able to beat him on these hard courts.&quot;</p>
<p>Going into this match, Bruguera had a 6-1 edge in the series.</p>
<p>There were only two service breaks in the battle of booming serves between Rusedski and Krajicek. The crucial break came in the second game of the third set to give Rusedski a 2-0 lead.</p>
<p>&quot;I've beaten him four out of five times, so I wouldn't really call this an upset,&quot; said Rusedski, who joined Mark Philippoussis as the only players with serves recorded above 140 mph (225 kph). &quot;But all our matches have been really close. One break is pretty decisive when we play each other.&quot;</p>
<p>Krajicek said he is going to take a long rest before the Open. &quot;I don't plan to touch a racket for five days. I played four tournaments in a row and I'm a little fed up.&quot;</p>
<p>Wheaton's comeback effort came to a crashing halt as he just could not finish off Korda.</p>
<p>Wheaton, who had upset third-seeded Philippoussis in the first round, held four match points in the second set and a 5-1 lead in the tiebreaker.</p>
<p>&quot;I was a little too tentative when I had those match points,&quot; said Wheaton. &quot;I just couldn't seem to relax and I made some bad mistakes.&quot;</p>
<p>Wheaton double-faulted away his final match point at 6-5 in the breaker. At 7-7, Korda served an ace and Wheaton netted a stretch volley to end the breaker and force the third set.</p>
<p>Wheaton, tiring, lost his service in the 10th game of the final set to end the two-hour, 45-minute struggle.</p>
<p>&quot;I just kept fighting,&quot; said Korda, the 1991 champion here. &quot;He was playing without any pressure until he got that 5-1 lead in the breaker. Then he got tight.</p>
<p>&quot;I might have struggled at times, but to come back and win like that had to be a positive thing for me. And I've had a few other comebacks in my life.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW HAVEN, Connecticut"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
