<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804046" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY UNION- NZ EDGE WALLABIES, SWEEP TRI-NATIONS.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION- NZ EDGE WALLABIES, SWEEP TRI-NATIONS.</headline>
<dateline>DUNEDIN, New Zealand 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's All Blacks beat Australia 36-24 on Saturday to win their second successive Tri-Nations series and extend their clean sweep this season to eight tests in a row.</p>
<p>A bulldozing first half, with 36 points unanswered by the Australian visitors, was capped with a scintillating solo try by fullback Christian Cullen before a 42,000 Carisbrooke crowd.</p>
<p>The Wallabies had to emphasise their wide back line, as they lacked key loose forwards through injury, but found their tactics frustrated by New Zealand throughout the first half.</p>
<p>However, a resounding recovery in the second half, when they scored four tries, gave the Australians some consolation and grounds for optimism ahead of the last game of the southern hemisphere's Tri-Nations series against South Africa in a week.  </p>
<p>In contrast with their earlier tests this season, New Zealand got off to a good start, with flyhalf Carlos Spencer putting 12 points on the board with three penalties in the first 20 minutes. Flanker Taine Randell added a try shortly after.</p>
<p>Fullback Christian Cullen brought the 42,000 crowd to their feet with a scintillating run down the centre of the field a few minutes later, in a solo effort that gave him his 18th try in as many tests for New Zealand.</p>
<p>Though Australia built play well in midfield during the half the All Blacks had the measure of their wide tactic, a trademark of the agile ACT Brumbies who dominated the Wallaby side.</p>
<p>The skill of the All Blacks' loose forwards under veteran tactician and number eight Zinzan Brooke set up their third try when a scrummaged ball close to the posts rocketed out to scrum half Justin Marshall.</p>
<p>His try, and another conversion from Spencer, took the scoreline to 33-0 and in the last minute of the half, Spencer got another penalty for a mid-way scoreline of 36-0.</p>
<p>Seemingly different sides came out in the second half, with the Wallabies turning the game on its head. Within 10 minutes they had two tries, one converted.</p>
<p>Brumbie backs Joe Roff and Stephen Larkham waltzed around a sleepy-looking New Zealand defence, using agile handling and running to dash in much-needed points.</p>
<p>In a torrid two-way phase, not helped by French referee Joel Dume interrupting the development of an open game by rigorously enforcing offside and mauling rules, the game lost pace.</p>
<p>Tired looking All Blacks flagged in defence, with the play shifting slowly into Australian hands by the last quarter of an hour.</p>
<p>Larkham levelled the try count in the 69th minute, after a superb running combination with Ben Tune, and flyhalf David Knox connected with Tune again three minutes from time for another classy try, Tune's seventh in test rugby, that took the final scoreline to 24-36.</p>
<p>Accepting the Tri-nations trophy, All Black captain Sean Fitzpatrick bemoaned his side's slump. &quot;It was disappointing for us to finish the season on a second half note like that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>New Zealand coach John Hart told reporters: &quot;I think you might be seeing a bit of a tired team at the end of a pretty hard run, and maybe without the ball the second half became very difficult for them.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Dume's refereeing policy, awarding a total of 38 penalties in 80 minutes, meant the game ended up frustrating.</p>
<p>Despite the disappointing finish, he noted his side had come through a testing southern hemisphere international season with eight &quot;decisive&quot; wins.</p>
<p>Australian coach Greg Smith said he couldn't understand why his team lacked intensity in the first half, and noted that they would have to work harder on their skills, including kicking.</p>
<p>But asked if the All Blacks could be beaten, he said: &quot;They're not unbeatable -- they're a great team but they're certainly not unbeatable.&quot;</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>New Zealand: 15-Christian Cullen; 14-Jeff Wilson, 13-Frank Bunce, 12-Alama Ieremia, 11-Glen Osborne; 10-Carlos Spencer, 9-Justin Marshall (18-Ofisa Tonu'u, 65th minute); 8-Zinzan Brooke, 7-Josh Kronfeld, 6-Taine Randell, 5-Ian Jones (20-Mark Allen), 4-Robin Brooke, 3-Olo Brown, 2-Sean Fitzpatrick (captain), 1-Craig Dowd.</p>
<p>Australia: 15-Stephen Larkham; 14-Ben Tune, 13-Jason Little, 12-James Holbeck, 11-Joe Roff (Mitch Hardy, 70th); 10-David Knox, 9-George Gregan; 8-Troy Coker, 7-David Wilson (captain), 6-Fili Finau, 5-John Langford (19-Brett Robinson, 65th), 4-Owen Finegan, 3-Andrew Blades, 2-Michael Foley, 1-Richard Harry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUNEDIN, New Zealand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
