<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804022" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-JANZEN HOLDS ONE-SHOT LEAD AFTER TWO ROUNDS OF THE PGA.</title>
<headline>GOLF-JANZEN HOLDS ONE-SHOT LEAD AFTER TWO ROUNDS OF THE PGA.</headline>
<byline>Larry Fine</byline>
<dateline>MAMARONECK, New York 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lee Janzen jumped out to a big lead with a spectacular birdie binge at Winged Foot before a bogey-bogey finish Friday brought him back to the pack after the second round of the PGA Championship.</p>
<p>Janzen, who had reached six-under after making his sixth birdie of the day at the 16th hole, finished with a 67 for a four-under-par total of 136 and a one-stroke lead over Davis Love.</p>
<p>&quot;It would have been nice to birdie them but they are really tough holes,&quot; the quiet 32-year-old said about his finish. &quot;I made plenty of mistakes, but I'm still on top of the leaderboard.&quot;</p>
<p>Janzen, whose best finish in the last four weeks was a tie for 39th at the Western Open, said: &quot;It's fun to be playing well.&quot;</p>
<p>Love's roller-coaster round of 71 included four birdies, three bogeys and a double bogey.</p>
<p>A crowd of contenders lurked just off the pace on a day that saw constant shifting at the top before Janzen, the 1993 U.S. Open champion, took charge.</p>
<p>Seven players stood two shots behind Janzen -- British Open champion Justin Leonard, Fred Couples, Phil Mickelson, Italy's Costantino Rocca, Jeff Maggert, Phil Blackmar and Shigeki Maruyama of Japan.</p>
<p>Another stroke adrift lay six more players -- John Daly, Australian Greg Norman, Tom Kite, Paul Stankowski, Chris Perry and Vijay Singh of Fiji, who shot a course record-tying 66.</p>
<p>Tiger Woods was among a group of five another shot away.</p>
<p>The leaderboard saw some dizzying changes during the day after Daly, who held a two-shot lead in the early going, began to fade. First-round co-leader Love, Kite, Leonard and Jeff Maggert all had turns at the top before Janzen swept past.</p>
<p>Janzen had struggled in the first round, going out in three-over 38 before catching fire on the back nine. He made six birdies coming in to post a 69 and then continued his hot streak Friday, making five birdies in his first 10 holes.</p>
<p>&quot;I got off to another great start and kept yesterday's back nine going,&quot; said Janzen, whose Open victory came at Baltusrol, which like Winged Foot is an A.W. Tillinghast design.</p>
<p>Daly, who thrilled the fans and his fellow players alike with a record-tying opening round of 66 as he continues his comeback from alcoholism, held the second-round lead until he bogeyed the 13th to let Kite past.</p>
<p>The 31-year-old former PGA and British Open champion bogeyed three more holes after that to finish at three-over 73 for a 139 total.</p>
<p>&quot;I just missed a lot of putts. I missed a lot of four or five-footers,&quot; said Daly, who missed the Masters and British Open after undergoing alcoholism treatment, and walked off the course at the U.S. Open in the second round with a case of the shakes.</p>
<p>Daly, however, was not disappointed or discouraged.</p>
<p>&quot;If someone told me I'd be one-under after two days I'd have taken it,&quot; said Daly. &quot;Any time you're three or four shots out in the last two rounds of a major you have a chance.&quot;</p>
<p>Woods looked set to make a big charge as he birdied his first two holes after a level-par opening round, but the 21-year-old Masters champion had putting problems that slowed his momentum and he faded back to even par.</p>
<p>Leonard briefly joined a three-way tie for the lead with Daly and Kite at four under but he slid back with bogeys at the eighth and 10th.</p>
<p>Couples holed out from the fairway at the par-4 11th hole for eagle and added two more birdies to climb to four under before bogeys at the 16th and 18th pulled him down.</p>
<p>Seventy-seven players made the cut, which was established at six-over-par 146.</p>
<p>Among the prominent players failing to qualify were defending champion Mark Brooks (149), Fuzzy Zoeller (148), who won the 1984 U.S. Open here, Ian Woosnam (149), Jack Nicklaus (150), Tom Watson (150) and Nick Faldo (153).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAMARONECK, New York"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
