<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804087" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Charles poses again, Diana media frenzy unabated.</title>
<headline>Charles poses again, Diana media frenzy unabated.</headline>
<byline>Jill Serjeant</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prince Charles, heir to the British throne, interrupted his summer break in Scotland for the second time on Saturday to pose with his two sons for photographers.</p>
<p>Royal aides denied suggestions that the rare photo-call on the royal family's vast private Balmoral estate in rural Scotland was a bid to deflect attention from the media fenzy over Princess Diana's romance with millionaire Egyptian playboy Dodi Al Fayed.</p>
<p>The shots of Charles, dressed in a green kilt, beside a waterfall with princes William and Harry, seemed hardly likely to grab world newspaper headlines dominated by the affair of Diana, Dodi and spurned other woman Kelly Fisher.</p>
<p>Diana flew out to Greece with a woman friend on her third Mediterranean holiday in two months, leaving behind a breach of contract suit brought against the new man in her life by U.S. model Kelly.</p>
<p>Kelly claims she was Al Fayed's fiancee until pictures of him kissing Diana appeared in newspapes around the world.</p>
<p>Dodi, son of Harrods boss Mohammed Al Fayed, has denied her claims but the saga looked certain to run with Britain's best-selling Sunday newspaper, the News Of The World, promising that Fisher would be telling the tabloid her side of the story.</p>
<p>Charles, who was divorced from Diana a year ago, usually guards his privacy jealously during his annual holiday at Balmoral and seeks to protect their sons from the more unsavoury publicity surrounding the marriage breakup.</p>
<p>Royal aides said that by volunteering to pose for photogaphers there, Charles and the boys would be left in peace for the rest of their break.</p>
<p>&quot;It was an experiment. I am not saying it's setting a precedent. It has worked. We want to work with the media, we will come halfway if you leave them alone,&quot; the prince's press spokeswoman Sandy Henney told reporters.</p>
<p>Henney denied the two photo-calls were part of a &quot;charm offensive&quot; by the prince, who faces an uphill task as the next king after opinion polls showed popularity for the monarchy slumping to below 50 percent for the first time.</p>
<p>Henney said Charles and his sons were grateful for being left alone since first posing for photographers on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's meant a lot to them. They have been able to go places and do things, they have not been previously able to do,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>British newspapers remained obsessed with Diana and Dodi on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Sun splashed a front-page picture of Al Fayed arm in arm with Fisher and inside carried the results of a telephone poll by its readers -- they voted five to one for &quot;Di to dump Dodi.&quot;</p>
<p>Readers who sent in humorous limericks -- dubbed &quot;Di and Dodi odes&quot; -- were given 30 pound prizes for the best ones.</p>
<p>Other tabloids also rounded on Al Fayed. &quot;You're a Dodi rotten cheat,&quot; declared the Daily Mirror.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
