<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804083" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Queen Victoria film tipped for Oscar nominations.</title>
<headline>Queen Victoria film tipped for Oscar nominations.</headline>
<byline>James Forrester</byline>
<text>
<p>EDINBURGH, Aug 17 (REUTER) - Scottish comedian Billy Connolly shrugged off suggestions on Saturday that his new film &quot;Mrs Brown&quot; was certain to be in the running for Oscar nominations for the 1998 Hollywood awards ceremony.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't win prizes,&quot; Connolly told a news conference before the British premiere of the film about Britain's Queen Victoria and her highland ghillie (personal servant) John Brown.</p>
<p>&quot;It's like asking a footballer how he'll cope with winning the European Cup before playing the first round. For me it's enough to hear &quot;Oscar&quot; and Billy Connolly in the same sentence.&quot;</p>
<p>The film, shown to an Edinburgh Film Festival audience, was widely praised on its release in North America a few weeks ago, leading to speculation that it could win Oscar honours.</p>
<p>It tells the story of how the widowed queen, who withdrew from society after the death of her husband Prince Albert, was brought back by Brown's devotion and stubborn persistence to her role as Queen Empress at the peak of Britain's imperial power.</p>
<p>It portrays a growing intimacy and developing affection between the queen and her servant but is ambiguous about any physical relationship, an ambiguity present in an emotional death bed scene as Brown succumbs to pneumonia brought on by his obsessive regard for the queen's security.</p>
<p>Dame Judi Dench, the British actress who plays Queen Victoria, said she doubted the relationship was consummated. But she said research showed the queen was not the dour, rigid disciplinarian of popular belief but &quot;a passionate woman -- a very passionate woman, capable of enthusiasms and prone to sudden outbursts of rage.&quot;</p>
<p>The film title recalls contemporary gossip that the queen secretly married Brown and rumours that her insistence on his presence during a visit to Switzerland was to ensure they were together when she bore his child -- even though she was 50 at the time.</p>
<p>Connolly noted that the queen was surrounded by courtiers on almost every occasion, making a physical relationship virtually impossible.</p>
<p>He suggested the stables as the only location where they could have been alone, but wondered whether the queen would have been amenable to a tumble in the hay. &quot;But I hope they did,&quot; he added. &quot;What else could they do?&quot;</p>
<p>Connolly has a nude bathing scene, leading one shrewd cinemagoer to say that no one could doubt why the folk singer, turned comedian, turned straight actor, has long been called &quot;The Big Yin.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
