<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804023" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-MALCOLM CLAIMS ATHERTON DOUBLE.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-MALCOLM CLAIMS ATHERTON DOUBLE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Michael Atherton was dismissed twice in three hours by his England team mate Devon Malcolm on Saturday as Derbyshire swept to victory over Lancashire on the second day of their four-day county championship match.</p>
<p>The England skipper scored four and five as Lancs were bowled out for 118 and 256 in reply to Derbyshire's 411 to lose by an innings and 37 runs.</p>
<p>John Crawley hit 133 off just 127 balls in Lancashire's second innings but paceman Malcolm's match figures of 10 for 65 - including six for 23 in the first innings - clinched Derbyshire's first championship win of the season.</p>
<p>England new boys Adam and Ben Hollioake both hit career-bests as Surrey stayed in charge against Middlesex.</p>
<p>Skipper Adam hit 182 and Ben 76 as Surrey made 531 for nine declared before Middlesex closed on 24 for one, a deficit of 302.</p>
<p>Yorkshire pace bowler Paul Hutchison made a stunning championship debut as he took six Hampshire wickets.</p>
<p>Hutchison finished with six for 42 as Hampshire closed on 264 for eight, still 88 runs short of avoiding the follow-on after Yorkshire had declared on 501 for eight earlier in the day.</p>
<p>Glamorgan captain Matthew Maynard struck an unbeaten 140 as his side reached 355 for eight in reply to Worcestershire's 476 for nine.</p>
<p>Nottinghamshire slumped from 152 for two to 231 for six after bowling out Somerset for 337.</p>
<p>Sussex collapsed from 157 from one to 218 for seven before closing on 255 for seven against title hopefuls Gloucestershire, who earlier reached 320 in their first innings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
