<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804049" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: DIVING-DUMAIS WINS SECOND TITLE IN TWO DAYS AT U.S. NATIONALS.</title>
<headline>DIVING-DUMAIS WINS SECOND TITLE IN TWO DAYS AT U.S. NATIONALS.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>California teenager Troy Dumais staked a claim as an early 2000 U.S. Olympic hopeful Saturday by winning his second national title in two days at the USA Diving Senior National Championships.</p>
<p>Dumais, 17, won the 3-metre springboard title over an impressive field of six finalists that included 1996 Olympian David Pichler and past national champions Dean Panaro and Bryan Gillooly.</p>
<p>Dumais had 666.36 points. Pichler, 28, finished a disappointing fifth.</p>
<p>Dumais, who won the 1-metre springboard title Friday night, has won four national titles in two weeks. Last week at the USA Diving Junior Nationals in Austin, Texas, he set the national record (16) by winning the 1- and 3-metre titles.</p>
<p>&quot;I am having a good two weeks,&quot; Dumais said. &quot;This is the best I've done in back-to-back meets. It gives me a lot of confidence for the future. Sure, I want to go to the Olympics but a lot can happen between now and then.&quot;</p>
<p>Dumais barely missed the 1996 Olympic team when at age 16 he finished third on 3-metre springboard. Only the top two qualify for the Olympics.</p>
<p>It was also the first time in U.S. diving history, a brother tandem finished 1-2. Justin Dumais, 18, Troy's older brother, finished second with 647.73.</p>
<p>In the women's platform, Laura Wilkinson, 19, won her first national title among a crop of new faces. With two-time Olympic bronze medallist Mary Ellen Clark retired, the women's platform competition is wide open.</p>
<p>The top two finishers qualify for the September 10-14 diving World Cup in Mexico City and the world aquatics championships in Perth, Australia, next January. The six-day meet concludes Sunday.</p>
<p>Men's 3-metre springboard final</p>
<p>1. Troy Dumais 666.36</p>
<p>2. Justin Dumais 647.73</p>
<p>3. Dean Panaro 644.70</p>
<p>4. P.J. Bogart 641.37</p>
<p>5. David Pichler 622.56</p>
<p>6. Bryan Gillooly 599.97</p>
<p>Women's platform final</p>
<p>1. Laura Wilkinson 503.49</p>
<p>2. Kim Stanford 484.02</p>
<p>3. Megan Gardner 463.83</p>
<p>4. Kathy Pesek 449.73</p>
<p>5. Lizzy Flynt 443.52</p>
<p>6. Michelle Davidson 408.24</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
