<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804096" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Four killed in Kenya violence, 2,000 displaced.</title>
<headline>Four killed in Kenya violence, 2,000 displaced.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>MTWAPA, Kenya 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four people were killed in sporadic violence northeast of the port city of Mombasa overnight, raising the death toll in four days of violence to 25, police sources said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The violence, which started on Wednesday night, has shaken Kenya's political and security establishment but the motive and identity of the attackers remains a mystery.</p>
<p>Police said earlier that one person died overnight, but revised the figure after receiving more information on the incident at Mtwapa, a tourist village 15 km (nine miles) northeast of Mombasa.</p>
<p>&quot;We now have four people killed last night,&quot; a senior police officer who declined to be identified told Reuters.</p>
<p>Police said a total of 31 people had been injured in the violence which has triggered a major military operation to hunt down the assailants.</p>
<p>A night club and a tourist lodge were burnt down in Mtwapa by the unknown attackers.</p>
<p>&quot;I evacuated four tourists from the lodge and moved them to my house where they spent the night,&quot; said lodge owner Margaret Shundu.</p>
<p>Scores of people have been rounded up in connection with the violence, which began with a wave of attacks on Wednesday night in which at least 15 people were killed, including seven police officers.</p>
<p>Police said the situation had largely returned to normal and tension eased in and around Mombasa, but a hunt for the attackers was still under way.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation in Mombasa has been contained. The worst is over and people are now getting back to their normal lives, but we shall maintain a heavy security presence, at least for the time being,&quot; an intelligence officer told Reuters in Nairobi.</p>
<p>Police and intelligence officers were trying to identify the motive for the violence.</p>
<p>A combined team of army, police, navy and elite paramilitary units is hunting the killers and maintaining law and order in and around Mombasa.</p>
<p>But residents said they still felt insecure after Wednesday night's attack.</p>
<p>&quot;The government appears incapable of restoring law and order and most people have fled from their homes,&quot; said Nyagah Murano, a resident of the Likoni area south of Mombasa.</p>
<p>Crack paramilitary unit reinforcements have been trucked into the area, which is hilly and has caves where police thought the attackers might be hiding.</p>
<p>Church officials said up to 2,000 frightened local residents have taken shelter at a Roman Catholic church compound in Likoni.</p>
<p>Police have said six police, five attackers and two civilians were killed during Wednesday's night- long raid on Likoni police posts. A seventh policeman died on Thursday and another civilian on Friday.</p>
<p>A total of 43 people have been arrested since the Likoni raid. Hotel shuttle buses were suspended on Friday and tourists told to stay on hotel property until security was restored.</p>
<p>Scores of attackers armed with machetes seized 28 police issue G-3 rifles and two sub-machineguns on Wednesday and also burned two police posts at Likoni and freed Kenyan prisoners.</p>
<p>Several slogans painted on walls near Matuga pointed to a political motive exacerbated by tribal and land tensions.</p>
<p>&quot;These are not criminals. These are not thugs. Federalism,&quot; said one. &quot;Federalism. Mainlanders should go to their homes,&quot; said another. &quot;Federalism, justice and land,&quot; said a third.</p>
<p>The violence is the latest blow to the government of President Daniel arap Moi in an election year. His government has come under increasing pressure since May from an opposition-backed alliance demanding democratic reforms before a general election later this year. Violent police action to break up rallies and opposition protests has rattled investors and tourists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MTWAPA, Kenya"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
