<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804157" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia says E. Timor leader won't be released.</title>
<headline>Indonesia says E. Timor leader won't be released.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian Justice Minister Utoyo Usman has said the government did not plan to release jailed East Timorese rebel leader Jose &quot;Xanana&quot; Gusmao any time soon, Kompas newspaper reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;No. I can assure you there will not be either (sentence) reduction or a release for Xanana,&quot; Usman was quoted as telling Kompas on Friday.</p>
<p>Justice Ministry officials could not be reached for comment on Saturday.</p>
<p>Gusmao is serving a 20-year jail sentence at Jakarta's Cipinang jail for resisting Indonesian rule in East Timor, a former Portuguese colony invaded by Indonesia in 1975 and annexed the following year in a move not recognised by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Usman said he had checked the list of inmates whose jail sentences would be reduced or who would be released to mark Indonesia's independence anniverary celebrations on Sunday and that Gusmao's name was not on the list.</p>
<p>The paper gave no further details.</p>
<p>Rumours about Gusmao's release appeared after last month's state visit by South African President Nelson Mandela.</p>
<p>During the visit, Mandela secured the temporary release of Gusmao and dined with him at the government guest house.</p>
<p>Mandela later sent a letter to Suharto suggesting Gusmao be released to better the prospects for a settlement of the East timor problem.</p>
<p>But government officials have reiterated that Gusmao was in jail for criminal offences and not because of his political beliefs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
