<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804100" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO: Brazzaville calmer but residents still flee.</title>
<headline>Brazzaville calmer but residents still flee.</headline>
<byline>Helen Vesperini</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Congo Republic capital Brazzaville was relatively calm on Saturday after a week of intense mortar fire, residents said.</p>
<p>But many residents trapped by political violence since June took advantage of the lull to flee. They crossed the river Congo in canoes to the Democratic Congo's capital Kinshasa or headed southwest towards the port of Pointe-Noire, witnesses said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's the odd bit of firing but it's really very sporadic,&quot; said one Brazzaville resident reached by telephone.</p>
<p>The relative calm raised hopes for a speedy resumption of slow-motion talks in the Gabonese capital Libreville where President Omar Bongo and United Nations special envoy Mohamed Sahnoun are trying to find a diplomatic solution.</p>
<p>Residents also noted a conciliatory tone in an Independence Day speech on Friday by President Pascal Lissouba whose forces are locked in battle with militia of his predecessor, Denis Sassou Nguesso.</p>
<p>&quot;It was far more moderate than usual -- he mentioned neither Sassou's name nor the words 'rebellion' or 'coup d'etat' and his tone was quite conciliatory,&quot; commented one resident.</p>
<p>Envoys of the two rivals returned to Libreville on Thursday after consultations in Brazzaville, and diplomats said they expected the negotiations to resume on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm told President Bongo is tied up with Independence Day celebrations,&quot; one diplomat said. &quot;I think it may be Monday before he gets involved in the talks again.&quot;</p>
<p>The fighting has forced the indefinite postponement of presidential elections last month in which both Lissouba and Sassou were to be candidates.</p>
<p>Talks have been stalled by arguments over the appointment of an interim prime minister and what powers he should have.</p>
<p>Well over two thousand people were killed in militia warfare in Brazzaville following disputes over elections in 1993. The latest unrest has killed hundreds and devastatd whole districts of the city.</p>
<p>In Kinshasa, the office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees assembled some of the refugess at a camp at Kinkole, near the city's airport.</p>
<p>The Kinkole site, which was opened in mid-July to accommodate Brazzaville refugees of all nationalities, is currently home to more than 3,000 people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
