<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804185" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Palestinians condemn Israeli demolition of homes.</title>
<headline>Palestinians condemn Israeli demolition of homes.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinians condemned on Saturday a wave of Israeli demolitions of Arab houses in East Jerusalem and the West Bank this month as a violation of their peace accords.</p>
<p>Ahmed Korei, speaker of the Palestinian Legislative Council called on Israel to halt the demolitions which he said caused &quot;excessive humanitarian harm&quot; to Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;With this racist policy the Israeli government is trying to pre-empt the final status negotiations and speed up the Judaisation of Jerusalem,&quot; Korei, also known as Abu Ala, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Israel tore down nine houses in East Jerusalem and surrounding parts of the West Bank on Wednesday and another five on Thursday. It said they were all built without permits and that the demolitions were conducted according to the law.</p>
<p>The status of East Jerusalem is one of the most volatile issues dividing Palestinians and Israelis. Israel says the whole of Jerusalem forms its undivided capital, while Palestinians want East Jerusalem as the capital of a future state.</p>
<p>Korei urged &quot;the immediate halt of (the demolitions) which completely contradict the international agreements on Jerusalem and the accords signed by the Israeli and Palestinian sides&quot;.</p>
<p>Korei was joined by a chorus of Palestinian criticism from the cabinet, a human rights group, and the militant Islamic resistance movement Hamas.</p>
<p>Israeli bulldozers have razed at least 18 Palestinian houses in East Jerusalem and the West Bank since a twin suicide bombing in an Israeli market killed 16 people including the bombers.</p>
<p>&quot;Israel is trying to exploit the current situation, after the suicide bombing, in order to carry out its illegal practices,&quot; the Palestinian human rights group Al-Haq said in a statement.</p>
<p>Hamas, which has spearheaded suicide attacks inside Israel, said the demolitions were &quot;terrorism against innocent civilians&quot; and urged international intervention to stop them.</p>
<p>The Palestinian cabinet criticised Israel for continuing demolitions when the sides were trying to resume security coordination in the wake of the bombings.</p>
<p>Israeli officials say the demolitions were planned for months and Israel's mayor of Jerusalem, Ehud Olmert, has called illegal Arab building a &quot;cancer&quot; which threatens Israel's sovereignty in the holy city.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
