<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804103" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ANGOLA: After 1,000 days, Angola's peace could crumble.</title>
<headline>After 1,000 days, Angola's peace could crumble.</headline>
<byline>John Flemming</byline>
<dateline>LUANDA 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Angola's peace process marked 1,000 days on Saturday amid growing signs the country is drifting toward renewed conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say this is the most crucial point in the peace process,&quot; said one official close to Angola's peace negotiations. &quot;This is our last chance to secure peace in Angola.&quot;</p>
<p>On November 20, 1994, the Angolan government and the former rebel movement UNITA, the National Union for the Total Independence of Angola, signed a peace agreement in the Zambian capital, Lusaka.</p>
<p>The agreement ended nearly two decades of civil war and has brought the country the longest period of peace since a war of independence was launched against the Portuguese in the 1960s.</p>
<p>But recent weeks have shown a rapid deterioration in the peace process with government military incursions into UNITA territory and foot dragging on remaining crucial elements of the Lusaka agreement.</p>
<p>The former rebels were given until Friday to respond to a number of Security Council demands or face possible sanctions.</p>
<p>On Friday U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan, appeared to clear the way for punitive sanctions by the Security Council, saying last-minute &quot;half-hearted concessions by UNITA, under pressure and on the eve of Security Council deliberations, are no longer acceptable&quot;.</p>
<p>But diplomats say Annan wanted to hold off sanctions while U.N. officials in Angola verified recent promises made by UNITA.</p>
<p>Diplomats in Luanda said the former rebels were likely to be hit with sanctions soon, possibly after a two-week grace period.</p>
<p>The atmosphere among the key negotiators in the peace process has recently turned sour with daily admissions in private by diplomats and officials that patience is wearing thin.</p>
<p>Officials of the U.N. Observer Mission in Angola (MONUA) stress that the Lusaka agreement can still be implemented and point toward the successes of the U.N. action in Angola.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically after 1,000 days our triumph is that the ceasefire has held,&quot; said David Wimhurst, spokesman for MONUA.</p>
<p>&quot;In that sense we have saved the lives of thousands. We oversaw the establishment of a unity government, the integration of the army and the police, all things called for in the Lusaka agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course the bad news is that we are still here,&quot; Wimhurst continued. &quot;This mission was supposed to end six months ago.&quot;</p>
<p>One symbol of the Lusaka agreement can be found in Eugenio Ngolo &quot;Manuvakola&quot;, the man who signed the agreement for UNITA leader Jonas Savimbi in 1994.</p>
<p>Ngolo has not been seen in public in close to a year. Though UNITA officials in Luanda deny it, Ngolo is strongly rumored to be under house arrest in the UNITA-held highland city of Bailundo and has fallen out of favor with Savimbi.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ANGOLA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
