<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804116" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin, Chechnya's Maskhadov to meet on Monday.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin, Chechnya's Maskhadov to meet on Monday.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin and Chechen leader Aslan Maskhadov will meet in Moscow on Monday in a bid to break the deadlock in peace talks between Russia and the breakaway region, Itar-Tass news agency said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The long-awaited meeting, previously postponed due to deep disagreement over Chechnya's status, was announced by Ivan Rybkin, secretary of Russia's Security Council, and Chechen First Deputy Prime Minister Movladi Udugov, Tass said.</p>
<p>Maskhadov, who led Chechen separatists in their 21-month-long bloody conflict with Russian troops that ended last August, insists that his republic is already independent.</p>
<p>The Kremlin says Chechnya must stay within the Russian Federation, although with wide autonomy.</p>
<p>Interfax news agency quoted Maskhadov as saying on Saturday that his trip to Moscow was aimed at establishing full diplomatic ties with Russia befitting two equal sovereign states.</p>
<p>&quot;The time has come to define our relations and to conclude an all-embracing treaty with the establishment of diplomatic relations,&quot; Maskhadov said in the Chechen capital Grozny.</p>
<p>But Maskhadov also sounded a note of frustration.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Russia and the international community) do not want us Chechens to create our own state and show the world our ability to live independently,&quot; Interfax quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>No country has recognised Chechnya as an independent state.</p>
<p>Tensions between Moscow and Chechnya have risen again in recent days after Udugov accused Russian fighter planes of simulating an attack on Grozny's airport and central market.</p>
<p>Russia's military denied the allegation.</p>
<p>On Friday the Kremlin said Yeltsin would put pressure on Maskhadov during their meeting to do more to help free Russian journalists and other hostages held in Chechnya.</p>
<p>Diplomats from Germany, France and Britain -- which all have nationals held in Chechnya -- urged Rybkin on Friday to keep up the pressure on the Chechen authorities to ensure the safe release of the hostages.</p>
<p>Maskhadov has been fighting a wave of lawlessness in his tiny Caucasus region since being elected president in January.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
