<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804139" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia's Suharto focuses on currency crisis.</title>
<headline>Indonesia's Suharto focuses on currency crisis.</headline>
<byline>Raju Gopalakrishnan</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's President Suharto used an annual state-of-the nation address on Saturday to quell panic on the country's financial markets, pushing his more traditional comments on political events to the background.</p>
<p>The 65-minute speech, broadcast live on national television on the eve of independence day, was dominated by the recent volatility in the rupiah currency, which was floated on Thursday and plunged to a record low the following day, and its effect on the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;It is of a temporary nature and, with the appropriate policy and the calmness of domestic players, the exchange rate will find a new equilibrium in line with prevailing economic fundamentals,&quot; said Suharto, dressed in a sombre grey suit and reading from a prepared text.</p>
<p>He said, however, that monetary and fiscal policies would be tight in the interim, that foreign borrowings should be curbed and that some projects would have to be cut back.</p>
<p>The central bank effectively floated the rupiah on Thursday by scrapping the band under which it intervened in the market and the currency sank to a record low on Friday at 2,960 to the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>Its value has fallen more than 20 percent against the dollar so far this year, with much of the decline coming in the past few months as economic woes in Thailand led to speculative attacks on most currencies in the region.</p>
<p>Jakarta stocks fell 3.94 percent on Friday to 617.71 points, its lowest level this year, because of the weak rupiah. The index has lost more than 100 points since the beginning of the month.</p>
<p>Economic analysts have said worse may be in store because of a domino effect -- many Indonesian companies have unhedged foreign borrowings and the fall in the rupiah may force them to cover by buying more dollars, which would lead to a further fall in the rupiah.</p>
<p>&quot;The suggestion is that Indonesian corporates have at least $5 billion of the $55.5 billion foreign debt unhedged,&quot; the I.D.E.A. consultancy said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;Unhedged debt concerns are primary on players minds now...a contagion effect threatens to undo moral suasion and trigger a fresh round of panic dollar buying by nervous corporates.&quot;</p>
<p>Suharto admitted that foreign borrowings by local companies were quite high but added that the positive fundamentals of the Indonesian economy would soon guide the rupiah back to a more realistic range.</p>
<p>&quot;The recent experience has taught us that in a situation full of uncertainties and upheavals, the economic fundamentals (are) very important and decisive,&quot; he said. &quot;At present, Indonesia's economic fundamentals are very solid. This should automatically reinforce our self-confidence to address prevailing challenges.&quot;</p>
<p>Suharto's comments on politics included a call to alter laws governing the campaign for general elections following unprecedented violence in the run-up to the May national vote.</p>
<p>&quot;Democracy does not need victims. A general election that ensures a democratic process and proceeds smoothly, peacefully...and does not claim human lives and property losses must become one of our political development agendas in the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the government said that its usual amnesty for prisoners on independence day would not include any relief for Jose &quot;Xanana&quot; Gusmao, the jailed East Timorese rebel leader.</p>
<p>Gusmao is serving a 20-year jail sentence at Jakarta's Cipinang jail for resisting Indonesian rule in East Timor, a former Portuguese colony invaded by Indonesia in 1975 and annexed the following year.</p>
<p>Rumours about Gusmao's release appeared after South African President Nelson Mandela held a meeting with the rebel leader during a state visit to Indonesia last month and later sent a letter to Suharto requesting his release.</p>
<p>Justice Minister Utoyo Usman told Kompas newspaper that Gusmao was not on a list of inmates to be freed under the independence day amnesty programme.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
