<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804169" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: N. Korea says religious figure defects from South.</title>
<headline>N. Korea says religious figure defects from South.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A man described as a major South Korean religious figure has defected to North Korea, official North Korean media was quoted as saying on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Tokyo based RadioPress news agency quoted the state-run Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) as saying that O Ik-je, the leader until 1995 of the 130-year old Chandogyo religious group, arrived in Pyongyang on Friday but did not say when he had defected from the south, RadioPress reported. A South Korean government run news agency quoted KCNA as saying he was a member of the main opposition National Congress for New Politics.  </p>
<p>A spokewoman for the party in Seoul said O was a member but could not confirm the KCNA report that he had defected.</p>
<p>O gave a speech on his arrival at Pyongyang's train station slamming South Korean president Kim Young-sam and praising the North Korean leader Kim Jong-il, Radio Press quoted KCNA as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;I have not shirked from doing my best towards the peaceful reunification of the motherland by opposing this facist presidency which is against reunification&quot;, KCNA quoted O as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;I wanted to defect many years ago but until now I could not fulfill this desire,&quot; O added. &quot;It is the highest honour to come to this great society guided by Kim Jong-il... and I wish to uphold the principle of unification of the nation made clear by the great leader Kim Il-sung.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
