<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804146" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam's Pham Van Dong urges democratic reform.</title>
<headline>Vietnam's Pham Van Dong urges democratic reform.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam's senior adviser, Pham Van Dong, has called for further and wide-ranging reforms, including political reforms, and warned that without them the communist country risked falling into recession.</p>
<p>In an unusually outspoken commentary, carried in a weekend edition of the Lao Dong newspaper, the former prime minister said greater democracy was the answer to a slew of difficulties now facing Vietnam's decade old Doi Moi (renovation) process.</p>
<p>He said basic shortcomings had been exposed in recent months in the economy and in the government's managerial and executive apparatus.</p>
<p>But he said it was vital that Vietnam remained committed to furthering its reform process if it wanted to avoid a slide back into poverty.</p>
<p>&quot;The country is faced with two big possibilities: a faster and more sustainable advance to successful achievement of the socio-economic plan to 2000...or a slow down in growth, leading to recession and further backwardness,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The above mentioned situation demands continuous reforms. This is the crimson thread, the core in a chain of the whole revolutionary evolution: in politics, the economy, culture, society, security, national defence and internal and external affairs.&quot;</p>
<p>Dong added that Hanoi should work to expand democracy within its internal political system, and from that allow democracy to spread to the broader population.</p>
<p>&quot;Effectively and efficiently expanding democracy, bringing into play the mastership of the people in the right place, at the right moment, for the right deed, at the right level is the golden key to overcoming the current difficulties,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pham Van Dong, whose official age is 91, is one of the most respected figures in Vietnam and was a close friend of the late president Ho Chi Minh.</p>
<p>His comments, written to mark the August 19 anniversary of Vietnam's 1945 communist uprising, come at a critical time for Hanoi, which is currently embroiled in the complex and arcane process of selecting a new collective leadership.</p>
<p>President Le Duc Anh, 76, and Prime Minister Vo Van Kiet, 74, are due to be replaced in September, while Communist Party chief Do Muoi, 80, has expressed an intention to retire soon.</p>
<p>The lengthy period of debate ahead of their planned stepping-down has seen the emergence of conservative groups who favour more cautious reforms coupled with greater social and other controls.</p>
<p>Vietnam is a single party state and Western democratic ideals remain an anathema.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
