<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804184" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Palestinians to launch boycott of Israeli goods.</title>
<headline>Palestinians to launch boycott of Israeli goods.</headline>
<byline>Paul Holmes</byline>
<dateline>RAMALLAH, West Bank 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Palestinian Authority plans to boycott non-essential goods from Israel in response to a freeze by the Jewish state on the transfer of funds, Palestinian officials said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Somebody should share with us the negative impact (of the freeze) and I think that should be the Israeli producers,&quot; Mohamad Rachid, President Yasser Arafat's economic adviser, told reporters in the West Bank town of Ramallah.</p>
<p>He said the boycott would be gradual and selective.</p>
<p>The Palestinian trade ministry said the embargo would apply to all Israeli goods except those which had previous permits from the commerce, agriculture and supply ministries to enter Palestinian self-rule areas of the West Bank and Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>&quot;Tomorrow we will start working in cooperation with the ministers to know what we need domestically,&quot; Nasser al-Sarraj, the trade ministry's director general, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We will import according to our cash, liquidity and needs. We will not import luxury goods,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu blocked the transfer of millions of dollars of tax money and customs duties Israel owes to the Palestinian Authority after a double suicide bombing in a Jerusalem market on July 30.</p>
<p>He has said the freeze, which the United States has called counterproductive to the peace process, will be eased if Arafat cracks down on Moslem militants.</p>
<p>Israel agreed to the transfer of the funds, which include taxes and other deductions from the wages of Palestinians with jobs in Israel, under an interim agreement on economic links between Palestinian self-rule areas and the Jewish state.</p>
<p>Rachid said the Palestinian Authority no longer felt bound by the protocol, which the parties signed in Paris in 1994 and is meant to provide for the free movement of labour and goods.</p>
<p>He estimated that 96 percent of goods that usually entered self-rule areas were from Israel and worth $9 million a day.</p>
<p>&quot;The green light we have is that except for medicines and necessary foodstuffs, we have the right to discuss all the possibilities (concerning which goods to blacklist),&quot; Rachid said.</p>
<p>Israeli businessmen, such as leading soft drinks distributors, would be advised of the action, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to see them lobbying and campaigning to help us and explain to the Israeli government, in particular the prime minister himself, that what they are doing is damaging the Israeli economy.&quot;</p>
<p>Other measures Netanyahu imposed in the wake of the bombing include a security closure of the West Bank and Gaza, barring entry to Israel to tens of thousands of Palestinian workers.</p>
<p>Arafat, who says he is making a &quot;100 percent effort&quot; on security, has branded the measures &quot;collective punishment&quot; designed to weaken his legitimacy and wreck peace moves.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an attempt to steal money from the VAT and taxes that belong to the Palestinian people,&quot; Arafat said on Saturday.</p>
<p>U.S. envoy Dennis Ross urged Netanyahu to end the financial freeze during his mission to the region earlier this week which was intended to restore Israeli-PLO security cooperation after the bombing.</p>
<p>&quot;We are disappointed every day that there is not a decision to provide the Palestinian Authority (with) these funds because we believe the decision to withhold them is counterproductive,&quot; State Department spokesman James Rubin said on Friday.</p>
<p>He said Washington hoped to see the measures eased in a day or two if there was action on security coordination.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RAMALLAH, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
