<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804194" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish forces kill 27 Kurd rebels in clashes.</title>
<headline>Turkish forces kill 27 Kurd rebels in clashes.</headline>
<dateline>DIYARBAKIR, Turkey 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish security forces killed 27 Kurdish rebels in clashes coinciding with the 13th anniversary of the outbreak of their separatist insurgency, government officials said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The emergency rule governor's office said in a statement that 26 guerrillas from the Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK) died in fighting in the southeastern province of Diyarbakir.</p>
<p>Clashes ensued after the rebels launched an attack on patrolling security forces, killing three state-sponsored village guards overnight.</p>
<p>In the central Anatolian province of Sivas, a group of PKK guerrillas clashed with security forces after attacking a train bound for the city of Diyarbakir from Istanbul.</p>
<p>One rebel, said to be a senior PKK member, was killed in the fighting on Friday evening, Anatolian news agency said.</p>
<p>The PKK, fighting for self rule in the southeast, began their armed struggle on August 15, 1984. Since then, more than 26,000 people have died in the conflict.</p>
<p>On Friday, armed assailants held up a group of 40 Italian and Belgian tourists in a roadblock in southern Turkey and set fire to their vehicles, according to Anatolian.</p>
<p>No group has claimed responsibility for the attack.</p>
<p>According to the local governor in Antalya province, there were indications that the attackers belonged to the PKK.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DIYARBAKIR, Turkey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
