<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804136" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia's Suharto seeks to calm currency markets.</title>
<headline>Indonesia's Suharto seeks to calm currency markets.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's President Suharto, concerned over this week's slump in the rupiah currency, said on Saturday the country would continue enforcing tight monetary and fiscal policies and called for a curb on borrowings.</p>
<p>&quot;The relatively tight fiscal and monetary policies will be maintained until the market situation is calm again and the exchange rate becomes relatively stable at a new level of equilibrium,&quot; he said during an 65-minute speech on the eve of Indonesia's 52nd anniversary of independence.</p>
<p>&quot;With the appropriate policy and the calmness of domestic players, the exchange rate will find a new equilibrium in line with prevailing economic fundamentals,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Suharto's annual state-of-the-nation address, traditionally a wrap-up of political events of the past year, was dominated by comments on the economy and appeared aimed at calming market panic after the falls in the rupiah and stock market.</p>
<p>The currency was floated on Thursday and sank to a record low on Friday of 2,960 per U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>Its value had eroded by more than 20 percent against the dollar so far this year, with much of the decline coming in the past few months as economic woes in Thailand led to speculative attacks on most currencies in the region.</p>
<p>Jakarta stocks fell 2.37 percent on Friday to a 13-month low of 643.01 on news of the float. The index has lost almost 80 points since the beginning of the month.</p>
<p>Suharto said he expected the upheavals in the rupiah would be temporary. But he added it had an effect on the economy nevertheless and called for a curb on borrowings.</p>
<p>&quot;All parties concerned are reminded by recent events to act prudently in borrowing, in order not to rely excessively on loans to finance their business and to seek safer and steadier ways of funding,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This means that the business community and the government should carefully make their choice on projects and activities that should be given priority and those which should be temporarily postponed,&quot; Suharto said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything must be in accordance with the national priority scale and based on the consideration of the current upheavals confronting Indonesia's economy.&quot;</p>
<p>Indonesia has long guided the rupiah toward a four to five percent annual depreciation target. But on Thursday it removed intervention bands on the unit after deciding that protecting it in the face of speculative attacks on all South East Asian currencies would prove prohibitively expensive.</p>
<p>Suharto also said businesses would have to become used to the absence of government protection on currency risks.</p>
<p>&quot;These are normal business practices in many advanced countries,&quot; he said. &quot;Our business community should move toward this direction.&quot;</p>
<p>Suharto said the debt service ratio to exports was &quot;quite high&quot; and said it was due to increasingly significant private foreign borrowings.</p>
<p>Analysts estimate that slightly under 10 percent of Indonesia's $58.6 billion corporate debt is unheeded. The central bank has said government debt was another $53.6 billion at the end of March.</p>
<p>&quot;The suggestion is that Indonesian corporate have at least $5.0 billion of foreign debt unheeded,&quot; the IDEA constancy said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;Unheeded debt concerns are primary on players minds now...a contagion effect threatens to undo moral Susan and trigger a fresh round of panic dollar buying by nervous corporate.&quot;</p>
<p>Suharto, however, said the rupiah would return to a more stable levels on the good economic fundamentals of the economy.</p>
<p>He said economic growth was 7.98 percent in 1996 against a previous provisional estimate of 7.82 percent.</p>
<p>The current account deficit was controlled, inflation had been lowered and foreign exchange reserves had increased, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The recent experience has taught us that in a situation full of uncertainties and upheavals, the economic fundamentals (are) very important and decisive,&quot; he said. &quot;At present Indonesia's economic fundamentals are very solid. This should automatically reinforce our self-confidence to address prevailing challenges.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
