<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804110" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: West presses for elections in Bosnian Serb entity.</title>
<headline>West presses for elections in Bosnian Serb entity.</headline>
<byline>Dan De Luce</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Western countries plan to press for early elections in Bosnia's Serb territory as part of efforts to force hardline nationalist Radovan Karadzic to quit power and face trial for war crimes, diplomats said on Saturday.</p>
<p>International peace mediators debated how to proceed after Karadzic pushed through a ruling in the Bosnian Serb Constitutional Court which struck down a decision by his rival, President Biljana Plavsic, to dissolve parliament and call early elections.</p>
<p>The seven-member court gave no explanation for the ruling and said it would release a full legal opinion soon.</p>
<p>The office of the international High Representative to Bosnia, Carlos Westendorp, dismissed the court's decision as the product of &quot;political pressure&quot; by Karadzic loyalists.</p>
<p>The High Representative was also concerned over allegations that one of the judges who disagreed with the ruling had been badly beaten before the decision was announced.</p>
<p>Court justice Jovo Rosic had suffered serious injuries from the beating and was in hospital in Banja Luka, opposition politician Milorad Dodik was quoted as saying by the Belgrade-based Beta news agency.</p>
<p>Westendorp's deputy, Gerd Wagner, said the court ruling showed Karadzic and his allies were seeking to shore up their position in their power struggle with Plavsic.</p>
<p>&quot;They are reinforcing their dams. The tide is against them,&quot; the German diplomat told Reuters.</p>
<p>The United States and European states agreed that early elections called by Plavsic were the only way forward out of the current crisis in Serb territory, Wagner said.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel that there is growing dissatisfaction in Republika Srpska (Serb republic) with some positions that the leadership has taken and that people in Republika Srpska want to be part of Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;They are not happy with being isolated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Plavsic, herself a nationalist ideologue, has accused her opponents of rampant corruption and of damaging Serb interests by blocking peacemaking efforts.</p>
<p>Plavsic has won strong international support in her conflict and Western governments hope she and opposition parties could deliver a blow to Karadzic's authority in an election.</p>
<p>But international mediators first had to lay the legal ground for early elections. Western officials said Westendorp may choose to exercise his authority as High Representative and overrule the Bosnian Serb court.</p>
<p>Washington wanted the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) to supervise the Serb elections but Russia had yet to lend its support to the proposal.</p>
<p>The OSCE was expected to hold a high-level meeting possibly as soon as next week to decide if it will supervise the Bosnian Serb vote, diplomats said.</p>
<p>With Karadzic allies refusing to participate in the elections, diplomats are concerned the conflict could create two rival authorities, one in Banja Luka run by Plavsic and another in Pale, outside Sarajevo, loyal to the former president.</p>
<p>The power struggle in Serb territory intensified amid growing international pressure for Karadzic to face trial before the U.N. war crimes tribunal, which has indicted him for crimes against humanity.</p>
<p>Karadzic's once unassailable authority was threatened by NATO plans to crack down on Serb special police units which form the backbone of his rule.</p>
<p>The NATO-led peace force announced last week that special police would have to submit to strict supervision by peacekeeping troops and would no longer be allowed to guard suspected war criminals such as Karadzic.</p>
<p>NATO would not say if it had set a deadline for the special police to withdraw from posts around Karadzic's home and office, but the tougher policy fed speculation that Karadzic might be snatched or spirited to a third country.</p>
<p>U.S. envoy Richard Holbrooke, architect of the Dayton peace agreement, warned that Karadzic could face the same fate as two suspects apprehended last month in a NATO raid.</p>
<p>&quot;A free Karadzic is incompatible with a peaceful Bosnia,&quot; Holbooke was quoted as saying in an interview with the German news weekly Focus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
