<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804124" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Cold kills thousands of alpacas in Peruvian Andes.</title>
<headline>Cold kills thousands of alpacas in Peruvian Andes.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Snowstorms and freezing temperatures have killed about 2,500 alpacas in a remote zone of the Peruvian Andes over the last week, local authorities said Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;The snow has buried the alpacas and it's practically impossible to recover either the meat or bodies of these animals,&quot; said Maximo Inca, mayor of Virundo, a town in the southeastern highland region of Apurimac.</p>
<p>He said the region's population of alpacas -- an Andean animal related to the llama and prized for both its meat and wool -- had been reduced to half.</p>
<p>&quot;Help us rescue the rest of our animals,&quot; Inca added in comments to local radio station Radio Programas del Peru.</p>
<p>Heavy snows in the Andes have brought chaos to Peru in the last week, leaving at least nine people dead, stranding hundreds of motorists on remote roads, ruining crops, and cutting off scores of villages.</p>
<p>Weather changes, caused by the El Nino weather phenomenon that warms surface waters in the Pacific Ocean, have contributed to unusually cold temperatures this year in the Andes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
