<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804127" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil landless radicals to restart 'land invasions'.</title>
<headline>Brazil landless radicals to restart 'land invasions'.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Dickson</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leaders of Brazil's Landless Movement (MST) said on Friday they would relaunch &quot;land invasions&quot; this weekend after a six-month hiatus despite warnings by landowners that a bloodbath was in the making.</p>
<p>Walter Gomes, a senior MST leader in the tense Pontal do Paranapanema region in western Sao Paulo state, said the renewed occupations would be a response to the federal government's failure to speed up its land reform program.</p>
<p>&quot;The government promises but never delivers,&quot; Gomes told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>During the land invasions, groups of 200-300 peasant farmers move in on large properties of land that they claim is not being productively used by the landowner. They set up tents and begin farming the land.</p>
<p>The landless movement is perhaps the biggest thorn in the side of President Fernando Henrique Cardoso, who claims his administration has settled more landless families than all previous Brazilian governments combined.</p>
<p>But Cardoso has failed to appease the MST leadership, which is demanding that more than 3,000 families be settled in the Pontal do Paranapanema region alone.</p>
<p>&quot;If blood is spilled it will be a result of the federal government and the Sao Paulo state government's cowardice. This can only result in disaster,&quot; Gomes said.</p>
<p>The MST's militant stance in the cattle-rich Pontal do Paranapanema region has prompted a reorganization of the landowners who are intent on protecting their property from the peasant campaigners.</p>
<p>Under a resurrected organization they called the Democratic Rural Union (UDR), ranchers are leading armed teams of farm laborers and have sworn they will shoot if necessary to prevent the landless peasants from pulling down their fences.</p>
<p>&quot;If a tragedy takes place the fault will belong to the state and federal governments, which have encouraged these invasions,&quot; said UDR spokesman Roosvelt dos Santos.</p>
<p>&quot;The UDR has exhausted all legal measures to avoid these illegal invasions and this lack of respect for the law,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dos Santos said the UDR had requested police support to prevent the land invasions planned for this weekend.</p>
<p>The landless movement, which has made illegal land invasions its trademark, has won widespread domestic and international support for its radical approach to the country's chronic land distribution problem.</p>
<p>Just 2 percent of Brazil's population controls over 50 percent of the arable land in a country where more than 100 people have been killed in land dispute conflicts in the past two years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
