<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804158" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia says not worried on ringgit, big projects.</title>
<headline>Malaysia says not worried on ringgit, big projects.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said on Saturday that speculators were free to hammer down the ringgit as much as they wanted to, as the government was confident of overcoming the crisis in its currency.</p>
<p>&quot;Well they can hammer as much as they like but we will come out of it somehow. We are quite confident we can manage our economy,&quot; Mahathir told reporters after opening a meeting of one of the coalition parties in his ruling National Front.  </p>
<p>The ringgit fell to 2.8250 to the U.S. dollar on Friday, its weakest level since the currency was officially floated in 1973, before recovering back to 2.7700. It has lost 13 percent of its value over the past month.</p>
<p>Mahathir said he would like to see the ringgit return to its old level.</p>
<p>&quot;If you asked me whether I'm happy with the level of ringgit, of course I'm not happy. I want it to go back,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that although long-term benefits such as tourism can gain from a lower currency, &quot;it is the current instability of the ringgit that is the problem.&quot;  </p>
<p>Mahathir also said there was no need for the country to suspend any major infrastructure projects to protect the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;I did not ask for any suspension (of infrastructure projects). I said there (should be) a slowdown, that's all,&quot; he said. &quot;We are not suspending anything because they are private sector projects which will go on.&quot;</p>
<p>Mahathir said the government would also not make a decision on the $6.0 billion Bakun dam project, which is running into a snag, until the contractors for the project resolve their differences.</p>
<p>&quot;We will give the time and they will try to resolve it as soon as they can,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ekran Bhd and Asea Brown Boveri have been given a month to resolve the dispute over a contract to build the dam in Borneo state of Sarawak.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom 603-201 4813; Fax-603-232 6752</p>
<p>-- Email: kuala.lumpur.newsroomzreuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
