<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804183" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Exiled Egypt Islamist says truce call suspect.</title>
<headline>Exiled Egypt Islamist says truce call suspect.</headline>
<byline>Esmat Salaheddin</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>One of the leaders of Egypt's main Islamist militant group said on Saturday from exile that he was suspicious of a call by imprisoned founders of the group for a truce with the government.</p>
<p>Last month six leaders of the Gama'a al-Islamiya (Islamic Group), serving life sentences for their role in the 1981 killing of President Anwar Sadat, issued a statement ordering followers to cease armed struggle against the government.</p>
<p>&quot;For us (those in exile), this truce call is ambiguous. There are a lot of question marks. Hidden fingers are moving it,&quot; Yasser el-Serri, who lives in Britain after being sentenced to death in absentia by an Egyptian court, told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Serri, one of the main Gama'a leaders, said he was in favour of an end to hostilities but only &quot;within the framework of a comprehensive and just solution&quot;.</p>
<p>The truce call was welcomed by Interior Minister Hassan el-Alfi, the official at the forefront of the fight against the Moslem militants.</p>
<p>It was also backed by Sheik Omar Abdel-Rahman, the spiritual leader of the Gama'a jailed in the United States for a plot to blow up New York City landmarks.</p>
<p>But other exiled militant leaders expressed doubts about the call, saying they would continue their armed struggle.</p>
<p>Egypt's official newspaper Al-Ahram on Saturday quoted Salah Hashem, who it said was a founder of the Gama'a and its leader in the southern province of Sohag, as supporting the call to unconditionally lay down arms.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's look for development and investment and put our hands in the state's hand...We should give the fugitives in mountains and farms more chances...to lay down arms and surrender,&quot; Hashem said, according to the paper.</p>
<p>Serri condemned Hashem's remarks, saying they would hurt the safety of young Islamists.</p>
<p>&quot;This is nonsense. This statement will ruin the youths. Security must be for both parties,&quot; Serri said.</p>
<p>Serri said all those detained under martial law should be set free and no civilians should be tried at military courts. &quot;I tell Salah Hashem: 'You yourself are a prisoner inside Egypt even if you are (free) in the street'.&quot;</p>
<p>Egyptian courts are trying more than 150 suspected Moslem militants in three simultaneous cases that analysts say are part of the government's bid to show it has the upper hand in the bloody war with Islamists.</p>
<p>Serri said he doubted that Alfi was sincere in welcoming the ceasefire call and said the minister's statement on Monday did not refer to the fate of the numerous militants who have taken refuge in egypt's mountains and sugar-cane fields.</p>
<p>More than 1,000 people have been killed since Gama'a took up arms in 1992 to overthrow the government and transform Egypt into a strict Islamic state.</p>
<p>Police say they have broken the back of the military wing of the Gama'a through crackdowns and the number of attacks has declined sharply since the mid-1990s, when the militants were killing about one policeman a day.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
