<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804177" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey passes education bill reviled by Islamists.</title>
<headline>Turkey passes education bill reviled by Islamists.</headline>
<byline>Daren Butler</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's parliament on Saturday approved a critical education bill after a marathon debate that rekindled smouldering conflict between the country's Islamists and secularist establishment.</p>
<p>Deputies voted by 277 to 242 in favour of the law after a gruelling three days of debate, culminating in a night-long session of speeches from across the party spectrum.</p>
<p>Education Minister Hikmet Ulugbay hailed the bill's passage in a short speech, alluding to its underlying aim as centrepiece of a military-inspired move against Islamist activism.</p>
<p>&quot;Politics must not be thrust into schools, barracks and the world of faith,&quot; he told weary looking deputies, kept awake through the night by servings of soup and tea. They now face a holiday until the assembly reconvenes on October 1.</p>
<p>Islamists condemn the reforms, drafted by the seven-week-old secularist coalition under Prime Minister Mesut Yilmaz, as a death-knell for many of Turkey's Islamic Imam Hatip schools.</p>
<p>Under the law, compulsory state education is to be extended to eight years from five, effectively bringing an end to the primary section of Imam Hatips.</p>
<p>Such a prospect has fuelled protests by Islamists, both on the streets and in parliament.</p>
<p>Former prime minister Necmettin Erbakan vowed to seek the law's annulment in the constitutional court, where a case is already threatening his Islamist Welfare Party with closure.</p>
<p>&quot;They call it a reform but what they are doing is closing schools,&quot; Erbakan said in a speech to Welfare members shortly after the bill's approval.</p>
<p>&quot;They think they will be able to deceive the nation...but those who try that are ultimately deceiving themselves,&quot; he said, predicting a Welfare victory in the next elections.</p>
<p>Erbakan, Turkey's first Islamist leader, was edged out of office in June after months of secularist pressure led by the armed forces. They demanded introduction of the law in February as part of an anti-Islamist offensive by the authorities.</p>
<p>On Friday, police fired water cannon and used batons to break up a crowd of about 2,000 Islamists gathered outside an Istanbul mosque after midday prayers. More than 100 people were arrested across Turkey in protests outlawed by police.</p>
<p>In the wake of the demonstrations, one Welfare deputy said the real test of public support for the new law would be general elections, expected to take place next year.</p>
<p>&quot;You can ban people from the streets but you cannot ban them from the ballot box,&quot; Welfare deputy Ahmet Demircan told members of the 550-seat assembly.</p>
<p>Conservative Tansu Ciller, Welfare's partner in the previous government, stuck by her Islamist allies in blasting the bill. Formerly a harsh critic of the Islamists, she last year enraged secularists by entering a coalition with Erbakan.</p>
<p>Government MPs tout the law as a reaffirmation of Turkey's secularist foundations set out by Mustafa Kemal Ataturk when he established the republic in 1923.</p>
<p>Rallying behind the military, secularist politicians regard Imam Hatips as a breeding ground for radical Moslem activists.</p>
<p>The schools were originally created to train Imams, or prayer leaders, for state-run mosques, but they now produce more graduates than even the vast religious establishment can absorb.</p>
<p>Turkish consumers have been asked to contribute to funding the reforms with levies on tobacco, alcohol and gambling.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
