<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804148" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian stocks seen rattled by regional currency woe.</title>
<headline>Asian stocks seen rattled by regional currency woe.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The steep plunge on Wall Street and fallout from the latest wave of currency weakness in the region were likely to keep Asian stocks markets unsettled in the week ahead, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average fell 247.37 points, or 3.1 percent, to 7,694.66 on Friday. The sell-off, sparked by the weakening dollar and worries about corporate earnings, was the second biggest point drop ever and left the index at its lowest close since June.</p>
<p>In Jakarta, the stock market was hard hit on Friday and shed nearly four percent when the rupiah fell to a record low after the central bank abolished the currency's intervention band.</p>
<p>Brokers also warned that a market like Hong Kong, which previously was immune from the currency turmoil, was also starting to the feel the heat amid concern that the local dollar would be the next target for speculators.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TOKYO - Tokyo shares are highly vulnerable to Wall Street's drop and if New York continues to fall, it will almost certainly hit shares here, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dow's tumble is likely to hurt sentiment in the market because it will raise concerns that investors with global assets may decrease their holdings in Japanese equities,&quot; said Masaaki Higashida, strategist at Nomura Securities.</p>
<p>Before the Wall Street sell-off, Tokyo traders had expected the Nikkei index of 225 shares to drift around the 19,000 level.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Nikkei closed at 19,326.03, down 278.43 points, or 1.4 percent, from a week earlier.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Nikkei was now likely to test the 19,000 level, and whether it breaks through that would depend on how New York fares.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HONG KONG - A heavy selloff is likely to continue following Hong Kong's biggest weekly point decline in stocks since March, with investors set to flee amid concerns over the local dollar and plummeting Wall Street stocks, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index fell 550.66 points, or 3.31 percent, last week, to close at 16,096.88 on Friday over fears of a speculative attack on the dollar and an upward spike in short-term interest rates.</p>
<p>Friday's 400.83-point drop was the biggest since June 12, and the Hang Seng London Reference Index later slid another 525.39 points, or 3.26 percent, to 15,571.49.</p>
<p>Percy Au-Young, director of research at DBS Securities, said the Hang Seng Index could lose another four to five percent when the market reopens on Tuesday. Hong Kong markets will be closed on Monday for a public holiday.</p>
<p>&quot;People are still uncertain about how long speculation on the (Hong Kong) dollar is going to drag on. The Hang Seng Index is still at a very high level, so that is why there is so much selling pressure,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Friday's slide on Wall Street and the U.S. Federal Reserve policy-setting meeting on Tuesday will add to the market's woes, analysts said, although they expect U.S. interest rates to remain unchanged next week.</p>
<p>They said the Hang Seng Index should find support around 15,200 points.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TAIPEI - Taiwan's stock market was expected to consolidate in the week ahead following Wall Street's plunge, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors will step to the sidelines to see whether Wall Street will fall further,&quot; said International Investment Trust vice-president David Yu. &quot;If Wall Street falls further, it will trigger overall downward corrections in global stock markets -- Taiwan also cannot exempt from this.&quot;</p>
<p>But Yu said loosening liquidity and a recovering domestic economy should help support the market.</p>
<p>On Saturday, the index ended down 64.23 points or 0.66 percent at 9,706.57, down 2.87 percent from last Saturday's 9,993.54. A 9,500-9,850 range was seen for next week.</p>
<p>The central bank was slated to announce second-quarter current account on Wednesday, the economics ministry to report July export orders and industrial output figures on Thursday, and the Directorate General of Budget, Acounting and Statistics to announce July jobless rate on Saturday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SEOUL - Seoul stocks are expected to continue consolidation early next week before starting to recover, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said the index, which fell on Saturday on dull interim company results released the day before, would strengthen next week as analysts predicted better year-end results.</p>
<p>Dealers said the overnight slump of the Dow Jones index did not seem to have affected the domestic market.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dow has soared all through the year, but the Korean market has remained weak. I don't expect any additional investments from the U.S. as our markets are still seen as risky,&quot; said Han Jong-dok, a dealer at Daewoo Securities.</p>
<p>The composite index closed at 748.41 on Saturday, down 12.43 points from the previous Saturday's 760.84.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - A bad week was expected for Singapore shares with fears over the rumoured merging of foreign and domestic tranches of key blue chips compounded by Wall Street's fall.</p>
<p>&quot;Next week is going to be bad,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The dominant factor was likely to be speculation on tranche mergers, which sent the Straits Times Industrials Index (STII) to four-year lows mid-week before a 62-point rebound on Friday.</p>
<p>Wall Street's fall was seen adding to the downside &quot;but I don't expect it to start any panic selling&quot;, said one analyst at a local broking house.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a slide on Monday, but it will be more from domestic factors than Wall Street,&quot; another dealer said.</p>
<p>The STII ended Friday at 1,953.80, up 9.88 points against the previous week's close of 1,943.92.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA - Jakarta stocks are seen remaining weak as the rupiah is likely to stay volatile in the wake of the central bank decision to scrap its intervention band, analysts and brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock market has become the victim of the currency markets. How long would the market remain like this? It will largely depend on the currency markets,&quot; Goei Siauw Hong, head of research with Socgen Crosby Securities, said.</p>
<p>The rupiah fell to a new record low of 2,960 to the dollar on Friday afternoon from its opening level of 2,770/90.</p>
<p>The composite index fell 25.31 points, or 3.94 percent, to close at 617.71 points against last week's close of 675.44.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KARACHI - Pakistani stocks are likely to open up on fresh buying by investors in the week ahead, and dealers expect bellwether stocks to post further gains on buying by overseas investors.</p>
<p>Some local investors are likely to pick up second-tier stocks as prices of some blue chips have risen sharply, said broker Majid Chapra at the Karachi Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Karachi Stock exchange's 100-share index ended up 16.05 points, or 0.85 percent, at 1,914.32, compared to a marginal increase of 1.47 points, or 0.07 percent, to 2,014.8 on August 8.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SYDNEY - Australian shares are set to hold the line in the short term with the profit reporting season the focus of most trader's attention.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index closed at 2,666.2, up 1.5 percent on the day but down 1.7 percent on the week.</p>
<p>The market bolted higher on Friday, supported by a bond market that was buoyed by fresh hopes of a local interest rate easing and stable U.S. policy.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a lot of results coming up. My best guess is that we'll probably be a little bit firmer, but not a lot,&quot; said analyst David Perry of Austock Brokers.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WELLINGTON - All eyes will be on the profit results of key stocks Telecom and Fletcher Challenge next week for an indication of how well corporates are faring in the sluggish New Zealand economy.</p>
<p>Brokers said the share market's 1.6 percent rally on Friday after heavy falls earlier in the week had much to do with the stronger U.S. bond market, which would continue to influence equities next week.</p>
<p>&quot;You will still see volatility when you have got volatility offshore, but the Telecom and Fletcher results will be watched very closely,&quot; said Tim Koller at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>The NZSE-40 Capital Index closed at 2,495.63, 42.82 points lower than last week's 2,538.45 close.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BANGKOK - Thai stocks are expected to move in a tight range next week as investors remain reluctant to take any position because of lingering concerns about the economic downturn and turmoil in regional currencies, analysts said.</p>
<p>Brokers said the recent volatility in foreign exchange markets will continue to dampen foreign investors' interest to buy shares here.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors are really cautious to invest in the region including Thailand after the recent currency turmoil. So I don't think the market will move much next week,&quot; said one analyst at United Securities.</p>
<p>The composite SET index closed at 623.25 points compared with 636.85.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MANILA - Philippine shares are seen extending their retreat next week as the turmoil on the region's currencies continue to plague the market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We think there's even going to be a sharp drop next week still on the currency situation. We may venture into unchartered territory,&quot; said Cilette Liboro, research head of Orion-Squire Capital.</p>
<p>One foreign trader said the market may only see support at 2,200.</p>
<p>The main index closed lower for the seventh straight session on Friday by 44.56 points, or 1.79 percent at 2,448.93 points. Week-on-week, the index fell 198.89 points, or 7.51 percent from the previous Friday's close of 2,647.82 points.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
