<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804122" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAJIKISTAN: Tajik rebel retreats towards Uzbekistan-army.</title>
<headline>Tajik rebel retreats towards Uzbekistan-army.</headline>
<dateline>CHAPAYEV, Tajikistan 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A rebel Tajik colonel fighting government forces has retreated towards the border with Uzbekistan, but his exact whereabouts were unknown, a government field commander said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Rebel Colonel Makhmud Khudoyberdyev had made the village of Chapayev, 20 km (12 miles) south of regional centre Kurgan Tyube in southwest Tajikistan, his base of operations.</p>
<p>But on Friday he retreated ahead of the arrival of government forces, said Colonel Usmon Murchayev, commander of the government's 11th Brigade.</p>
<p>&quot;We entered the base without fighting because Makhmud Khudoyberdyev had left earlier, taking all hardware and people with him and moving toward Uzbekistan,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Murchayev could not give Khudoyberdyev's exact whereabouts but said government forces had surrounded the rebel troops.</p>
<p>Interfax news agency, quoting the president's spokesman, said the rebel colonel had moved into a farm settlement 40 km (25 miles) from the Uzbek border.</p>
<p>Fighting erupted in the capital Dushanbe last week, only weeks after President Imomali Rakhmonov signed a peace agreement with Islamic opposition guerrillas aimed at ending four years of civil war in Tajikistan.</p>
<p>The guerrillas were not involved in the latest clashes, but Khudoyberdyev joined the fray, moving his brigade towards the capital last Saturday.</p>
<p>He appeared to suffer some defeats in four days of fighting and Rakhmonov said on Wednesday the colonel had been dismissed.</p>
<p>A new government commander, Seralisho Mirzoyev, on Saturday arrived in Kurgan Tyube, 110 km (70 miles) south of Dushanbe, another Khudoyberdyev stronghold they seized on Friday.</p>
<p>But he found his task of organising remaining local forces difficult as many had retreated with working military hardware alongside the rebel colonel.</p>
<p>On Saturday a few government tanks rode around Kurgan Tyube, one flying a victorious red flag. Cars stayed off the street, shops were closed, and people seemed afraid to leave their homes.</p>
<p>Khudoyberdyev's home in Kurgan Tyube was looted on Friday, and it remained open on Saturday, with possessions scattered across its rooms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UZBK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHAPAYEV, Tajikistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAJIKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
