<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804109" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAJIKISTAN: Tajik rebels defiant, govt sends more troops.</title>
<headline>Tajik rebels defiant, govt sends more troops.</headline>
<dateline>DUSHANBE 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tajik rebels battling government forces vowed on Saturday to carry on fighting and denied a report that they were retreating towards the border with Uzbekistan.</p>
<p>&quot;We have consolidated our forces in an advantageous location in the mountain heights. We will fight to the bitter end. We would rather die fighting than disgrace ourselves,&quot; Lieutenant-Colonel Sergei Zavarygin told Reuters.</p>
<p>A government field commander said earlier that the rebels led by Colonel Makhmud Khudoyberdyev were heading towards the Uzbek border.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not true that we are going to Afghanistan or to Uzbekistan...We do not want asylum there,&quot; said Zavaryugin, a deputy of Khudoyberdyev whose rebellion sparked fighting this week in the mountainous Central Asian state.</p>
<p>President Imomali Rakhmonov's government is sending more troops to the Shaartuz and Kabodien regions in southern Tajikistan to destroy the last pockets of resistance, Itar-Tass news agency said.</p>
<p>A government source told Tass that Khudoyberdyev had no choice but to lay down his weopons. &quot;The only sensible route open to him is to immediately surrender his arms and stop all armed resistance,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tass said Uzbek border guards had stepped up their patrols and added that Russian peacekeeping troops helping to police the border with Afghanistan were concerned by the Tajik standoff.</p>
<p>A Reuters correspondent travelling with Khudoberdyev's entourage said his men were now about 160 km (100 miles) southwest of the capital Dushanbe.</p>
<p>The latest turmoil in Tajikistan came weeks after Rakhmonov signed a peace agreement with Islamic opposition guerrillas aimed at ending four years of civil war in the impoverished former Soviet republic.</p>
<p>The Islamic guerrillas were not involved in the latest clashes but Khudoyberdyev joined the fray, moving his brigade towards Dushanbe a week ago.</p>
<p>He appeared to suffer some defeats in four days of fighting and Rakhmonov said on Wednesday that he had been dismissed.</p>
<p>Khudoyberdyev and his men refused to surrender their weapons, saying the government could not guarantee their safety, and moved out of their stronghold of Kurgan Tyube, 110 km (70 miles) south of Dushanbe.</p>
<p>A few government tanks, one flying a victorious red flag, drove around Kurgan Tyube on Saturday. Cars stayed off the street, shops were closed and people seemed afraid to leave their homes.</p>
<p>The U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, Bill Richardson, met Rakhmonov in Dushanbe on Saturday to discuss the peace accord between the government and the Islamic opposition, Tass reported.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUSHANBE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAJIKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
