<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804120" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Commander cites money problems for Mir's woes.</title>
<headline>Commander cites money problems for Mir's woes.</headline>
<byline>Adam Tanner</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's space station Mir is in difficulty in orbit because of economic woes on earth, the man who commanded the ship for six months said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;It all derives from earth, from our economy, our affairs, our poor lives,&quot; said Vasily Tsibliyev, who returned to earth with flight engineer Alexander Lazutkin on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Because even that equipment needed to live aboard the station that we requested to be sent -- and we're not talking about coffee, tea and milk for us -- it just doesn't exist on earth,&quot; he said. &quot;Simply the factories don't work, or have insufficient supplies, or they ask for, excuse me, crazy prices.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortuately many things we need on the station just aren't there. It's not because it's a bad station,&quot; Tsibliyev told a news conference at Star City, the cosmonaut training centre outside Moscow.</p>
<p>Tsibliyev was manually docking a Progress cargo ship on June 25 when it collided with Mir in the worst accident in the station's 11 years in space. Russian media reports said he was responsible for the crash, but an official commission has yet to issue conclusions.</p>
<p>Wearing track suits and sneakers and still looking tired after one of the most difficult missions in space exploration history, the two cosmonauts defended their actions aboard the station.</p>
<p>Asked about the June 25 accident, Tsibliyev said his monitors were not working at the time but he was confident that the situation could be corrected until the last minute.</p>
<p>After the accident he said the crew risked their lives by sealing off the punctured Spektr module rather than abandoning ship.</p>
<p>&quot;We didn't think about jumping ship, although in principal at that time we were obliged to throw aside everything and race into the (escape) capsule,&quot; he said. &quot;Despite that, we stayed and continued our work.&quot;</p>
<p>Tsibliyev said since returning he had read media accounts of the Mir's troubles and called many of them inaccurate.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not pleasant to read things about yourself that just aren't true,&quot; he said, adding that had the crew not conducted itself professionally it might have abandoned ship on three separate occasions.</p>
<p>He added the crew worked day and night to keep the station in orbit, often staying up far past the 11 p.m. &quot;goodnight&quot; from Mission Control.</p>
<p>The mission overall, Tsibliyev's second in space, was positive because they survived, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think my second expedition was very happy because we are alive and healthy,&quot; he said. &quot;Perhaps many wanted us to return as corpses, that would have been great -- thank God everything happened as it should have.&quot;</p>
<p>The two cosmonauts had problems up to the last minute when a booster that should have eased their landing on earth did not work. If a cosmonaut rather than cargo was in the right seat of the capsule, another accident might have occurred when the capsule touched down in the Kazakh steppe, Tsibliyev said.</p>
<p>The commander, 43, who suffered an irregular heartbeat after the June accident, said he felt fine. &quot;Yes we are pale, but it's because we haven't seen the sun in a long time,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
