<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804178" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Arafat rejects Israeli &quot;dictates&quot; for crackdown.</title>
<headline>Arafat rejects Israeli &quot;dictates&quot; for crackdown.</headline>
<byline>Khader Abusway</byline>
<dateline>NABLUS, West Bank 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat said on Saturday he would not bow to Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's demand he crack down on militants in the aftermath of July's double suicide attack.</p>
<p>&quot;We reject any dictates or any conditions,&quot; Arafat told reporters in the West Bank town of Nablus when asked about Netanyahu's demand.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Netanyahu) should learn from others and know who the Palestinian people are. He should know who he is talking to.&quot;</p>
<p>Netanyahu sealed off the West Bank and Gaza Strip and halted financial transfers to the Palestinian Authority after last month's bombings in an Israeli market which killed 16 people, including the two attackers.</p>
<p>The Israeli leader demanded Arafat crack down on Islamist militant groups and destroy their infrastructure in areas under his control. The United States has also put pressure on Arafat to increase security cooperation with Israel.</p>
<p>The Palestinian leader blasted Israel for freezing financial transfers it owes the Palestinian Authority under a joint economic protocol.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an attempt to steal money from the VAT and taxes that belong to the Palestinian people,&quot; Arafat said. &quot;He cannot wipe out the agreements.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States said on Friday it was disappointed at Israel's delay in releasing funds to the Authority.</p>
<p>&quot;(U.S. envoy Dennis) Ross said that there are measures done by Israel outside the security framework that have no relation to security. He tried to reach solutions with the Israelis but had no results,&quot; Arafat said.</p>
<p>Washington, chief sponsor of Middle East peace moves, sent Ross to the region in the past week to get Israel and the Palestinians to revive security coordination.</p>
<p>Arafat said he would next week convene a Palestinian &quot;national unity&quot; forum, including opponents of Israeli-PLO peace accords, to discuss the peace crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;It was decided that next Wednesday there will be an expanded meeting of the Palestinian national movement with all its actors,&quot; Arafat said.</p>
<p>The Palestinian leader in February held the first round of &quot;national unity&quot; talks, which included the militant Islamist group Hamas. Hamas boycotted a later round in April, saying Arafat had yet to free some of the movement's activists.</p>
<p>Hamas' armed wing claimed responsibility for last month's suicide attacks in a leaflet whose credibility has been questioned by both Israeli and Palestinian officials. The attackers have yet to be identified.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NABLUS, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
