<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804141" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: FOCUS-Mahathir calm on ringgit, taunts speculators.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Mahathir calm on ringgit, taunts speculators.</headline>
<byline>K. Baranee Krishnaan</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said on Saturday he was confident of overcoming a crisis in the ringgit after the currency fell to its worst level this week.</p>
<p>&quot;We are quite confident of managing our economy,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>Mahathir, who has always maintained that Malaysia's economic fundamentals were strong enough to survive any crisis, admitted that the instability of the ringgit was a problem.</p>
<p>&quot;If you asked me whether I'm happy with the level of the ringgit, of course I'm not happy,&quot; he said. &quot;I want it to go back.&quot;</p>
<p>Fresh speculative selling pushed the ringgit to 2.8250 to the dollar on Friday, its weakest level since it was officially floated in 1973.</p>
<p>But the ringgit staged a sharp recovery to 2.7780 before the end of the day.</p>
<p>Mahathir said the country would ride out speculative attacks on the currency.</p>
<p>&quot;Well, they can hammer (the ringgit) as much they like but we will come out of it somehow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However, foreign exchange dealers and analysts said the worst may not be over for the ringgit as Southeast Asian currencies remain under pressure.</p>
<p>The ringgit, like the Thai baht, the Philippine peso and the Indonesian rupiah, has been hit by speculative attacks and a rush by local companies to hedge foreign borrowings over the past month, losing nearly 13 percent of its value.</p>
<p>The ringgit was around 2.50 against the dollar before it sank along with the baht, rupiah and peso last month. A year ago, it was at 2.49.</p>
<p>Mahathir was reported earlier this week as saying that Malaysia planned to reduce imports and review the implementation of some large projects to manage the currency losses.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not suspending anything because they are private sector projects that will go on,&quot; he said on Saturday, adding that his call for a &quot;slowdown&quot; should not be misinterpreted as a freeze.</p>
<p>Fast-growing Malaysia has several huge infrastructure projects under construction such as the 13.6 billion ringgit ($4.9 billion) Bakun hydro-electric dam and the nine billion ringgit new Kuala Lumpur International Airport.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom 603-201 4813; Fax-603-232 6752</p>
<p>-- Email: kuala.lumpur.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
