<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804181" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel, PLO dig in, wait for other side to blink.</title>
<headline>Israel, PLO dig in, wait for other side to blink.</headline>
<byline>Daniel Sternoff</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian leaders dug deeper into their entrenched political positions as if waiting for the other side to blink first before U.S.-sponsored peace moves could move ahead.</p>
<p>The United States has called on the Palestinian Authority (PA) to improve security cooperation with Israel and has criticised Israel's decision to clamp sanctions on Palestinians after last month's double suicide bombings in a Jerusalem market.</p>
<p>But neither side showed the signs of flexibility needed to help Washington to break a deadlock in the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>Israel says the Palestinian leadership must crack down on Arab militants before it will ease its closure of the West Bank and Gaza or lift a freeze on millions of dollars of customs and tax transfers it owes to the Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat, who says he is making a &quot;100 percent effort&quot; on security, said on Saturday he would not bow to dictates from Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>
<p>&quot;We reject any dictates or any conditions,&quot; Arafat told reporters in Nablus when asked about Netanyahu's demand that he must halt guerrillas activities by anti-Israeli militants.</p>
<p>Arafat accused Israel of trying to steal PA funds, while his economic aide said the PA would parry Israel's sanctions with a selective boycott of Israeli goods.</p>
<p>Netanyahu says he will ease the sanctions in parallel with Arafat's steps against militants.</p>
<p>In a move slammed by Israel as &quot;appeasement of terrorism&quot;, Arafat called for national unity talks with all Palestinian factions including opponents of his peace deals with Israel.</p>
<p>Arafat's economic adviser Mohamed Rachid told Reuters that Arafat would use the unity talks set for Wednesday to explain his strategy to Palestinian movements and &quot;to protect the internal front.&quot;</p>
<p>Rachid also announced plans for a gradual and selective boycott aimed at putting economic pressure on Israel.</p>
<p>&quot;Somebody should share with us the negative impact (of the funds freeze) and I think that should be the Israeli producers,&quot; he said. &quot;We will decide what type of goods from the Israeli market have the right to enter our markets and which goods not.&quot;</p>
<p>The Palestinian leadership has described Israel's sanctions and its closure of the West Bank and Gaza Strip as a collective punishment which can only weaken the PA at the expense of militants.</p>
<p>Arafat cited the arrest by Palestinian forces of three Palestinian car thieves convicted of murdering an Israeli taxi driver in Jericho on Saturday as proof that the PA was working with Israeli police.</p>
<p>Israeli police praised Palestinian forces for apprehending the taxi driver's killers, who received long prison terms in a summary trial, but Israeli officials said cooperation in a criminal case could not replace a crackdown on &quot;terror&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;What is needed is a crackdown on the terrorist infrastructure. In that area the Palestinian Authority has done almost nothing,&quot; Netanyahu aide David Bar-Illan told Reuters.</p>
<p>Arafat held a first round of &quot;national unity&quot; talks, including the militant Islamist group Hamas, in Febrary. Hamas boycotted a later round in April, saying Arafat had yet to free some of its activists.</p>
<p>The Hamas armed wing claimed responsibility for last month's double suicide bombing in a leaflet whose credibility has been questioned by both Israel and the Palestinians. The bombers have yet to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;The call to Hamas to participate in national talks does not bode well,&quot; Bar-Illan said.</p>
<p>&quot;(Arafat) has been making agreements that flirt with the terrorist organisations since the Palestinian Authority was established. We don't believe that this kind of appeasement of terrorism works.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
