<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804106" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO: New Congo names Kasa-Vubu as minister in Belgium.</title>
<headline>New Congo names Kasa-Vubu as minister in Belgium.</headline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Democratic Congo's President Laurent Kabila has appointed Justine Kasa-Vubu, a former member of his cabinet, as minister based in Belgium, state radio reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>Kabila's aides said this meant Kasa-Vubu, who campaigned in Brussels against the former Zaire's ousted dictator Mobutu Sese Seko, would become ambassador with ministerial rank.</p>
<p>Mobutu's veteran ambassador to Belgium, Kingulu Moyanso, was last year asked to leave by the former colonial ruler in circumstances that are still unclear.</p>
<p>Kasa-Vubu is a daughter of Congo's independence president, the late Joseph Kasa-Vubu, from whom Mobutu took over in 1965.</p>
<p>She was one of two members of radical opposition leader Etienne Tshisekedi's UDPS party appointed as ministers after Kabila toppled Mobutu in May at the climax of a seven-month armed campaign. She was civil service minister until Kabila dropped her in a minor cabinet shuffle earlier this month.</p>
<p>The UDPS denounced her and another member for joining the government after Kabila had snubbed Tshisekedi, who expected to be appointed prime minister.</p>
<p>Tshisekedi led the internal campaign against Mobutu's 32-year dictatorship and his legion of fanatical supporters have staged repeated street protests against his exclusion from Kabila's government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
