<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804210" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Aug 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Aug 16.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Saturday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-RAI</p>
<p>- Crown Prince Hassan's son, Prince Rashed, recuperates in hospital after a car crash on the main highway leading to the Red Sea port of Aqaba. Two of his companians die in the accident.</p>
<p>AD-DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- The government plans to open dialogue with opposition parties who are boycotting the coming parliamentary elections due next November; Moslem Brotherhood says the Islamist movement hopes for a fruitful dialogue that produces results.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Abdul-Salam al-Majali says the participation of the Brotherhood in the elections &quot;enriches democracy in Jordan&quot;.</p>
<p>AL-ARAB AL-YAWM</p>
<p>- Prominent political leaders including former prime ministers Taher al-Masri and Ahmad Obeidat plan to boycott parliamentary election; activists circulating a petition to enlist signatures against participation in the coming elections in protest at government policies.</p>
<p>AL-ASWAQ</p>
<p>- Moslem Brotherhood head Abdul Majid Thunaibat says the meeting with the government on Saturday to focus on the mechanism of the dialogue over resolving issues of contention between the two sides.</p>
<p>- Interior Ministry gives political parties which are in breach of the law a year-end deadline to rectify their status.</p>
<p>JORDAN TIMES</p>
<p>- King reiterates door open for dialogue with Islamists; calls on all Jordanians to share in construction of kingdom.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
