<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804276" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India sees high growth, but worried on farm sector.</title>
<headline>India sees high growth, but worried on farm sector.</headline>
<byline>Sambit Mohanty</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian leaders said on Saturday the country could achieve higher economic growth if remaining state controls over businesses were removed, but added a note of concern on stagnating productivity in agriculture.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt that we can easily sustain seven percent growth and by the turn of the century we can achieve eight percent growth,&quot; Finance Minister P. Chidambaram told a meeting of business leaders in the capital.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said India was capable of raising its annual economic growth rate to eight percent by the end of the century but needed to remove remaining controls over business to eradicate poverty.</p>
<p>In 1996/97 (April-March), India's gross domestic product grew by 6.8 percent. Over the past three fiscal years, average annual GDP growth has been seven percent.</p>
<p>More than a third of Indian citizens are below a &quot;poverty line&quot; that measures spending on basic needs in food, clothing and shelter.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said that, despite the strengthening of India's growth since free-market economic reforms were launched in 1991, some continued to hold the belief that a more robust economy will not be enough to alleviate poverty.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of well-meaning people genuinely believe that growth, particularly growth led by industry, will not abolish poverty in this country,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't share this diagnosis. Unless we meet this argument, it will be difficult to move forward.&quot;</p>
<p>Chidambaram said sectors which continued to be highly regulated -- coal, power, petroleum, roads -- performed poorly in 1996/97. &quot;We must continue de-monopolisation for higher productivity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said the government needed to press ahead with removing controls on agriculture, services including insurance, and industry. &quot;We need to deregulate sectors that are highly regulated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral told the same seminar, organised by the Confederation of Indian Industry to mark the 50th anniversary of independence from Britain, that he was keen to ensure fair play for small firms.</p>
<p>Gujral said the government was concerned about complaints from small units that complained about unfair competition from big firms and foreign companies after India launched its market reforms programme.</p>
<p>&quot;The policies we are trying to make will not be of the 16th century capitalism where anybody can come and overwhelm you,&quot; Gujral said. &quot;Outsiders are welcome, but not to take over.&quot;</p>
<p>Gujral said that he was worried by low agricultural productivity, and urged the development of new seeds and dry farming to ensure a healthy farm sector.</p>
<p>&quot;I think productivity is now causing anxiety....I see the ominous signs (of productivity), I hate, I hesitate to use the word, coming towards a halt. And if that halt comes, we'll be in difficulty,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our research and development must aim towards dry farming,&quot; Gujral said. &quot;As water problems continue, we have to think of new technologies.&quot;</p>
<p>Chidambaram said that agriculture was one on the most over-regulated sectors and urged industry to support a special emphasis this year to remove controls over prices, trade and exports.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
