<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804263" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German police detain 31 neo-Nazis at checkpoints.</title>
<headline>German police detain 31 neo-Nazis at checkpoints.</headline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>German police in the eastern state of Thuringia detained 31 right-wing extremists suspected to be on their way to banned rallies to commemorate the 10th anniversary of the death of Hitler's deputy, Rudolf Hess.</p>
<p>A police spokesman said 22 of the extremists had been detained at a checkpoint in the north of the state, which has imposed a blanket ban on gatherings connected with Hess's death.</p>
<p>The extremists were detained for inciting racial hatred and displaying sybols of anti-constitutional organisations.</p>
<p>Hess hanged himself with an electric cord in Berlin's Spandau prison on August 17, 1987, and the date has become a rallying point for the radical right in Germany and other European countries in recent years.</p>
<p>Last year German police detained 160 right-wing activists on the ninth anniversary, while hundreds of neo-Nazis battled with police in Sweden, Norway and Germany's neighbour Denmark, which permits such rallies.</p>
<p>Several German states have imposed blanket bans on Hess rallies this weekend and officials have said they believe many neo-Nazis may head for events in Denmark.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
