<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804200" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi shares continue upward trend, banks dominate.</title>
<headline>Saudi shares continue upward trend, banks dominate.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi shares gained about two percent in the week to Wednesday in moderate trade focused on bank shares, the Riyadh-based Bakheet Financial Advisors (BFA) said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 178.8 points from 175.34 points the previous week.</p>
<p>Of the 62 shares traded in the week, 53 rose, five fell and four were unchanged.</p>
<p>Bank shares accounted for about 53 percent of the week's total trading value which BFA put at 1.088 billion riyals ($290 million), down from 1.75 billion a week earlier.</p>
<p>BFA said 4.9 million shares changed hands in the week down from 7.4 million shares in the previous week.</p>
<p>Tabuk Agriculture Co was the week's major gainer with an eight percent increase to 95 riyals from 88 riyals a week earlier. SCECO-Eastern closed seven riyals higher at 107 riyals and Tabuk Electricity at 92 riyals from 87 riyals.</p>
<p>ZOUJAJ lost 9.6 percent to 150 from a previous 166 riyals and Saudi Industrial Export Co ended the week nine riyals lower at 136 riyals from 145 riyals.</p>
<p>($1=3075 riyals)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
