<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804251" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Sanctions against Angola's UNITA may be delayed.</title>
<headline>Sanctions against Angola's UNITA may be delayed.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan on Friday recommended a delay in withdrawing U.N. troops from Angola and pointed the way toward sanctions against the rebel UNITA movement for flouting peace accords.</p>
<p>Apparently fearing peace accords were unraveling, Annan in a written report to the Security Council, said he wanted at least a six-week delay in further withdrawals of U.N. peacekeepers from Angola.</p>
<p>He said 2,650 military personnel should stay until the end of October &quot;given the precarious situation,&quot; to help feuding parties complete the peace process.</p>
<p>Annan, in a his report, gave the council the green light to impose sanctions by saying last-minute &quot;half-hearted concessions by UNITA , under pressure and on the eve of Security Council deliberations, are no longer acceptable.&quot;</p>
<p>Such sanctions could range from a travel ban to closing UNITA's offices abroad to embargoes on its lucrative diamond trade which worldwide diamond cartels would have to honor.</p>
<p>Behind the scenes, diplomats said Annan wanted the council to hold off while U.N. officials in Angola verified the new promises UNITA had made.</p>
<p>Any sanctions resolution would probably include a two-week grace period to allow UNITA to comply with its demands. Or the council might delay all action for two weeks, the envoys said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not clear whether we move to a sanctions resolution, and if we do exactly what they will be,&quot; a senior council member said.</p>
<p>A resolution would be drafted by the United States, Portugal and Russia, special advisors on the Angola question, who will meet among themselves next week.</p>
<p>Portugal is the former colonial power while Washington and Moscow had conducted a Cold War proxy fight over Angola.</p>
<p>In Washington, State Department spokesman James Rubin told reporters the United States was &quot;ready, willing and able to consider a tighter sanctions package on UNITA.&quot;</p>
<p>He called UNITA leader Dr. Jonas Savimbi &quot;an unhelpful player in the process in recent months.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said that Annan apparently had concluded that &quot;there are some recent steps that Dr Savimbi has taken ... that improves the chances of getting compliance&quot; and that the United States was willing to be flexible.</p>
<p>The council earlier imposed an arms embargo on UNITA but apparently Savimbi is able to keep supply lines open despite the fall of President Mobutu Sese Seko in the neighboring Democratic Republic of the Congo, formerly Zaire. Mobutu was one of UNITA's principal backers.</p>
<p>The council has demanded that UNITA demilitarize all its forces, transform its radio station into a non-partisan broadcasting facility and cooperate fully in extending government administration throughout the country as required in 1994 peace agreements signed in Lusaka, Zambia.</p>
<p>After two decades of civil war, UNITA, the National Union for the Total Independence of Angola, entered into a unity government in April with the MPLA, the Popular Movement for the Liberation of Angola.</p>
<p>But UNITA still controls about 70 percent of the country, including Angola's diamond mines, and only a minority of its fighters have been demobilized and incorporated into a new national Angolan army.</p>
<p>The conflict, after Angola gained independence from Portugal in 1975, became a superpower proxy fight with the United States and the former white government of South Africa supporting Savimbi and the Soviet Union and Cuba supporting the now-ruling MPLA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
