<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804232" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Thousands mourn Elvis through the night.</title>
<headline>Thousands mourn Elvis through the night.</headline>
<byline>Michael Conlon</byline>
<dateline>MEMPHIS, Tenn. 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Like pilgrims to a holy place, 30,000 Elvis Presley fans sang to his music, locked hands and held candles outside the home where he died 20 years ago on Saturday in the largest outpouring of its kind since the king of rock n' roll stopped making the music they loved.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the largest crowd we have ever, ever had,&quot; Todd Morgan of Elvis Presley Enterprises told the assemblage in the closed four-lane highway outside Graceland mansion. &quot;Elvis is a bigger star than he ever, ever was.&quot;</p>
<p>Some stood in line for 24 hours to be among the first to walk up the hill to the white-columned mansion, circle the graveyard of Presley and his family, and return to the street -- a 10-minute stroll. Police said 30,000 people were outside Graceland when the vigil ceremonies took place on Friday night and many of them, along with more still arriving, waited in line to make the same walk all night long until the gates closed at daybreak on Saturday.</p>
<p>Twenty years ago this same night the 42-year-old Presley, addicted to a nightowl lifestyle, stayed up all night, finishing a racketball game with a cousin at dawn, by contemporary accounts. Facing a concert tour beginning the next evening he retired to his bedroom and told fiance Ginger Alden that he was going into the bathroom to read. She told reporters she found him dead in the bathroom in early afternoon, a death later ascribed to a heart attack induced by a combination of prescription drugs.</p>
<p>But from death, Presley and his music drew new life.</p>
<p>At this year's vigil, fans from around the world stood side-by side, singing along with Elvis recordings broadcast over loudspeakers, songs that continue to be hot sellers today. They were all ages and mostly white -- couples in their 50s and grandmotherly-looking women standing shoulder-to-shoulder with young couples.</p>
<p>Fan club presidents from around the world, led by the Elvis Country Fan Club from Texas which began organizing the vigil years ago, marched up the driveway first to take positions on each side, lighting the way with battery-powered candles.</p>
<p>For some, age had taken a toll. They were told not to go unless they could stand in position for at least an hour.</p>
<p>Sylvia Gibson of Miami, head of a Florida fan club, has kept the same vigil for 19 years. The first year after Presley's death, she said, it was an impromptu caldle-lit gathering on the lawn.</p>
<p>&quot;They never write about all the good Elvis did -- his charities. He paid people's mortgages,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Those in line to pass the graveyard under a nearly full moon carried candles, some stuck in plastic foam or clear plastic cups. Many clutched a single rose, most red but some yellow.</p>
<p>&quot;My husband brought me back for my 30th wedding anniversary as a gift. I brought my daughter and my best friend along&quot; said Sherry Hutchison of Independence, Mo., as she waited to walk to the grave.</p>
<p>&quot;We were here five years ago,&quot; she said, &quot;for my 25th anniversary.&quot;</p>
<p>During a 40-minute ceremony before fans began their trek to the Presley grave, the hot and humid night air was saturated with the voice of Elvis, singing the old spiritual &quot;Farther Along&quot; and other songs. During a moment of silent prayer there were only the voices of the insects in the old ash trees on the mansion's lawn.</p>
<p>When the preliminaries closed with &quot;I Can't Help Falling in Love with You&quot; the crowd took up the song in full, swaying and lifting lighted candles into the night. Some locked hands; others shed tears.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEMPHIS, Tenn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
