<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804215" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tributes mark anniversary of Elvis Presley's death.</title>
<headline>Tributes mark anniversary of Elvis Presley's death.</headline>
<byline>Michael Conlon</byline>
<dateline>MEMPHIS, Tenn 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Elvis Presley's fans and friends offered non-stop tributes on the 20th anniversary of his death on Saturday after at least 30,000 people filed by his grave during the night.</p>
<p>&quot;This man is still living and breathing in each and every one of us that knows how great, how sweet, how kind, how decent, how fair he was and is,&quot; said Sam Phillips, founder of Sun Records in Memphis where Presley got his start.</p>
<p>&quot;You, me -- we are the luckiest people in the world to have come along in this big old wonderful central great world, the creation of God, to have lived and seen and known Elvis Aron Presley,&quot; he told a three-hour memorial service at the University of Memphis where speaker after speaker eulogized Presley.</p>
<p>The ceremony took place 20 years nearly to the hour of Presley's death at age 42 from a drug-induced heart attack.</p>
<p>Officials at Presley's Graceland mansion said they were booked solid on Saturday for guided tours of the home where the king of rock n' roll lived, died and is buried.</p>
<p>The mansion's grounds from Friday night until Saturday morning were open for a candlelight vigil that officials had to extend by more than two hours to accommodate those who were in line at daybreak.</p>
<p>When the wrought iron, music-noted gates to the grounds were finally closed to foot traffic, the silent, candle-carrying pilgrims had heaped a 4-foot (1.2 metre) high mound of flowers, teddy bears and mementoes on his grave.</p>
<p>&quot;So many people came from so very far away. That was awesome. So many different languages,&quot; said a woman from Houston who gave her name only as Gail.</p>
<p>A member of the Elvis Country Fan Club, she was part of an honor guard that stood all night with other fan club presidents from around the world on the lane leading from the street up the hill to the mansion-side graveyard.</p>
<p>Todd Morgan, director of creative services for Elvis Presley Enterprises, told the crowd as the vigil began that they were the largest assembly ever to show up for what has become an annual event.</p>
<p>&quot;Elvis is a bigger star than he ever, ever was,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Saturday's Memphis Commercial Appeal newspaper said of the tribute:</p>
<p>&quot;They love him tender. They love him sweet. And because he said so, they haven't let him go ... Like George Washington and Jesus Christ, Elvis looms larger now than he ever did in life.&quot;</p>
<p>In the tiny plot next to the mansion's swimming pool where Presley, his parents and his paternal grandmother are laid to rest under inscribed bronze tablets, the steamy Tennessee dawn revealed evidence of the night-long tribute.</p>
<p>Candles, some dripping wax, others in glass jars, burned at the base of a nearby tableau of Christ crucified flanked by two kneeling angels in white marble.</p>
<p>There were cards, notes, baskets of fresh flowers and sprays of plastic ones. Many dropped a single rose or two as they passed the graves.</p>
<p>An orange placard signed by one Nancy Falcon read: &quot;Elvis, your beautiful voice echoes gently on my mind. Your soft blue eyes enter my soul like a summer breeze.&quot;</p>
<p>Some had stood in line for 24 hours to be among the first to walk to the white-columned mansion, circle the graveyard and return to the street -- a 10-minute stroll. Police said 30,000 people were outside Graceland when the vigil began at dusk on Friday and many more arrived during the night.</p>
<p>The vigil, followed by a concert on Saturday night, were the last major events in a weeklong observance marking the two decades since Presley's death on Aug. 16, 1977.</p>
<p>Twenty years ago Presley, overweight and in and out of hospitals often, stayed up all night, finishing a racquetball game with a cousin at dawn. He was scheduled to begin a concert tour the next night and retired to his bedroom, telling a companion he was going into the bathroom to read.</p>
<p>The companion told reporters she found him dead in the bathroom early in the afternoon.</p>
<p>At this year's vigil the fans were of all ages and mostly white -- couples in their 50s and grandmotherly looking women standing shoulder-to-shoulder with youngsters.</p>
<p>Sylvia Gibson of Miami, head of a Florida fan club, has kept the same vigil for 19 years. The first year after Presley's death, she said, it was an impromptu candle-lit gathering on the lawn.</p>
<p>&quot;They never write about all the good Elvis did -- his charities. He paid people's mortgages,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEMPHIS, Tenn"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
