<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804207" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi cement mkt set for glut as factories expand.</title>
<headline>Saudi cement mkt set for glut as factories expand.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Arabia's cement market faces a glut in coming months as expansion projects go on stream against a background of slumping demand, a London-based Arabic newspaper said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Saudi cement companies have fixed a period of three months for the start of the real impact of the supply surplus,&quot; al-Sharq al-Awsat newspaper quoted cement industry sources as saying.</p>
<p>The Saudi cement market has been saturated, with a drop in demand due to a slowdown in the construction sector, the newspaper said, adding that companies were storing excess production.</p>
<p>It said revenues from sales had also been affected by stoppages for routine maintenance.</p>
<p>Six main Saudi cement producers have reported a drop in  sales revenues in the first six months of 1997 to 752.14 million riyal ($200 million) down from 789.9 million during the same period last year, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>It said Saudi Arabia's cement companies had reported a 10.34 percent drop in profits in the first half of 1997 compared with the same period last year.</p>
<p>The newspaper said factory expansions, and a new firm expected to start production later this year, would add seven million tonnes a year to current production levels.</p>
<p>But Industry and Electricity minister Hashem bin Abdullah bin Hashem Yamani said in June that cement output, which in 1996 stood at 16 million tonnes, was expected to grow to 22 million tonnes by the end of the century.</p>
<p>He projected demand at 17.5 million tonnes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
