<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804230" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. shuttle crew captures satellite.</title>
<headline>U.S. shuttle crew captures satellite.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The space shuttle Discovery picked up a free-flying satellite on Saturday, ending a nine-day health check on Earth's upper atmosphere.</p>
<p>The satellite named CRISTA-SPAS was plucked from orbit by the shuttle's 60-foot (18-metre) long robot arm at 11:13 a.m. EDT (1513 GMT), as the two craft soared 185 miles (296 kms) above the Pacific, north of New Zealand.</p>
<p>&quot;Good job Discovery,&quot; mission control's Ellen Ochoa said. &quot;Congratulations on a very smoothly rendezvous and grapple.&quot;</p>
<p>Astronaut Jan Davis, operating the arm from the cabin, then set about berthing the 7,000-pound (3,200-kg) spacecraft in the shuttle's cargo bay.</p>
<p>The German-built spacecraft, which was released by the shuttle crew last week, has been probing Earth's upper atmosphere to learn more about the depletion of the ozone layer, which screens out harmful ultraviolet radiation.</p>
<p>The satellite's most surprising finding was evidence of much more water vapor in the upper atmosphere than scientists had expected. The results seem to back a theory that the Earth is being bombarded thousands of times a day by house-sized, water-laden comets.</p>
<p>Scientists are eager to get their hands on the data recorded aboard the spacecraft. Only a fraction of its atmospheric measurements were transmitted to the ground.</p>
<p>Discovery was due to head back to Earth on Monday. Weather conditions were expected to be favorable for a landing at the Kennedy Space Center in Florida.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
