<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804219" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UPS, Teamsters extend talks, union plans rallies.</title>
<headline>UPS, Teamsters extend talks, union plans rallies.</headline>
<byline>Peter Szekely</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Negotiators for United Parcel Service and the Teamsters union extended a marathon bargaining session late into the night on Friday as union president Ron Carey unveiled plans to rally strikers and their supporters.</p>
<p>With the strike concluding its 12th day, the nation's biggest package delivery service and second-largest union stepped up their efforts to reach a settlement, said Susan King, spokeswoman for Labor Secretary Alexis Herman.</p>
<p>Carey paid compliments to Herman and chief federal mediator John Calhoun Wells for their efforts to settle the strike. But he announced plans for rallies in 30 U.S. cities next week and said unions representing UPS workers in several European countries were planning job actions to drum up support for the 185,000 American workers on strike.</p>
<p>&quot;A contract that provides the good jobs for working families certainly won't be won at the bargaining table,&quot; he told a news conference. &quot;The only way you can win that is either on the picket lines, and in the community.&quot;</p>
<p>The two sides began informal talks on Thursday morning at the request of Herman and continued their discussions with federal mediators straight through Friday night, taking only a few hours break early on Friday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;We think they're redoubling their efforts to reach an agreement,&quot; King told reporters around midday.</p>
<p>At the White House, spokesman Mike McCurry declined to characterize the talks but noted: &quot;They're talking and that's good.&quot; United Parcel Service made no comment as the talks continued.</p>
<p>Clearly buoyed by opinion polls showing the strikers winning the lion's share of public support, Carey declared his resolve not to back down from the union's demand that UPS convert more part-time jobs into higher paying full-time jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;The Teamster fight for good full-time jobs has become America's fight as well,&quot; he said at the news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;It's obvious that there have been no agreements reached,&quot; he added. &quot;However, I will continue to negotiate as long as there is hope.&quot;</p>
<p>The strike was causing severe problems for some businesses and a blood bank.</p>
<p>A major U.S. blood bank reported it has destroyed more than 800 pints (approximately 400 litres) of blood because overburdened delivery companies Federal Express Corp. and Airborne Express could no longer guarantee their usual overnight delivery.</p>
<p>The group, America's Blood Centers, suggested its blood banks set up mobile collection units near UPS picket lines so that striking UPS workers can donate blood.</p>
<p>The UPS workers have been on strike since Aug. 4 to demand full-time status and benefits for some of the company's many part-time employees. The walkout is the biggest since a three- day strike by 400,000 Teamster truckers in 1976, Hurd said.</p>
<p>The strike is putting increasing pressure on both sides.</p>
<p>The strikers are getting help from other unions, but finding it tough to live on $55-a-week strike benefits.</p>
<p>The company estimates it is losing $300 million a week, putting its losses so far at about $500 million or more. UPS carried 80 percent of the small packages in the United States before the strike. It has tried to keep priority deliveries such as medical supplies going with management help, but its volume has shrunk to about 10 percent of normal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
