<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804292" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India RBI preparing steps to convertible rupee.</title>
<headline>India RBI preparing steps to convertible rupee.</headline>
<dateline>GOA, India 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) is busy clearing barriers on the road to full convertibility of the rupee, senior central bankers told an annual meeting of Forex Association of India on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;A stage has come when we cannot afford a negative answer to the question whether capital account convertibility is desirable,&quot; G. Padmanabhan, RBI's deputy general manager, told a workshop on capital account convertibility (CAC).</p>
<p>&quot;Someone drew a parallel. Your daughter has to be married. The question is when,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Each of the issues is being discussed threadbare,&quot; he said, referring to a roadmap set by an official panel earlier this year for the rupee's full float in three years.</p>
<p>The RBI has already announced some steps, like excluding external commercial borrowings (ECBs) of over 10 years maturity from an annual ceiling on the total ECBs that can be raised by Indian companies. More measures are in the pipeline.</p>
<p>The panel, headed by former RBI deputy governor S.S. Tarapore, recommended three years of phased reforms before launching a rupee convertible on the capital account.</p>
<p>RBI officials at the Goa meeting said they were expressing their personal views.</p>
<p>&quot;We have gone beyond that point (of discussing the desirability of full float),&quot; P. Krishnamurthy, deputy general manager at the RBI's department of external investments and operations, said.</p>
<p>Krishna Kumar, treasurer at engineering firm Larsen &amp; Toubro Ltd, said CAC would help globalisation of Indian industry.</p>
<p>He said domestic savings alone cannot generate the resources required to build infrastructure, the lack of which was slowing growth in industrial production.</p>
<p>&quot;CAC is one of the major options,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>CAC will lead to more realistic interest rates and a deepening of financial markets both of which would benefit Indian firms to become more competitive, he said.</p>
<p>Several delegates felt the pre-conditions for full float set by the committee were too tough.</p>
<p>The panel had recommended a reduction in the fiscal deficit to 3.5 percent of gross domestic product, lowering inflation to a 3-5 percent range and cutting banks' bad loan portfolio to five percent of total loans from over 13 percent now.</p>
<p>&quot;We should be looking at the trends rather than the absolute numbers,&quot; an RBI official said.</p>
<p>The RBI officials said the central bank had taken up issues concerning taxation on new foreign exchange products that would emerge once the rupee is floated.</p>
<p>Documentation of new derivative products and compliance with Indian laws are also under discussion, an official of the Foreign Exchange Dealers Association of India (FEDAI) said.</p>
<p>The Institute of Chartered Accountants of India is working on uniform accounting standards in consultation with the RBI, FEDAI officials said.</p>
<p>A few bankers expressed concern about lurking fears of capital flight and its consequences.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a fear the rupee will be traded in London and New York and we won't have much of a job,&quot; said a treasurer at a private Indian bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOA, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
