<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804267" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish town transformed before neo-Nazi protest.</title>
<headline>Danish town transformed before neo-Nazi protest.</headline>
<byline>Steve Weizman</byline>
<dateline>ROSKILDE, Denmark 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>This quiet Danish town was transformed on Saturday as hundreds of police prepared to keep Danish and foreign neo-Nazi groups from clashing with leftist counter-demonstrators.</p>
<p>Roskkilde, west of Copenhagen, resembled a town under siege. Police carrying tear gas guarded all entries to the town, scrutinising vehicles and checking their occupants.</p>
<p>The heaviest concentration of police was around the central railway station where officers told Reuters they feared rival groups arriving by train might clash.</p>
<p>Police said Roskild residents had been warned to stay out of the way on Saturday afternoon because of the possibility of clashes.</p>
<p>The neo-Nazi groups are marching to mark 10 years since the death of Hitler's deputy Rudolf Hess.</p>
<p>A force of 800 officers has streamed into Roskilde to keep up to 400 neo-Nazis and 1,000 of their sworn opponents apart.</p>
<p>&quot;We must hope that both sides behave better than last time but we shall plan for the worst eventuality, that's why we are deploying so many,&quot; Roskilde police chief Uffe Kornerup said.</p>
<p>A 1995 march in the town, against the arrest locally of German-American neo-Nazi leader Gary Lauck, turned into a rout when neo-Nazis were scattered by a far larger group of leftists who later stoned the buses taking the right-wingers home.</p>
<p>Jonni Hansen, chairman of the Danish National Socialist Movement (DNSB) says he has no confidence in the police to safeguard his marchers this time.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't trust the police, but we are well-prepared,&quot; he told Reuters. He did not give details.</p>
<p>Hansen was warned by police on Saturday that detailed threats against him had been received. The DNSB is secretive about its strength but is believed to number about 200.</p>
<p>Anti-Nazi groups say that local Hess marchers' numbers will be swollen by allied groups from Norway, Sweden and Germany and from Britain.</p>
<p>Denmark's liberal freedom of speech laws have made it something of a neo-Nazi haven, to the irritation of neighbouring Germany, where Nazi tracts and paraphenalia are banned and to the discomfort of Danes who remember wartime Nazi occupation.</p>
<p>German police are also bracing for clashes with neo-Nazi groups throughout the weekend of the Hess anniversary.</p>
<p>Hess hanged himself with an electric cord in Berlin's Spandau prison on August 17, 1987, and the date has become a rallying point for the radical right in Germany and other European countries in recent years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROSKILDE, Denmark"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
