<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804258" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Ex EU-Commissioner seeks Irish presidency.</title>
<headline>Ex EU-Commissioner seeks Irish presidency.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Hill</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>One of Ireland's former European Union Commissioners, Michael O'Kennedy, has emerged as a candidate to succeed President Mary Robinson when she steps down in October.</p>
<p>Kennedy, a member of the Fianna Fail party, said in remarks to a summer school quoted by the Irish Times that he felt his domestic and international experience coupled with 25 years as a senior lawyer suited him for the job.</p>
<p>His statement means that Ireland's biggest political party, Fianna Fail, could have at least two hopefuls for the presidential job after former prime minister Albert Reynolds formally entered the race last weekend.</p>
<p>But both the government and opposition are likely to agree not to hold an election if Northern Ireland peace broker John Hume heeds appeals to take on the vacancy caused by Robinson's nomination as U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights.</p>
<p>Hume, leader of Northern Ireland's Social, Democratic and Labour Party (SDLP), has said that he is considering whether to stand and will make his plans clear in coming weeks.</p>
<p>Hume, 60, is a member of the British and European parliaments and has suffered from overwork during four years of efforts to help launch a Northern Ireland peace process, according to his party colleagues.</p>
<p>That process gets under way in Belfast in September with the SDLP's ideological ally, Sinn Fein, likely to be admitted after its guerrilla allies, the Irish Republican Army (IRA), called a truce on July 20.</p>
<p>Hume has led a personal crusade to get all sides to the negotiating table in recent years but faces the prospect that the main pro-British Protestant group, the Ulster Unionist Party, may not take part in the talks directly.</p>
<p>But if Sinn Fein, which seeks an end to British rule of Northern Ireland, were to be joined at the talks by the UUP, Hume would be more likely to take on the Irish presidency and become the first president from Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>Anyone from Northern Ireland can have an Irish passport, under the Irish constitution, and all political parties would be likely to agree on Hume as the next president to avoid a costly election after June 6 national polls.</p>
<p>Kennedy said his candidature was appropriate because Ireland is likely to consider changing its constitution, which lays claim to Northern Ireland, as part of a political settlement being pursued at the Belfast talks.</p>
<p>Under Anglo-Irish proposals Ireland will shelve its claim and Britain will change its 1920 government of Ireland act to put the onus on Northern Ireland's 1.5 million people to work out their own future together.</p>
<p>&quot;The next seven years will see major changes in our society, particularly in the area of North-South relationships,&quot; O'Kennedy told the summer school.</p>
<p>&quot;This is likely to involve complex changes to our constitution and therefore leadership, constitutional knowledge and sound judgement will be required of the President.&quot;</p>
<p>Kennedy's candidature is likely to prompt former justice minister Maire Geoghegan-Quinn to declare her candidature within the next few days, party sources said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Bertie Ahern, who heads a minority Fianna Fail government, would be weakened if he lost a parliamentary Deputy to the presidency and was likely to welcome her candidature since she quit the asembly last year, they said.</p>
<p>Dana, a winsome one-time singing star and devout Catholic, has also expressed interest in the post after right-wing &quot;pro-life&quot; groups asked her to stand, but she is unlikely to get the required 20 nominations from parliament, the sources said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
