<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804247" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Police grab 140 in cat-and-mouse with neo-Nazis.</title>
<headline>Police grab 140 in cat-and-mouse with neo-Nazis.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gray</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>German police played in a tense cat-and-mouse game with neo-Nazis on Saturday and detained around 140 extremists suspected of heading for forbidden rallies to mark the 10th anniversary of the death of Hitler's deputy Rudolf Hess.</p>
<p>In neighbouring Denmark, where freedom of speech laws allow neo-Nazis more scope for public display, about 150 Scandinavians, Germans and Dutch marked Hess's death with a rally in the town of Koege, switching from nearby Roskilde at the last moment to avoid clashes with leftists.</p>
<p>Police in the central German state of Hesse said they had taken 78 people into temporary custody at traffic checkpoints set up to stop extremists gathering at Hess rallies over the weekend.</p>
<p>A Hesse police spokesman said officers had seized knives, music cassettes and placards with extremist slogans.</p>
<p>In the eastern state of Thuringia, police detained 60 right-wing extremists for inciting racial hatred and displaying symbols of anti-constitutional organisations.</p>
<p>Special information lines run by neo-Nazi groups had told members to have plenty of petrol in their cars and fresh batteries for mobile telephones so they could get to rallies without having to stop at service stations.</p>
<p>The extremists kept their plans top secret in a bid to outwit both police and the media. Some reports suggested they planned a central gathering somewhere in Germany.</p>
<p>In the eastern city of Halle, around 40 left-wing demonstrators attacked about 50 right-wingers holding a small rally in the city centre to mark Hess's death. Five of the left-wingers were detained over the scuffles, police said.</p>
<p>Around 40 neo-Nazis in the northern city of Braunschweig dispersed on police orders after gathering at the main rail station. Police seized placards bearing an image of Hess and the words &quot;Freedom Fighter, Peace Messenger, Martyr&quot;.</p>
<p>Appointed deputy Fuehrer in 1932, Hess was effectively in charge of the Nazi party until 1941, when he parachuted into Scotland on a mysterious mission.</p>
<p>Historians dispute his exact intention, some believing he wanted to make peace with Britain and press for an Anglo-German alliance against the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Hess hanged himself with an electric cord in Berlin's Spandau prison on August 17, 1987, and the date has become a rallying point for the radical right in Germany and other European countries.</p>
<p>Some neo-Nazi groups claim he was murdered by the Allies, making him a martyr to their nationalist cause.</p>
<p>Last year German police detained 160 right-wing activists on the ninth anniversary, while hundreds of neo-Nazis battled with police in Sweden, Norway and Denmark, which permits such rallies.</p>
<p>Several German states have imposed blanket bans on Hess rallies this weekend and officials have said they believe many neo-Nazis may head for events in Denmark.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
