<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804213" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Aug 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Aug 16.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Turkish press on Saturday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>SABAH</p>
<p>- Former prime minister Tansu Ciller is hoping to win the support of voters from the Islamist Welfare Party, her partner in the previous government.</p>
<p>- A leading businessmen says banks are deceiving the public with inflated profit figures.</p>
<p>MILLIYET</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Mesut Yilmaz says in an interview he expects the Islamist Welfare Party to split up after its loss of power.</p>
<p>- Economy officials say preparations are being made on a draft law to regulate public borrowing.</p>
<p>HURRIYET</p>
<p>- Twenty-five police officers are injured in a protest by Islamists after Friday prayers in Istanbul.</p>
<p>- The energy minister has ordered an investigation into charges connected with a tender made by electricity company TEDAS.</p>
<p>YENI YUZYIL</p>
<p>- An article of the secularist education bill is rejected because of opposition to plans for the religious directorate to control religious education.</p>
<p>RADIKAL</p>
<p>- President Suleyman Demirel criticises protesters who demonstrated after Friday prayers.</p>
<p>DUNYA</p>
<p>- The level of manufacturing capacity utilisation falls in July to 80.4 percent from 82 percent in May.</p>
<p>ZAMAN</p>
<p>- A state minister says Turkey will play a leading role in the Turkic republics of central Asia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
