<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804236" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. holds off on special status for Argentina.</title>
<headline>U.S. holds off on special status for Argentina.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secretary of State Madeleine Albright proclaimed Argentina one of the United States' &quot;closest friends and partners&quot; on Friday but held off granting it the status of a major non-NATO ally.</p>
<p>With President Bill Clinton scheduled to visit Argentina in October, it is expected the announcement of that status will be saved for then, U.S. officials said. Albright said earlier this week Washington was likely to grant recognition.</p>
<p>Argentine Foreign Minister Guido Di Tella &quot;and I will be discussing this subject, but there is no announcement being made,&quot; Albright told a news conference at the start of their talks in Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the kind of decision that requires consultation with Congress,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The designation would put Argentina in the same category with such countries as Israel, Egypt, Japan, South Korea and Jordan.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a category of our law that is intended to recognize a special political relationship with the United States that carries with it some limited military benefits, and it's a designation that we grant to very good friends,&quot; Albright said.</p>
<p>Argentina is &quot;one of the closest friends and partners the United States has in this hemisphere and around the world,&quot; Albright said, adding, &quot;In areas as diverse as economic reform and peacekeeping, Argentina is becoming a global leader.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain, which fought a war with Argentina in 1982 over the Falkland Islands, had been concerned about the U.S. designation.</p>
<p>But after bilateral discussions, including a telephone conversation this week between Albright and British Foreign Secretary Robin Cook, London and Washington indicated there were no serious problems.</p>
<p>British embassy spokesman Robert Chatterton Dickson said in a telephone interview: &quot;We discussed it with the United States, and we're satisfied that (the designation) won't affect our ability to defend the Falklands.&quot;</p>
<p>Diplomats said one of London's big worries was that the United States, which two weeks ago lifted a 20-year-old ban on selling high-tech weapons to Latin America, would allow the sale of F-16s or other advanced arms to Argentina.</p>
<p>Britain is not concerned that Argentina would have access to ammunition and spare parts from excess Pentagon stocks, as other countries named major non-NATO allies do, the diplomats said.</p>
<p>Albright, asked at the news conference if Washington had assured Britain there would be no sales of advanced arms to Argentina, said merely that Britain had been informed of the possible U.S. decision on ally status.</p>
<p>At a news conference on Wednesday, however, she made the point that the status did not mean countries would automatically be allowed to buy U.S.-made F-16 jets, that such high-tech sales were made on a case-by-case basis and that the designation did not establish a security relationship.</p>
<p>Chile and other countries are also being considered for major non-NATO ally status, Albright said.</p>
<p>On Friday she went out of her way to say that the designation signified &quot;an important and symbolic relationship&quot; and that Britain was the United States' closest NATO ally. The NATO pact pledges the two countries to come to each other's defense.</p>
<p>Di Tella declared Argentina's relations with Britain were &quot;not good but excellent&quot; and expressed confidence the two countries could manage any disagreements in the South Atlantic. Albright said Cook gave her the same assessment.</p>
<p>Argentina has disputed the sovereignty of the islands it calls the Malvinas with Britain for more than 160 years. In 1982 a military junta sent a force to snatch control of the South Atlantic archipelago. Britain then won a 10-week war in which about 1,000 troops, mainly Argentines, were killed.</p>
<p>Relations between the two countries slowly warmed after the return of Argentine democracy in 1983, and diplomatic ties were re-established after President Carlos Menem took office in 1989.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
