<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804225" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. calls Israeli delay on funds &quot;unhelpful&quot;.</title>
<headline>U.S. calls Israeli delay on funds &quot;unhelpful&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's delay in releasing funds to the Palestinian Authority after last month's suicide bomb attack was &quot;unhelpful&quot; to the peace process, the United States said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Israel withheld the tax money and customs duties after two Palestinians killed 16 people at a Jerusalem market on July 30. Palestinian leaders condemned the sanctions as collective punishment.</p>
<p>&quot;We've indicated some of Israel's actions, for example, withholding the money, is unhelpful,&quot; White House National Security Adviser Sandy Berger said in a television interview.</p>
<p>The Palestinian Cabinet issued a statement on Saturday calling on Israel to live up to its pledges and reverse the crackdown imposed after the bombing.</p>
<p>&quot;While the Israeli government says it is easing the siege measures, on the ground it is pressuring residents and cutting off their earnings,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>In addition to freezing financial transfers to the Palestinian Authority, Israel sealed the West Bank and Gaza after the attack.</p>
<p>Berger said there was certainly no equation between setting off a bomb in a marketplace and Israel's actions.</p>
<p>&quot;One is terror, the other is a policy which we think is unhelpful to the peace process,&quot; he said on the CNN program &quot;Evans &amp; Novak.&quot;</p>
<p>Berger urged Arafat and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to &quot;take some steps towards each other and restore a level of confidence&quot; which he said had been substantially and seriously eroded.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright plans a trip to the Middle East to focus on speeding Israeli-Palestinian peace talks, but Berger said no specific date had been set.</p>
<p>Albright said in a speech Aug. 6 she was prepared to go to the region provided progress was made in improving the security situation which had deteriorated over the past six months and culminated in the deadly July 30 bombing.</p>
<p>&quot;She'll be going soon ... There's only two more weeks left in August. But I would say she would be going soon,&quot; Berger told CNN.</p>
<p>&quot;We also have to have from the Palestinians a level of security cooperation with the Israelis that we have not seen yet, and that is really indispensable to getting this process going again,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
