<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804257" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Princess Diana shuns media on Greek island cruise.</title>
<headline>Princess Diana shuns media on Greek island cruise.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Princess Diana was island hopping in the Aegean Sea on Saturday on a luxury yacht owned by a family of Greek shipping magnates as Britain's tabloids continued their obsession with her latest romance.</p>
<p>The princess was whisked through passport control at Athens airport on Friday night and is believed to be on one of two yachts owned by the London-based Lemos shipping family somewhere in the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>Airport authorities said she arrived in a private Gulfstream jet wearing a long black dress and dark glasses. She is believed to be travelling with one of her closest friends, Rosa Monckton.</p>
<p>Greek media have failed so far to spot the princess, whose romance with millionaire Egyptian playboy Dodi Al Fayed has made headlines around the world.</p>
<p>The private television station SKAI reported that Diana went aboard one of the Lemos yachts, probably the Nemesis, at the Alimos marina near Athens and sailed to the Cycladic island of Andros, where the shipping family owns a villa.</p>
<p>Other Greek media said she might be on another Lemos boat, appropriately name the Lady-D, cruising the Cyclades.</p>
<p>Her latest love interest, Dodi Al Fayed, whose father owns the opulent Harrods department store in London, was left behind to defend himself against claims by an American model that the two were engaged to be married.</p>
<p>Al Fayed has denied the claims by model Kelly Fisher that she was jilted by him and the princess has made no comment on the dispute.</p>
<p>Diana's silence and the fact she used the Harrods jet to fly to Athens was seen by the press as an endorsement of her continuing relationship with the playboy whose name has been linked with a string of beautiful women.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
