<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804208" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Verdict in UK nurses' murder trial seen in days.</title>
<headline>Verdict in UK nurses' murder trial seen in days.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A verdict in the trial of two British nurses charged with murdering an Australian colleague in Saudi Arabia is expected within the next few days, sources close to the case said on Saturday.</p>
<p>A ruling in the murder trial of Deborah Parry, 38, and Lucille McLauchlan, 31, had been initially expected as soon as Sunday. But the sources said a decision could be made later in the week.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no set date and no guarantee, but a verdict is expected within the next few days,&quot; a source told Reuters. &quot;It's expected sooner rather than later.&quot;</p>
<p>It was not clear whether the court would convene another session to announce their verdict, or whether the judges would only inform the lawyers of both parties, the sources said.</p>
<p>Parry and McLauchlan stand accused of murdering 55-year-old nurse Yvonne Gilford. They were arrested shortly after Gilford's body was found in her room at the King Fahd military medical complex in the eastern Saudi city of Dhahran in December. She had been stabbed 13 times, bludgeoned and suffocated.</p>
<p>They say they are innocent and have withdrawn confessions they said were made under duress.</p>
<p>The Saudi lawyer for the two nurses said on Thursday he expected news from the court within a week but doubted it would be a verdict.</p>
<p>&quot;In theory it could be a verdict. What is more likely is that the court will make a ruling on the confessions or simply pass the case on to a higher court,&quot; Salah al-Hejailan he said.</p>
<p>The trial, which began in May, adjourned on August 10, and lawyers representing the victim's family said the judges were deliberating on the verdict.</p>
<p>If the court finds them guilty of any charge, the case would go through an elaborate appeals system in the kingdom, which applies strict Islamic laws including beheading by the sword for murderers, drug smugglers and rapists.</p>
<p>According to Saudi law, the victim's family has the right to demand an execution if the court finds the two women guilty and says the death penalty is appropriate. The victim's brother Frank Gilford has repeatedly called for the maximum sentence.</p>
<p>The family could also accept &quot;diah&quot;, or blood money, instead of capital punishment. The amount of blood money the family could demand is fixed under Saudi law, and currently stands at 30,000 riyals ($8,000) for a non-Moslem woman, lawyers in Riyadh said. Diah is higher for men and Moslem women.</p>
<p>Legal sources in Saudi Arabia said they believed no Western women had ever been executed in the kingdom. Some 80 people, including a Nigerian woman, have been beheaded in Saudi Arabia so far this year for crimes including murder.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
