<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804289" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Key ally backs India PM in war on corruption.</title>
<headline>Key ally backs India PM in war on corruption.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's influential Congress party on Saturday joined a renewed campaign launched by Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral to fight corruption, saying it would offer its backing to two laws that could help in the process.</p>
<p>The Congress party, which has ruled India for all but four years since independence in 1947, is a make-or-break ally for Gujral's three-month-old United Front coalition. The alliance is in a minority in parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;We and our party are in the forefront of the fight against corruption,...&quot; Congress president Sitaram Kesri said a day after Gujral issued a call against corruption during an address marking 50 years of India's independence from Britain.</p>
<p>Gujral's call reflected widespread public opinion that politicians as a class had let down the country by encouraging corruption.</p>
<p>Kesri said he was ready to back Gujral's measures to legislate the appointment of a Lok Pal (ombudsman) to probe public figures and a law to provide freedom of information.</p>
<p>&quot;I am ready to support it tomorrow. Our party will support this immediately,&quot; Kesri said in response to a question at a news conference in the Indian capital. &quot;Let them bring it on Monday.&quot;</p>
<p>The United Front changed its leader to please Kesri after his party withdrew its support for incumbent H.D. Deve Gowda, whose government lost a confidence vote in April.</p>
<p>Kesri said he signalled his party's intention to fight corruption by nominating two leaders with a clean image to the party's decision-making Congress Working Committee.</p>
<p>He said he appointed former finance minister Manmohan Singh and southern leader A.K. Antony to the 20-member panel, to which 10 members were directly elected by delegates at a party plenary earlier this month.</p>
<p>The Congress president fills up 10 posts. Kesri said he would name eight members later.</p>
<p>&quot;I have appointed two clean candidates to the CWC. The nomination of the two gives a message,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Congress party has itself fallen prey to corruption scandals. Last year, it suffered its worst defeat in history widely linked to corruption scandals.</p>
<p>Seven Congress ministers had resigned in January 1996 after federal police slapped bribery charges on them in a $18-million illegal foreign exchange scandal.</p>
<p>Kesri replaced the then party president P.V. Narasimha Rao in September after a court framed charges against him in a criminal cheating case.</p>
<p>Rao says he is innocent, but resigned as party chief in the face of intense pressures to quit.</p>
<p>Earlier on Saturday, Gujral kept up momentum from his speech on Friday, when he had asked countrymen to launch a &quot;satyagraha,&quot; or civil disobedience campaign, against corruption.</p>
<p>He asked industrialists at a conference to expose corrupt businessmen in their midst, and announced the setting up of a special cell in his office to deal directly with complaints against corruption.</p>
<p>On Friday, he told the nation in a televised address from the 17th century Red Fort that bribe-giving was as much to blame as bribe-taking.</p>
<p>Gujral echoed President K.R. Narayanan, who made a speech at a midnight session of parliament on Friday to mark the anniversary, in calling for a mass movement to end bribery.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
