<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804227" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Former Secretary of State George Shultz weds.</title>
<headline>Former Secretary of State George Shultz weds.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Secretary of State George Shultz and a San Francisco socialite have tied the knot in what was being called the city's wedding of the year.</p>
<p>Shultz and Charlotte Mailliard Swig were married at San Francisco's Grace Cathedral on Friday evening, attended by a select group of guests including former first lady Nancy Reagan, Gov. Pete Wilson, Sen. Dianne Feinstein and San Francisco Mayor Willie Brown.</p>
<p>Swig wore a yellow gown and a star-shaped Chanel diamond ring that Shultz gave her. The red-carpet ceremony was followed by a glittering reception for 650 guests.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to have a honeymoon and it's going to go on for years and years and years,&quot; Shultz told reporters.</p>
<p>Shultz, 76, was secretary of state in the Reagan administration from 1982 to 1989 and is now a scholar at the Hoover Institution at Stanford University. His first wife died in 1995.</p>
<p>The twice-widowed Swig, 64, is San Francisco's protocol chief, involved in organizing city events. A wealthy woman with four homes, she is a star of San Francisco's social scene.</p>
<p>Feinstein was matchmaker for the couple, who got to know each other when the Democratic senator placed them together at a dinner party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
