<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804233" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Goal is &quot;promptly&quot; ending Whitewater probe - Starr.</title>
<headline>Goal is &quot;promptly&quot; ending Whitewater probe - Starr.</headline>
<dateline>LITTLE ROCK, Ark. 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Whitewater special prosecutor said on Friday his investigation of the personal and political finances of President Clinton and Hillary Clinton would be concluded &quot;as promptly as we can.&quot;</p>
<p>But the prosecutor, Kenneth Starr, declined to be more specific.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not going to give you a date. I've learned the hard way it is unwise to give a date certain. It cannot be done,&quot; Starr said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are mindful of the interests of the country in moving forward and bringing this to a conclusion one way or another as promptly as we can,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are proceeding as diligently as we can. We are already evaluating the information that we have as well as gathering additional information,&quot; he said. He declined to say if the information involved Clinton or his wife.</p>
<p>Starr spoke with reporters after a hearing in federal court here in a criminal case brought by the Whitewater prosecutor. Jim Guy Tucker, Clinton's successor as governor of Arkansas, and two other men are charged with bankruptcy fraud and tax evasion.</p>
<p>A judge granted the defense a seven-month delay in the trial, citing Tucker's poor health, but accepted Starr's argument that Tucker's co-defendants should not receive separate trials.</p>
<p>Tucker was convicted last year in a separate Whitewater case. Found guilty in the same trial were Clinton's partners in the Whitewater real estate project in Arkansas, James McDougal and his former wife, Susan McDougal.</p>
<p>Although the pending case does not involve Clinton directly, Starr called it &quot;an integral part of what is frequently called the Whitewater investigation.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LITTLE ROCK, Ark."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
