<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804245" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Neo-Nazis remember Hess in Denmark, 44 arrested.</title>
<headline>Neo-Nazis remember Hess in Denmark, 44 arrested.</headline>
<byline>Steve Weizman</byline>
<dateline>KOEGE, Denmark 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Around 150 neo-Nazis from Scandinavia, Germany and The Netherlands succeeded in holding a rally in Denmark on Saturday to mark the 10th anniversary of the death of Hitler's deputy Rudolf Hess.</p>
<p>Shouting &quot;Sieg Heil&quot; and waving swastika flags, they switched their rally at the last moment to this sleepy town west of Copenhagen to avoided a battle with anti-Nazi protesters who fought with police at the original site in nearby Roskilde.</p>
<p>Many of the neo-Nazis wore ski masks and carried wooden shields with portraits of Rudolf Hess. They chanted; &quot;Rudolf Hess -- Fighter For Peace.&quot;</p>
<p>Liberal freedom of speech laws have made Denmark something of a neo-Nazi haven, to the irritation of neighbouring Germany, where Nazi tracts and symbols are banned, and to the discomfort of Danes who remember wartime Nazi occupation.</p>
<p>Hess hanged himself with an electric cord in Berlin's Spandau prison on August 17, 1987, and the date has become a rallying point for the radical right in Germany and other European countries in recent years.</p>
<p>Some 44 protesters from both sides were arrested during the course of the day, mainly for carrying knives or clubs, police said. One anti-Nazi activist was arrested for violence against a police officer.</p>
<p>Two television cameramen, one working for Danish state television and one working for Reuters Television, had their cameras damaged by neo-Nazis.</p>
<p>The Danish television cameraman was hit over the head with his camera but was not seriously injured.</p>
<p>Danish neo-Nazi leader Jonny Hansen said the rally had been a success. &quot;We changed plans to have a peaceful demo. We have had that, so it was a success.&quot;</p>
<p>The neo-Nazis from Denmark, Sweden, Norway, Germany, Finland and The Netherlands marched four km (2.5 miles) to the medieval cobbled square of Koege, led by a lone drummer.</p>
<p>The Danes carried Danish flags and swastikas. They were followed by contingents of Swedish fascists brandishing their version of the national flag, a yellow swastika on a blue background.</p>
<p>Most of the marchers had shaven heads and their leaders wore paramilitary uniforms. The Danes wore white shirts, red ties and red swastika armbands. The Swedes chose the original Nazi uniform of brown shirts and black caps.</p>
<p>As Hansen addressed the rally, supporters replied with Sieg Heil chants.</p>
<p>An English-born member of the far-right Dutch Centre Party 86, Stewart Mordant, addressed the crowd with an attack on black people.</p>
<p>&quot;The niggers will try to destroy you. Your best salvation is to join our struggle. Beware, we never forget, they'll never beat the white warriors.&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Townsfolk gathered to watch and shout &quot;Nazi swine.&quot; The meeting only lasted about 15 minutes.</p>
<p>A short distance away in Roskilde, police and a group of about 1,000 anti-Nazi demonstrators clashed when the neo-Nazi marchers failed to arrive there as scheduled.</p>
<p>Protesters threw stones at police, who replied with tear gas.</p>
<p>There was a second clash later in the day when far-left activists gathered near the neo-Nazi headquarters at Greve, just south of Copenhagen, to confront the returning marchers.</p>
<p>The protesters threw stones and bottles at police cordoning off the area and the police again responded with tear gas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KOEGE, Denmark"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
