<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804309" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: S.Lanka opposition protests aginst government misrule.</title>
<headline>S.Lanka opposition protests aginst government misrule.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka's main opposition United National Party (UNP) organised rallies and pickets across the island on Saturday to protest against what they called goverment misrule as the People's Alliance completed three years in power.</p>
<p>Thousands of people gathered in central Colombo holding placards protesting against a recent rise in wheat flour prices as UNP leaders lambasted President Chandrika Kumaratunga for doing little for the common people.</p>
<p>&quot;We are protesting against three years of misrule of the government. They have completed half their term and not been able to solve any of the pressing problems facing the people,&quot; former prime minister and UNP leader Ranil Wickeremsinghe told Reuters Television.</p>
<p>Several thousands more were reported to have picketed elsewhere in this Indian Ocean island.</p>
<p>UNP officials said the party had organised pickets and rallies at about 150 places to inform people about the government's failures.</p>
<p>Wickeremesinghe accused the government of raising the cost of living and doing little to improve the the military situation in the war-ravaged north and east.</p>
<p>Prices of wheat flour and bread, staple food for millions of Sri Lankans, rose this week after the government further slashed subsidies in a bid to control its budgetary deficit.</p>
<p>The 14-year-old war against Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam, who demand a separate homeland for minority Tamils in Sri Lanka's north and east, has escalated in the last three years as troops try to marginalise the separatists.</p>
<p>The state-owned Daily News however lauded the government for its efforts to rekindle the economy and restore peace to the country.</p>
<p>&quot;...The people's continuing support for a benevolent government has brought with it a political stability which has in turn led to an upturn in the economy,&quot; the newspaper said in an ceditorial.</p>
<p>&quot;The war too is manifestly coming to an end. The national security forces are now firmly in control and the separatist terrorists are on the defensive. There is the political will to end the war and bring peace to the people,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
