<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804306" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian PM wants corrupt businessmen exposed.</title>
<headline>Indian PM wants corrupt businessmen exposed.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral on Saturday appealed to industrialists to expose corrupt businessmen as part of a new campaign to wipe out graft.</p>
<p>Saying he was ashamed over the level of corruption in government and business, Gujral told a conference of industry executives that he planned to create a special department in his office to gather information about dishonest individuals.</p>
<p>&quot;I have talked to you privately and I now want to say publicly, 'Please help me,'&quot; Gujral told the Confederation of Indian Industry at a conference honouring India's 50 years of independence from Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm setting up straight away a cell in the PMO (prime minister's office) which will definitely take care of all the complaints about corruption that are directly directed to me. That is where I want to help.&quot;</p>
<p>It was the second speech in two days, both nationally televised, in which the prime minister underscored his determination to stamp out corruption and indicated it had become a major government priority.</p>
<p>On Friday, in a speech commemorating India's 50 years of freedom, Gujral echoed President K.R. Narayanan in calling for a mass movement of civil disobedience to end bribery.</p>
<p>&quot;This now comes to occupy an important issue in my agenda, and I want to repeat it within 24 hours of yesterday's speech to bring your attention to this,&quot; the prime minister said.</p>
<p>Gujral told the business leaders on Saturday that he was distressed over the levels of graft in India, which surveys have shown as one of the most corrupt countries.</p>
<p>&quot;I sometimes feel ashamed, and I hang my head in shame when I am told that India is one of the 10 most corrupt countries in the world. I think you share my shame also,&quot; he said, adding that corruption was at odds with the legacy of Mahatma Gandhi.</p>
<p>Gujral revealed that he had already privately asked business leaders to turn in information to help curtail corruption.</p>
<p>&quot;I had invited some of you in private and asked you to give me private information. You do know who takes the money. You do give money. But please tell us, if you want India to grow.&quot;</p>
<p>The prime minister said corruption was a two-way street requiring someone who pays and someone who receives a bribe.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not only the taker but the giver, and the giver, I want to emphasise, has to be aimed at,&quot; he said, referring to those who pay bribes.</p>
<p>&quot;Those people who are harassed...must stand up and resist. If you cannot do it individually, please do it collectively.&quot;</p>
<p>Gujral said his campaign against corruption was linked to economic reforms, which he said depended on the elimination of graft to go forward.</p>
<p>&quot;Particularly we are keen that more and more effort is made to withdraw government from many sectors... But that is possible only if...corruption is eliminated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Liberalisation and corruption cannot sleep in the same bed.&quot;</p>
<p>Finance Minister P. Chidambaram told the same conference that the government could help combat corruption by removing controls over industry that can give civil servants an opportunity to take bribes from business.</p>
<p>&quot;Who corrupts? It is a by-product of controls,&quot; Chidambaram said. &quot;If we remove controls, the corrupt are easily identified, isolated and punched.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
