<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804303" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Taleban increase restrictions on Afghan sports.</title>
<headline>Taleban increase restrictions on Afghan sports.</headline>
<byline>Tim Johnston</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Taleban administration in Kabul on Friday reiterated a series of decrees aimed at bringing sport in Afghanistan in line with its strict interpretation of Islamic law.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the victory of the Taleban, we have tried to make sport in Afghanistan totally Moslem.&quot; Ehsan Motmayn, the secretary general of the Afghan National Olympic Committee, said on Saturday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;According to Islamic law men should be covered to below the knee and above the navel.&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;For a Moslem, it is an obligation to offer prayers five times a day. If a competition coincides with prayer time, the competition should be stopped, whatever is going on, so that sportsmen and the audience can offer prayers.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Applauding to encourage athletes is forbidden, they should show their support by shouting 'Allah-u-Akbar' (God is greatest),&quot; Motmayn said.</p>
<p>He said that the Taleban's ruling council had not decided on the acceptability of women's participation in sporting events.</p>
<p>&quot;After peace and security has been established in Afghanistan, women's sports will be discussed by the religious scholars of the council. But for the moment women are forbidden to participate in sporting events.&quot; Motmayn said.</p>
<p>He said that the council also still had to rule on sports such as swimming and body building, which would in normal circumstances contravene the dress code.</p>
<p>Sport in Afghanistan is in a sorry state. During the 1980s, after the Soviet Union invaded the country, international competition was limited to the countries of the communist bloc.</p>
<p>Since the defeat of the communists in 1992, there has been little exposure for Afghan athletes. The one Afghan competitor at the last Olympic games in Atlanta -- a boxer -- was disqualified for missing the weigh-in and then defected to Canada.</p>
<p>Most of the sporting facilities have suffered during the war. The national stadium, where Motmayn has his office, is a scarred concrete shell, although it has been cleared of the land mines that once made it a death trap.</p>
<p>Motmayn says that the Taleban want to encourage sport as part of their drive to create a pure Islamic state, albeit one on a war footing.</p>
<p>&quot;Islam says that we should always be prepared for battle with our enemies. By offering prayers we strengthen our souls, and with sport we strengthen our bodies.&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
