<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804318" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GM, UAW keep talking past strike deadline.</title>
<headline>GM, UAW keep talking past strike deadline.</headline>
<byline>Todd Nissen</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT, Mich. 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Auto Workers union said Friday night it extended a strike deadline at two General Motors Corp. transmission plants after progress was made during negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;We've made some significant progress,&quot; said UAW spokesman Reg McGhee, without elaborating. &quot;Things are looking positive.&quot;</p>
<p>Talks have gone on all week between UAW Local 735 and GM for a new local contract covering 5,320 hourly workers at GM's Powertrain Willow Run Transmission plant in Ypsilanti, Mich., and a smaller facility in Romulus, Mich.</p>
<p>Union officials said earlier this week they expected to strike the plants because progress had been so slow.</p>
<p>The plants make transmissions and related components for many of GM's front-wheel drive and rear-wheel drive cars and trucks. Because they supply both assembly and other parts operations in the U.S. and Canada, a strike could quickly ripple through the rest of GM's North American manufacturing facilities.</p>
<p>Local 735 leaders want GM to add more workers to replace those who have retired and cut down on overtime. They also want the automaker to settle health and safety issues and limit the amount of work it sends to outside contractors.</p>
<p>GM has been on a mission to make its manufacturing operations more efficient and has adopted a hard line against adding staff, preferring to let its hourly workforce shrink through attrition.</p>
<p>Union leaders, who say their members are overworked, have resisted those efforts. The clash has led to six strikes since the beginning of this year.</p>
<p>Strike deadlines have been set by the UAW on an almost weekly basis during the last month as it struggles to get contracts for the remaining seven of its 105 GM locals. A new national pact was signed last November.</p>
<p>GM and the union reached a new contract a week ago at the automaker's Cadillac assembly plant in the Detroit community of Hamtramck.</p>
<p>In July, GM and the UAW agreed on a new contract for its workers at a Warren, Mich., transmission plant after a three-day strike. That walkout idled 17,000 workers and six car assembly plants before the new pact was reached.</p>
<p>Among the locals that do not yet have new agreements is one in Dayton, Ohio, which represents workers at two brake plants. Those workers struck the company in March 1996 in a 17-day walkout that forced GM to suspend operations at 26 of its 29 North American assembly plants.</p>
<p>Two strikes earlier this year cut GM's second quarter profits by $490 million. In 1996, GM lost $1.2 billion in earnings because of work stoppages in the U.S. and Canada.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
