<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803989" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-WOODS TAKES WILD RIDE THROUGH WINGED FOOT.</title>
<headline>GOLF-WOODS TAKES WILD RIDE THROUGH WINGED FOOT.</headline>
<byline>Larry Fine</byline>
<dateline>MAMARONECK, New York 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tiger Woods took a wild ride through Winged Foot on Saturday, soaring and swooning through the fabled layout before limping off with an exhausting one-over 71.</p>
<p>The 21-year-old Masters champion had four birdies, one after a miraculous recovery, three bogeys, an eagle and two double bogeys as he waged an unsuccessful war with the severe rough lining Winged Foot's tight fairways.</p>
<p>Woods was favoring his right leg as he limped up the fairway at the 18th after trying in vain to muscle his second shot out of the junk at the finishing hole. He finished with a bogey there to drop to one over par for the tournament.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing I hurt was my ego,&quot; Woods said after his tumultuous round, which ended double bogey/bogey.</p>
<p>Woods's adventures left him seven shots off the lead shared by British Open champion Justin Leonard and Davis Love when play was halted late in the third round because of an approaching thunderstorm.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel like I'm still in the tournament,&quot; said Woods, who admitted to making some &quot;mental errors.&quot;</p>
<p>Woods had lifted himself into contention at two under par, three shots back at the time, with a spectacular birdie at the par-4 16th hole after putting his tee shot amongst the trees on the right, 171 yards from the pin.</p>
<p>With his back nearly against a tree and his backswing impaired, Woods slashed a 6-iron shot through an opening, bending the ball towards the green, where it rolled to a stop 12 feet from the cup. He sank the putt and walked off the green pumping his fists.</p>
<p>But at the 17th he mis-clubbed from the fairway and put his 7-iron shot into the rough short of the green. He blasted long out of the rough, settling into the collar of the green. He flubbed his chip using a 3-wood and went 18 feet past the hole and two-putted.</p>
<p>His 3-wood off the tee at the 18th again found the rough on the right. His 7-iron from there was short, his pitch to the green was weak and rolled back into the fairway and he saved bogey with a 10-foot putt.</p>
<p>&quot;It was disappointing to finish the way I did and being right there and in contention just three back going into the last round and then do something that dumb. Make a double on 17, then bogey 18, that's not what you want to do,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Woods's bid to win the British Open was also ruined by some horrendous holes. The young superstar made a slew of birdies at Royal Troon but also posted a quadruple bogey and two triples.</p>
<p>When he wasn't scuffling his way out of the Winged Foot rough, Woods was often making brilliant shots, thrilling the huge gallery that follows him.</p>
<p>After balancing three birdies against two bogeys and a double bogey through his first 11 holes, Woods jumped up the leaderboard with an eagle at the 540-yard par-5 12th, where he drained a 20-footer after his 7-iron approach.</p>
<p>Someone wondered whether his ability to pull off wondrous shots like the one at 16 led Woods to try to do too much from the rough on the other holes and put himself into further trouble.</p>
<p>&quot;Not at all,&quot; replied the supremely confident Woods.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAMARONECK, New York"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
