<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803999" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CRICKET-KASPROWICZ AND LEE SHOW AUSSIE BOWLING STRENGTH.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-KASPROWICZ AND LEE SHOW AUSSIE BOWLING STRENGTH.</headline>
<dateline>CANTERBURY, England 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia showed the depth of their bowling talent on Saturday as Mike Kasprowicz and new boy Shane Lee each took four wickets as the tourists bowled out English county championship leaders Kent for 201.</p>
<p>Paceman Kasprowicz, a certain test starter in the absence of three front-line bowlers, ended with figures of four for 72 while all-rounder Lee, called up as an emergency replacement this week, posted four for 27. He took the last four Kent wickets without conceding a run.</p>
<p>Australia ended the the first day of the three-day match on 207 for five after looking in trouble at 40 for four.</p>
<p>Kasprowicz accounted for the first three Kent batsmen in his opening three overs, with Trevor Ward, Alan Wells and Ed Smith all falling for ducks as the big Queenslander did not concede a run off the bat for 32 deliveries.</p>
<p>Ward and Wells nicked catches behind to Darren Berry, while Smith was superbly caught, one-handed, by Lee at second slip.</p>
<p>Will House became Kasprowicz's fourth victim as Kent reached lunch at 122 for six.</p>
<p>Lee, who was called up from the Lancashire League this week after Brendon Julian broke his wrist to follow Jason Gillespie and Paul Reiffel on the plane home, then mopped up the innings to give himself the chance of a dream test debut at the Oval on Thursday.</p>
<p>Only Matthew Fleming with 67, stood up to the assault.</p>
<p>Former England fasler Alan Igglesden gave Kent a good start in the field, claiming three of the first four Australian wickets, including Mark Waugh for a single.</p>
<p>But from 106 for five Australia took command with Steve Waugh and Michael Bevan unbeaten on 94 and 37 respectively.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANTERBURY, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
