<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803992" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONACO: ATHLETICS-TIRED GREENE SUFFERS SECOND DEFEAT.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-TIRED GREENE SUFFERS SECOND DEFEAT.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>MONACO 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>American world champion Maurice Greene suffered his second defeat over 100 metres since his Athens triumph on Saturday and complained of feeling drained of energy.</p>
<p>Greene, who finished behind Namibia's Frankie Fredericks in Zurich on Wednesday in his first major race since his 100 win at this month's world championships, could not match the strong finish of compatriot Tim Montgomery and had to settle for third at the Monaco grand prix.</p>
<p>With a 0.4 metre-per-second wind behind his back, world bronze medallist Montgomery clocked 9.99 seconds ahead of second-placed American Dennis Mitchell who ran 10.05.</p>
<p>Greene finished one hundreth of a second further behind in third on a warm evening on the Cote d'Azur which was perfect for sprinting.</p>
<p>The pressure was off the American after Fredericks decided to run the 200 here and Olympic champion Donovan Bailey was not competing.</p>
<p>But the 23-year-old American will need to win races like this before he can claim to be the leading 100 metres sprinter in the world. He left the track shaking his head.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I'm very tired,&quot; Greene said. &quot;I have been training very hard for the last two years.&quot;</p>
<p>Montgomery added: &quot;I ran a much better race than in Athens and I felt much more relaxed. No pressure, so a better race. It's simple.&quot;</p>
<p>Fredericks, who missed out on the medals in the Athens 100 and was second behind Trinidad's Ato Boldon in the 200, took revenge when he beat Boldon over 200 with a time of 19.93, faster than the winning time of 20.04 in Athens.</p>
<p>Boldon could not live with Fredericks's stamina and speed in the final 20 metres and slowed up at the finish to take second in 20.11. The Namibian pointed his finger at the crowd at the end as if to say 'I told you so'.</p>
<p>&quot;In Athens I was injured so I couldn't do what I wanted,&quot; Fredericks said.</p>
<p>American Marion Jones, the women's world sprint champion who also lost her first 100 race since Athens to veteran Merlene Ottey in Zurich, bounced back with a victory over the Jamaican in the 200 metres in 21.92.</p>
<p>Ottey closed on the American in the last 50 metres but could only take second in 22.06.</p>
<p>One of the most impressive performances of the night came from Kenya's world 5,000 metres champion Daniel Komen who stepped down to 1,500 and beat several Olympic champions including Spain's Fermin Cacho and Algeria's Noureddine Morceli in a victory in three minutes 29.46 seconds.</p>
<p>The 21-year-old Komen, who decided to pull out of a bid to break the 3,000 metres world record here because he was disappointed by his 5,000 defeat in Zurich, proved emphatically that he has the speed for the shorter race.</p>
<p>At the end Komen outsprinted Burundi's Venuste Niyongabo, the Olympic 5,000 champion who took second in 3:30.47.</p>
<p>Cacho, the 1992 Olympic champion who won silver at last year's Atlanta Olympics and broke Briton Steve Cram's 12-year-old European record in Zurich with a time of 3:28.95, could only finish fourth in 3:31.64 with Morceli back in 12th in 3:33.98.</p>
<p>Denmark's former Kenyan Wilson Kipketer, who smashed Seb Coe's 16-year-old 800 metres world record in Zurich when he clocked a historic one minute 41.24 seconds, was clearly not in record-breaking mood although he won in a quick 1:42.77.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONACO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONACO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
