<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803994" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-LOVE LEADS IN THIRD ROUND OF PGA CHAMPIONSHIP.</title>
<headline>GOLF-LOVE LEADS IN THIRD ROUND OF PGA CHAMPIONSHIP.</headline>
<byline>Walter Bagley</byline>
<dateline>MAMARONECK, New York 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Davis Love used back-to-back birdies to overtake Lee Janzen and lead the third round of the PGA Championship by two strokes on Saturday with nine holes to play on an extremely hot, humid day.</p>
<p>Love, one of the best players never to have won a major championship, birdied the fifth hole, where he just missed an eagle putt, to catch halfway leader Janzen, and then jumped two ahead when he birdied the next hole while Janzen made bogey.</p>
<p>The 33-year-old Love made the turn at five under par, two shots ahead of not only Janzen but also Phil Mickelson and British Open champion Justin Leonard, who were both a couple of holes ahead.</p>
<p>Tiger Woods, U.S. Ryder Cup captain Tom Kite, Jeff Maggert and Shigeki Maruyama of Japan were all at one under par as no one was able to sustain a charge at famous Winged Foot Golf Club in conditions that resembled a steambath.</p>
<p>Mickelson, who gave up three strokes in two holes on the front nine with a double bogey at the par-5 fifth hole and a bogey at the next, birdied the first two holes on the back nine to move within two shots of Love.</p>
<p>Leonard, whose brilliant short game helped him survive the first two rounds, birdied the third hole and then made nine consecutive pars to keep pace.</p>
<p>The discomfort caused by the weather was difficult enough but the heat also made famed Winged Foot's 6,987-yard, par-70 West Course play much harder, especially for the late players. It dried out the greens and fairways which had been softened by rain the day before the championship began.</p>
<p>The leaders also had to contend with breezes that blew up in the late afternoon as thunderstorms loomed in the distance.</p>
<p>Woods, who opened the tournament with a pair of even-par 70s, continued to draw big galleries among the 25,000 spectators -- who appreciated the shade of Winged Foot's tree-lined fairways.</p>
<p>The 21-year-old Masters champion, who started the day four shots behind, jumped into contention with an eagle at the 540-yard 12th hole, where he hit driver and 7-iron and sank the putt to go to two under par.</p>
<p>Woods, however, gave a shot back on the next hole, a 212-yarder, where his tee shot strayed way left and his next landed in a greenside bunker. Only a brilliant blast saved him from a double bogey, which would have been his second of the day.</p>
<p>He took the double bogey on the 460-yard fourth hole, where Winged Foot's long rough got the best of him.</p>
<p>Woods drove into the ankle-deep rough and barely touched the ball on his second shot, advancing it only about 10 yards. He missed the green with his third and settled for a six.</p>
<p>The early starters had the best playing conditions and several took advantage.</p>
<p>Colin Montgomerie of Britain, Frank Nobilo of New Zealand and American Scott McCarron all shot 67 -- one off the course record -- in the morning. It was the first time for each to break par in the championship.</p>
<p>They were all at two-over-par 212 -- one better than Tim Herron (68) and two better than Australians Steve Elkington (70) and Stuart Appleby (69) and Tom Byrum (70) among the early sweat-soaked finishers. Elkington won this championship in 1995 in a playoff with Montgomerie.</p>
<p>Montgomerie, another of the world's best players not to have won a major, struggled with his swing all tournament and he was not too optimistic about his chances here.</p>
<p>&quot;Tomorrow everything must be brilliant if I'm to win,&quot; he said. &quot;But it looks like another empty year for me as far as majors are concerned.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the players who struggled in the morning was U.S. Open champion Ernie Els of South Africa, who carded a 74 that left him 10 strokes over par at 220.</p>
<p>Els -- who also won the 1994 U.S. Open in very similar heat at Oakmont -- had been expected to contend here. He likes tough courses like Winged Foot and won last year's Westchester Classic only a few miles away. But he failed to break par in three trips around Winged Foot.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAMARONECK, New York"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
