<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804006" id="root" date="1997-08-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MOTORCYCLING-DOOHAN TAKES POLE FOR BRITISH GP.</title>
<headline>MOTORCYCLING-DOOHAN TAKES POLE FOR BRITISH GP.</headline>
<byline>Ashley Seager</byline>
<dateline>DONINGTON PARK, England 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Michael Doohan was poised for his fourth consecutive world championship on Saturday after taking pole position for Sunday's 500cc British motorcycling Grand Prix.</p>
<p>Doohan only has to finish in the top seven on Sunday to give him his fourth world title in a row, a feat matched only twice before -- by Mike Hailwood and Giacomo Agostini.</p>
<p>Doohan flew round the circuit on his Honda in a best time of one minute 32.872 seconds, just ahead of Spain's Carlos Checa on a Honda and Alex Barros of Brazil, also on a Honda.</p>
<p>Doohan, who complained of a lack of grip on the circuit on Friday, improved his time from the first practice session by 0.7 seconds.</p>
<p>&quot;The speeds were up today because we had more understanding of the track. All in all it was quite good,&quot; Doohan said.</p>
<p>He said he would not be content to merely try to finish in the top seven on Sunday to secure the title.</p>
<p>&quot;That would be dangerous. We will try to get the best result possible. It will be like any other race.&quot;</p>
<p>Doohan's only two challengers for the championship, Tadayuki Okada and Nobuatsu Aoki of Japan, qualified in fourth and six places respectively. Okada tumbled in practice but an official said he would be fit for Sunday's race.</p>
<p>A win for the 32-year-old Doohan would be his hat-trick at the Donington track and his 10th win of the season out of 11 grands prix. Doohan has four races left after Donington to overtake Agostini's 11 wins in one season, a record that has stood for a quarter of a century.</p>
<p>He currently has 245 points, Okada has 129 and Aoki 126. Alex Criville, the only man to have beaten Doohan this season, remains out injured since falling at the Dutch Grand Prix in June.</p>
<p>Doohan said he was considering offers from both his current Honda team and another team for next season.</p>
<p>&quot;In black and white, the other offer looks better. I hope to clear the matter up in the next couple of weeks,&quot; he said, without giving further detail.</p>
<p>In the 250cc category, Italian Loris Capirossi took pole while championship leader Tetsuya Harada of Japan was second. In the 125cc class, Youichi Ui put in the best time while runaway championship leader Valentino Rossi could manage only fourth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DONINGTON PARK, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
