<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412625" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-UNITED CLOSE IN ON TITLE WHILE NEWCASTLE'S HOPES FADE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-UNITED CLOSE IN ON TITLE WHILE NEWCASTLE'S HOPES FADE.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>While Manchester United moved nearer to winning the English league title for the fourth time in five years, Newcastle's bid for their first championship since 1927 nosedived on Saturday.</p>
<p>United stretched their unbeaten league run to 16 matches with a 3-1 home victory over Coventry.</p>
<p>Newcastle, meanwhile, crashed 1-0 at home to Southampton, a surprise setback after three straight league wins, and are now nine points behind United, although they have a match in hand.</p>
<p>Arsenal, meanwhile, rekindled their faint title chances with a convincing 2-0 win at Everton with goals from Dennis Bergkamp and Ian Wright to move into third place, six points behind United, but having played one more game.</p>
<p>Second-placed Liverpool, who have lost only once in their last 11 league matches, need to win at in-form sixth-placed Aston Villa on Sunday to keep the pressure on United. Liverpool are currently four points adrift, but would cut that gap to one point if they were to repeat last season's 2-0 win at Villa Park.</p>
<p>Wimbledon, the only other team in with a title chance -- albeit a slim one -- probably saw that chance disappear when they crashed 3-1 at home to Leicester. It was only their fourth league defeat in their last 22 matches.</p>
<p>While the hunt for the title is intensifying so is the battle to avoid the drop with Middlesbrough moving another step nearer the trapdoor after their 3-1 defeat at Sheffield Wednesday.</p>
<p>They were not helped by Southampton's win at Newcastle or Nottingham Forest's 1-0 victory over Tottenham at White Hart Lane, courtesy of an 18th minute Dean Saunders goal from Forest's only attack of note in the entire match.</p>
<p>With West Ham losing 1-0 at Leeds -- where the Hammers had Michael Hughes sent off in the second half -- and Coventry also losing, Blackburn did themselves a huge favour beating Sunderland 1-0, a result which drops Sunderland into the relegation zone.</p>
<p>Derby were another side who did themselves a good turn, twice coming from behind to beat Chelsea 3-2 with the winner arriving deep into injury time from Ashley Ward.</p>
<p>It was an afternoon Chelsea would rather forget. Frank LeBouef, scored to put Chelsea 2-1 up after 54 minutes, but the Frenchman was sent off for deliberate handball seven minutes later and from that incident, Derby equalised for a second time with Aljosa Asanovic's spot-kick.</p>
<p>There was a touching moment before United kicked off against Coventry at Old Trafford when the players greeted David Busst, the Coventry defender whose career was ended last April when the bones of his left leg were shattered after only two minutes of the corresponding fixture between the teams.</p>
<p>Busst has had 14 operations since then and will never play again, but attended as United's guest of honour and was given a standing ovation by the huge crowd.</p>
<p>But within five minutes of the start, the only people with anything to cheer were United's players and fans as Alex Ferguson's men raced into a 2-0 lead with an own goal off Gary Breen and a deflected shot from Andy Cole which went in off the leg of Eoin Jess.</p>
<p>United were not seriously troubled after that, and won easily with Karel Poborsky making it 3-0 early in the second half. Darren Huckerby scored a late consolation for Coventry.</p>
<p>Matt Le Tissier scored after 56 minutes at Newcastle to give Southampton a 1-0 win over Kenny Dalglish's team just a month after Southampton scored twice against them in the last two minutes of their match at The Dell to force a 2-2 draw.</p>
<p>Newcastle were without Alan Shearer, recovering from a groin operation earlier in the week and expected to be out for at least six weeks.</p>
<p>Southampton manager Graeme Souness, delighted with his side's success, said: &quot;Its a long way from Southampton to Newcastle -- a long way to come without getting anything.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been playing some good football this season and only some poor defending has kept us near the bottom. Hopefully a win like this one today will help to lift us away from danger. There are 12 games left and I believe we are good enough to stay in the premier league.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
