<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412626" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: TENNIS-HINGIS MAKES WINNING RETURN TO KOSICE.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-HINGIS MAKES WINNING RETURN TO KOSICE.</headline>
<byline>Jan Krcmar</byline>
<dateline>KOSICE, Slovakia 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Martina Hingis made a winning return to her birthplace on Saturday but her Swiss team were being held 1-1 by Slovakia in the Fed Cup.</p>
<p>Switzerland took the lead in the world group two first-round tie when Australian Open champion Hingis beat Katarina Studenikova 6-1 6-3.</p>
<p>Karina Habsudova drew Slovakia level 1-1 by beating Patty Schnyder 7-5 6-1.</p>
<p>Hingis, who was born in Kosice 16 years ago, got a kiss of congratulation from her father, Karol, who works as a groundkeeper and junior coach in Kosice.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a nice feeling to play here after 12 years,&quot; said Hingis, who is unbeaten this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I got a great welcome when I entered the court and it was also great to win.</p>
<p>&quot;I think my father was keeping is fingers crossed for me even though I was actually playing against his country.&quot;.</p>
<p>Hingis sped through the first set in 28 minutes after breaking Studenikova in the first game and conceded only the fifth game.</p>
<p>In the second set, Hingis lost her serve, broke back, but again lost serve to trail 3-2.</p>
<p>In the sixth game, Studenikova had three  points on serve for a 4-2 lead but Hingis kept her cool to level at 3-3 and went on to win the match.</p>
<p>&quot;My serve is not my strongest point and I haven't played a match for the last two weeks,&quot; Hingis said.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew I had to tighten up my game, managed it and got into it again,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Habsudova, who recently made the world top 10 rankings, said she had had a slow start against left-hander Schnyder becasuse she had to get used to her style.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't played a left-hander in three years, so I had to adapt to her game and that was why the set was more eqal than the second,&quot; Habsudova said.</p>
<p>The Slovak number one meets Hingis in the first return singles on Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KOSICE, Slovakia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
