<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412669" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-MANCHESTER UNITED MOVE FOUR POINTS CLEAR IN ENGLAND.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MANCHESTER UNITED MOVE FOUR POINTS CLEAR IN ENGLAND.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defending champions Manchester United pulled four points clear in the English premier league on Saturday with two goals in the opening five minutes setting them up for a 3-1 win over strugglers Coventry City.</p>
<p>An own goal by Coventry's new 2.0 million pounds ($3.6 million) defender Gary Breen after four minutes, and a second from Andy Cole which took a deflection off Eoin Jess a minute later plus a second-half strike from Czech striker Karel Poborsky put United on 57 points --four ahead of Liverpool who play Aston Villa on Sunday. Darren Huckerby scored a late consolation for Coventry.</p>
<p>Arsenal ended a run of four league matches without a win with a 2-0 victory at Everton thanks to goals from Dennis Bergkamp and Ian Wright. They move into third place on 51 points -- two ahead of Newcastle who surprisingly lost 1-0 at home to Southampton. Matt le Tissier scored the Saints winner after 56 minutes.</p>
<p>Frank LeBouef, Chelsea's hero when he scored the late penalty in their 1-0 F.A. Cup win over Leicester on Wednesday, scored again in Chelsea's 3-2 defeat at Derby -- but got sent off in the second half for deliberate handball. Leicester bounced back to win 3-1 at Wimbledon.</p>
<p>Bottom-placed Middlesbrough moved a step nearer the drop when they lost 3-1 at Sheffield Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
