<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412660" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-SCOTS POWER TO RECORD WIN OVER IRISH.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-SCOTS POWER TO RECORD WIN OVER IRISH.</headline>
<byline>Mitch Phillips</byline>
<dateline>EDINBURGH 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scotland produced a second-half storm to hammer Ireland 38-10 in their Five Nations rugby match at Murrayfield on Saturday.</p>
<p>Both teams struggled to deal with a swirling wind early on and the score was locked at 7-7 at half-time, but the Scots took control after the break and ran in four more tries to post their biggest win in the fixture.</p>
<p>Ireland opened the scoring with a try in the 22nd minute following a sharp break by captain Jim Staples, who kicked ahead for winger Denis Hickey to collect and touch down.</p>
<p>David Humphreys converted but Staples took no further part in the match after pulling a hamstring as he chased his kick.</p>
<p>Scotland levelled in the 31st minute when Craig Chalmers fed former rugby league centre Alan Tait who crossed from close range and Rowen Shepherd landed the first of his five conversions.</p>
<p>The home side took control after the break and driving tries by number eight Peter Walton and lock Doddie Weir broke the Irish resistance.</p>
<p>Ireland suffered a double blow in the second period when they lost two more backs, centre Kurt McQuilkin and scrumhalf Brian O'Meara, through injury.</p>
<p>Tait, last capped in 1988, revelled in the new-found space and was instrumental in the last two tries which both came from well-created backline moves finished off by Gregor Townsend and Tony Stanger.</p>
<p>&quot;We're overjoyed,&quot; said Scotland coach Arthur Hastie. &quot;We always felt capable of this sort of performance.&quot;</p>
<p>Victorious captain Rob Wainwright said the injury to Staples was &quot;the potential turning point in the game&quot; but Ireland coach Brian Ashton saw it differently.</p>
<p>&quot;The turning point was us not scoring two tries in the first 15 minutes,&quot; said Ashton, who this week committed himself to Ireland until 2003.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no excuse for today's performance. In the second half I was bitterly disappointed -- almost to the point of embarrassment.&quot;</p>
<p>Ireland end the championship with a solitary win over Wales while Scotland face a difficult trip to Paris in two weeks' time.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Scotland -  Rowen Shepherd; Tony Stanger, Alan Tait, Gregor Townsend, Kenny Logan; Craig Chalmers, Bryan Redpath; Peter Walton, Ian Smith, Rob Wainwright (captain), Andy Reed, Doddie Weir, Mattie Stewart, Graham Ellis, Tom Smith.</p>
<p>Ireland - Jim Staples (captain) (Conor O'Shea 24th); Denis Hickie, Maurice Field, Kurt McQuilkin (Paul Burke 65th), Jonathan Bell; David Humphreys, Brian O'Meara (Stephen McIvor 68th); Ben Cronin, Denis McBride, David Corkery, Jeremy Davidson, Paddy Johns, Paul Wallace, Ross Nesdale, Paul Flavin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EDINBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
