<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412677" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: NHL-YASHIN TIES CLUB RECORD WITH TWO GOALS IN OTTAWA WIN.</title>
<headline>NHL-YASHIN TIES CLUB RECORD WITH TWO GOALS IN OTTAWA WIN.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alexei Yashin scored twice to tie a team record for goals in a single season and Ron Tugnutt made 22 saves as the Ottawa Senators beat the New York Islanders 4-1 on Friday.</p>
<p>Yashin's second goal, a wraparound midway through the second period, was his 30th of the season, tying the club mark he set in 1993-94.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not just for me it's for the team,&quot; he said. &quot;It's good to score goals but what matters is the win. If we score more goals, we probably win more often.&quot;</p>
<p>Shaun Van Allen and Tom Chorske also tallied for Ottawa, which moved within two points of the final Eastern Conference playoff spot.</p>
<p>&quot;This is obviously a big game for us. We've got to keep going,&quot; said Tugnutt. &quot;If we play well and win games like this it's not like we're going to catch (first place) Philly, but this is one of the teams we have to beat.&quot;</p>
<p>Claude Lapointe scored the only goal for the Islanders with 41 seconds left in the first period. But Yashin restored Ottawa's two-goal lead 9:32 into the second period.</p>
<p>At Washington, Paul Kariya and Teemu Selanne each had a goal and an assist to lead the Mighty Ducks of Anaheim to a 4-1 victory over the Capitals.</p>
<p>Andrew Brunette scored the lone Washington goal 1:20 into the second period. Kariya's 31st goal and 10th this month lifted the Ducks into a 1-1 tie with 81 seconds left in the period.</p>
<p>Selanne's 37th goal, a power-play tally at 7:06 of the third period, put Anaheim ahead to stay. The Finnish Flash one-timed a pass from Dmitri Mironov past Jim Carey for his 200th career goal.</p>
<p>Guy Hebert made 24 saves for Anaheim, while Carey finished with 29 stops as the Ducks outshot Washington 33-25.</p>
<p>In Hartford, Jeff Friesen scored with 2:18 remaining as the San Jose Sharks rallied in the third period for a 3-2 victory over the Whalers.</p>
<p>Friesen put home a rebound of Doug Bodger's point shot after it deflected off teammate Bob Errey. It was his 20th goal of the season and fourth in the last six games.</p>
<p>Rookie Steve Guolla beat goaltender Jason Muzzatti with a blast from the blue line on a power play at 7:05 of the third period to lift the Sharks into a 2-2 tie.</p>
<p>Geoff Sanderson scored both goals for Hartford. Shean Donovan had a short-handed tally in the second for San Jose.</p>
<p>In Calgary, Jonas Hoglund and Theo Fleury scored powerplay goals late in the first period and the Flames held on for a 3-2 victory over the Montreal Canadiens.</p>
<p>German Titov also scored for Calgary, which has won six of its last seven at home and moved into a tie with Chicago and Anaheim for seventh place in the Western Conference.</p>
<p>Fleury also assisted on Hoglund's goal and Jerome Iginla picked up two assists for the Flames.</p>
<p>Martin Rucinsky and Saku Koivu tallied for Montreal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
