<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412678" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOTSWANA: SOCCER-MALAWI RECOVER TO BEAT BOTSWANA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MALAWI RECOVER TO BEAT BOTSWANA.</headline>
<byline>Mark Gleeson</byline>
<dateline>GABORONE 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malawi recovered from an early setback to beat Botswana 4-1 on Saturday in the first round of the new Cosafa Castle Cup in Gaborone.</p>
<p>The Malawians could afford the luxury of conceding two penalties, one in the second minute and the second 10 seconds after halftime, to open the new tournament with an impressive victory.</p>
<p>Saturday's match was the first in a competition organised by the Confederation of Southern African Football Associations (Cosafa).</p>
<p>A handball from Malawian defender Shabba Phiri allowed Botswana to take a third minute lead through Aaron Lesupi but the visitors went into the interval on level terms after defender Felix Nyirongo headed home a freekick.</p>
<p>A clumsy foul just 10 seconds into the second half presented Lesupi with another opportunity from the penalty spot but he hit his kick against the upright and it bounced away to safety.</p>
<p>After that, Malawi overwhelmed their youthful opponents with John Maduka heading home from another freekick in the 51st minute and Jones Nkhwazi scoring from a simple tap-in 22 minutes later.</p>
<p>Substitute Meck Mwase added to the home side's humiliation with a header from a corner two minutes from the end.</p>
<p>Malawi are now through to the group phase of the competition, designed to give southern African countries more international competition and experience.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Swaziland host Mozambique and Zambia are in Lesotho in two other first round matches while Namibia's tie with Zimbabwe has been postponed to March 16.</p>
<p>The competition carries almost US$200 000 in prize money.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Botswana: 16-Lesego Moeng; 19-Desmond Hambari, 13-Aaron Lesupi; 3-Asisanyang Mosimanegape, 15-Matlhogonolo Boitumelo; 6-Noah Kareng, 5-Masego Ntshingane, 10-Keitumele Paul (11-Barney Marman 65th minute), 7-Innocent Ranku (2-Phineas Maimela 36th); 8-Mohe Dipatane (17-Barshin Mashakola 78th), 12-Maano Mbaakanyi.</p>
<p>Malawi: 1-Navigator Dzinkambani; 2-Charles Manda, 3-Lawrent Kamanga, 4-Felix Nyirongo, 5-Patric Mabedi (15-Meck Mwase 77th); 6-Christopher John Banda, 7-Albert Mpinganjira, 8-Shaba Phiri (16-James Chimema 46th); 9-Jones Nkhwazi, 10-John Maduka, 11-BobMpinganjira (20-Dexter Bakali 63rd).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GABORONE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOTSWANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
