<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412680" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION-AUCKLAND AND NORTHERNS DRAW IN TRY FEAST.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-AUCKLAND AND NORTHERNS DRAW IN TRY FEAST.</headline>
<byline>Andy Capostagno</byline>
<dateline>PRETORIA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northern Transvaal number eight Adriaan Richter scored a hat-trick of tries as the South African side held defending Super 12 champions Auckland to a thrilling 40-40 draw on Saturday.</p>
<p>The New Zealand team scored five tries to four but the accurate kicking of flyhalf Theo van Rensburg, who landed 20 points, was enough to ensure Northern Transvaal escaped with a draw.</p>
<p>Springbok hooker Henry Tromp plunged over from a tap penalty in the dying minutes and Van Rensburg's conversion brought the game to a thrilling end.</p>
<p>Richter scored three first half tries to keep his side level at 27-27 at the break. Northerns had dominated possession until then, but Auckland scored four audacious tries from half chances.</p>
<p>Western Samoan wing Brian Lima responded to Richter's second minute try by finishing a tap penalty move in the left corner on seven minutes.</p>
<p>Fullback Adrian Cashmore gathered his own kick ahead for Auckland's second try and after Richter had gone over again flyhalf Carlos Spencer seemed to have turned the tide with two tries.</p>
<p>Spencer's second started on the visitor's own line and went through eight pairs of hands before the Northerns defence finally capitulated.</p>
<p>Richter's hat-trick came two minutes into injury time. From a Ruben Kruger burst Richter picked up and dotted the ball down through a pile of bodies. Van Rensburg's conversion tied the scores.</p>
<p>Van Rensburg eased Northerns six points ahead with two early second half penalties, but another spell of brilliant handling from Auckland put Lima over for his second try in the 55th minute.</p>
<p>Cashmore stretched the lead with two penalties in the 66th and 74th minute and with injury time looming Northern seemed down and out at 40-33.</p>
<p>But Auckland were penalised for going over the top in front of their own posts and Tromp's try from a quick tap earned the hosts a draw.</p>
<p>Lima was sent to the sin-bin for 10 minutes after felling Springbok scrumhalf Joost van der Westhuizen with a stiff arm tackle. Van der Westhuizen stayed on, but was hurt a second time and stretchered off 30 minutes into the game.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Northern Transvaal: Clive Terreblanche (Kosie Alberts 65 min); Wynand Lourens, Andre Snyman, Danie van Schalkwyk, Jacques Olivier; Theo van Rensburg, Joost van der Westhuizen (Conrad Breytenbach 28 min); Adriaan Richter, Schutte Bekker, Ruben Kruger (captain) (Jannie Brooks 53 min), Wium Basson (Johan Otto 49 min), Krynauw Otto, Matthew Proudfoot, Henry Tromp, Lourens Campher.</p>
<p>Auckland:  Adrian Cashmore; Joeli Vidiri, Eroni Clarke, Lee Stensness, Brian Lima; Carlos Spencer, Ofisa Tonu'u; Dylan Mika, Mark Carter (Matthew Webber 64 min), Xavier Rush, Richard Fromont, Robin Brooke, Olo Bron, Sean Fitzpatrick, Paul Thomson (Orcades Crawford 32 min).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRETORIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
