<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412632" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: TENNIS-HINGIS GIVES SWISS 1-0 LEAD OVER SLOVAKIA.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-HINGIS GIVES SWISS 1-0 LEAD OVER SLOVAKIA.</headline>
<dateline>KOSICE, Slovakia 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Open champion Martina Hingis put Switzerland 1-0 ahead in their Federation Cup world group two first round tie against Slovakia on Saturday.</p>
<p>Hingis, who was born in Kosice 16 years ago, beat Slovak</p>
<p>number two Katarina Studenikova 6-1 6-3 in the opening singles.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a nice feeling to play here after 12 years,&quot; Hingis said after the match.</p>
<p>&quot;I got a great welcome when I entered the court and it was also great to win,&quot; Hingis, who has yet to lose a match this year, added.</p>
<p>Hingis sped through the first set in just 28 minutes after breaking Studenikova in the first game and conceded only the fifth game.</p>
<p>In the second set Hingis lost her serve, broke back, but again lost serve to trail 3-2.</p>
<p>In the sixth game, Studenikova had three points on serve for a 4-2 lead, but Hingis kept her cool to level at 3-3 and went on to win the match.</p>
<p>&quot;My serve is not my strongest point and I haven't played a match for the last two weeks,&quot; Hingis said.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew I had to tighten up my game, managed it and got into it again,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>When Hingis entered the court she got a warm welcome from the home crowd which, however, turned patriotic when the match started.</p>
<p>&quot;But I think my father was keeping is fingers crossed for me even though I was actually playing against his country,&quot; Hingis said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KOSICE, Slovakia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
