<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412639" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-NEW LAW ALLOWS GOALKEEPERS TO MOVE AT PENALTIES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-NEW LAW ALLOWS GOALKEEPERS TO MOVE AT PENALTIES.</headline>
<byline>Damien Lynch</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Goalkeepers will be allowed to move along their line at penalties, but they will no longer be able to handle the ball direct from a throw-in, the International Football Board ruled on Saturday.</p>
<p>The board, soccer's ultimate law-making body which comprises four members from the British associations and four from FIFA, also issued a directive to referees that goalkeepers will only be permitted to hold on to the ball for a maximum of six seconds after initially getting hold of it and be allowed to take only four steps with the ball in their hands before having to release it.</p>
<p>Under the new laws, an indirect free kick will be awarded if the goalkeeper handles the ball after receiving it directly from a throw in.</p>
<p>The Board also ruled that a goal may now be scored directly from either a goal kick or from the kick-off without another player touching it.</p>
<p>In addition, the ball is now deemed in play when it is kicked or is moved forward, rather than when it has travelled its own circumference.</p>
<p>The new laws come into effect on July 1.</p>
<p>The laws themselves have also been re-written for the first time since they were re-drafted by Sir Stanley Rous in 1936.</p>
<p>Sepp Blatter, FIFA's general secretary said: &quot;This is the first time in over 60 years that the rule book has been re-drafted&quot; explaining that the reason was to simplify and modernise the language and iron out any misinterpretations from one continent to another.</p>
<p>But FIFA have turned down the use of video technology at matches, and also said it was against the idea of having two referees officiate in the same game.</p>
<p>&quot;So far we have had no demands to have two referees in a game,&quot; he said. &quot;But matches should be refereed by one person and so such experiments should not be allowed.&quot;</p>
<p>A plan to use video cameras as an aid to the referee in an international friendly between France and Sweden later this month was also turned down -- and it is now doubtful that any video technology will be used at soccer matches in the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very grateful to television for promoting our game and also for bringing in financial resources. But we do not want television to control our game, we do not want television to take over the responsibilities of the referee,&quot; Blatter said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our game will have to live with human errors and passion. If it becomes a scientific game that is not good. Television should be a good partner, but not control the game,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>If the proposal had been accepted, it would have allowed the referee to consult a television monitor at the side of the pitch to help him determine questionable incidents during play.</p>
<p>There has been a huge demand for video technology to be allowed at matches this week in England, following a controversial penalty awarded in an F.A. Cup match between Chelsea and Leicester on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The match, which Chelsea won 1-0 with a penalty three minutes before the end of extra time, became the subject of intense media interest after TV replays showed the referee had wrongly awarded the deciding spot-kick.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
