<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412689" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: RALLYING-MAKINEN LEADS IN PUNISHING FIRST DAY IN KENYA.</title>
<headline>RALLYING-MAKINEN LEADS IN PUNISHING FIRST DAY IN KENYA.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI, Kenya 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reigning world rally champion Tommi Makinen overcame punishing conditions on Saturday to take the lead in Kenya's Safari Rally on a day of crashes and punctures.</p>
<p>World championship leader Carlos Sainz was forced out midway through the second stage when he swerved to avoid an animal. He had been in third place at the end of the first stage.</p>
<p>The Spaniard's Ford car plunged off the road and suffered a puncture. Although he managed to repair it, dust damaged the wheel nuts, forcing him to withdraw.</p>
<p>Makinen, who won the event last season, fought back from a first stage crash that caused a puncture and left him down in fourth place in his Mitsubishi.</p>
<p>German Armin Schwarz was only 33 seconds behind after more than 220 kilometres of competitive stages through some of the most difficult terrain faced on the world rally calendar.</p>
<p>&quot;The conditions are unbelievable. This year the rally is very, very dry, but it still makes the conditions incredibly tough and unpredictable,&quot; said Swede Kenneth Eriksson, who was the first high-profile retirement from the event.</p>
<p>The winner of this year's Swedish Rally dropped out at the end of the first stage after leaving the service area too late following accident damage repairs.</p>
<p>&quot;I was going quite slowly over a crest and there was this big stone which had probably been thrown up by another car. We tried to avoid it but it was too late and it took the wheel off the car.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite being 50 kilometres from the end of the stage, Eriksson was able to continue on the run with three wheels on his Subaru, even reaching speeds of up to 120 kph, but the repairs took too long at the end of the stage.</p>
<p>His Subaru team mate Briton Colin McRae, in fourth place at the end of the second stage, also encountered difficulties in that first leg. He suffered two punctures and, with only one spare, was forced to complete that opening stage with a flat tyre.</p>
<p>With two stages left on Saturday, the most obvious threat remains home favourite Kenyan Ian Duncan, who lies in fifth place at the end of the second stage and could repeat his victory from the 1994 rally.</p>
<p>He made full use of his local knowledge of the terrain in the first stage to set the fastest time. Although he was more than five minutes behind Makinen at the end of the second stage after front strut failure, the harsh nature of the event means that anyone in the top 10 has a good chance of victory.</p>
<p>Schwarz had warned before the start of the rally that reliability would be an important factor in the outcome.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure some of my rivals will start really fast and think the car is strong enough to treat the Safari like a short European event,&quot; he said. &quot;The car that holds together will win this rally.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI, Kenya"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
