<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412656" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-FRANCE STUN ENGLAND, CLOSE IN ON TITLE.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-FRANCE STUN ENGLAND, CLOSE IN ON TITLE.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>France pulled off one of the great escapes in Twickenham history on Saturday to beat England 23-20 and wrap one arm around this season's Five Nations trophy.</p>
<p>Trailing 20-6 heading into the last 20 minutes against an England side looking totally in control, the French dug deep into their repertoire to conjure two converted tries and a final match-clinching penalty from hero-of-the-hour Christophe Lamaison.</p>
<p>The Brive centre scored 18 points in total, including a try, to ensure his side's first win at Twickenham since 1987 and give them an outstanding opportunity to clinch a grand slam at home to Scotland in a fortnight.</p>
<p>England, who had blown apart the Scots and Irish in the last 20 minutes of their previous matches, must now travel to Cardiff to face Wales with their world suddenly turned upside down.</p>
<p>Coach Jack Rowell and ex-captain Will Carling had hinted beforehand this could be their final match at Twickenham in their respective roles, but neither will surely want to depart on such a disappointing note.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the worst 20 minutes of my life,&quot; admitted Rowell. &quot;In the first half we didn't let them play, but it's all about mental and physical stamina.&quot;</p>
<p>Even the French, who performed a joyous lap of honour pursued by their supporters, could not quite believe what had happened.</p>
<p>Until Laurent Leflamand successfully pursued a chip by Alain Penaud in the 62nd minute to drag their side back into contention, there seemed no way England would let their hard-earned advantage slip.</p>
<p>On the sort of gusty afternoon which both goalkickers must have dreaded, England fly-half Paul Grayson had confounded everyone by landing three well-struck penalties inside the first 11 minutes to give his side a 9-3 lead after Lamaison had opened the scoring in the third minute.</p>
<p>The visitors, playing with the wind, would have wished for at least a 10-point cushion at the interval, but they found it almost impossible to force their way into dangerous territory.</p>
<p>Strong English defence, a shortage of line-out ball and the whistle of Scottish referee Jim Fleming caused an increasing amount of Gallic frustration and worse was to follow just before half-time.</p>
<p>Fleming allowed play to continue following a French offside and Lawrence Dallaglio burst on to a short pass from Phil de Glanville to storm 35 metres to the line for his third international try.</p>
<p>A 14-6 lead was extended further by a drop-goal and a fourth penalty from Grayson early in the second-half, leaving France with the rugby equivalent of scaling the Eiger.</p>
<p>Somehow they managed it without captain Abdel Benazzi, forced off through injury with France still trailing 20-13 and Lamaison, in particular, will not have to buy a drink for years.</p>
<p>He took Penaud's short pass superbly to dummy his way over in the 70th minute and kept his nerve to slot both the conversion and the all-important penalty, awarded against Dallaglio in a ruck close to the English line.</p>
<p>England flung themselves desperately into attack, but the French held firm and should now clinch their first grand slam for a decade.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>England - 15-Tim Stimpson; 14-Jon Sleightholme, 13-Will Carling, 12-Phil de Glanville (captain), 11-Tony Underwood; 10- Paul Grayson, 9-Andy Gomarsall; 8-Tim Rodber, 7-Richard Hill, 6- Lawrence Dallaglio, 5-Simon Shaw, 4-Martin Johnson, 3-Jason Leonard, 2-Mark Regan, 1-Graham Rowntree.</p>
<p>France - 15-Jean-Luc Sadourny; 14-Laurent Leflamand, 13-Christophe Lamaison, 12-Stephane Glas, 11-David Venditti; 10-Alain Penaud, 9-Philippe Carbonneau; 8-Fabien Pelous, 7-Olivier Magne, 6-Abdel Benazzi (captain) (21-Marc de Rougemont, 68th), 5-Hugues Miorin (19-Richard Castel, 49th), 4-Olivier Merle, 3-Franck Tournaire, 2-Marc Dal Maso, 1-Christian Califano.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
