<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412647" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: GOLF-WOOSNAM TAKES ONE-STROKE LEAD IN DESERT CLASSIC.</title>
<headline>GOLF-WOOSNAM TAKES ONE-STROKE LEAD IN DESERT CLASSIC.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ian Woosnam produced an eagle-birdie finish to snatch a one-shot lead with a five-under-par 67 in the third round of the Desert Classic on Saturday.</p>
<p>Woosnam pitched his second shot at the 351-yard 17th into the hole on one bounce from 110 yards out for an eagle two, then made a birdie four at the last for a 54-hole total of 203, 13 under par.</p>
<p>&quot;I just had a lucky break at 17 but it's my birthday tomorrow so I need it. I'll be 39 and it will be a nice birthday present if I can win.&quot;</p>
<p>Bernhard Langer could not birdie the last and finished one behind after a 68, level with Australian left-hander Richard Green, a 26-year-old from Melbourne who carded a six-under 66.</p>
<p>Defending champion Colin Montgomerie squandered birdie chances on the last three greens among others but emerged with a 68 for sole possession of fourth place on 11 under.</p>
<p>&quot;I missed from eight feet at the 16th, five feet at 17 and from 15 feet at the last. I'd have liked one of them to be a bit closer.</p>
<p>&quot;I left a lot out there today but I'm only two shots back and I haven't given up on this one yet,&quot; Europe's number one for the past four years said.</p>
<p>World number one Greg Norman shot 67 and shared fifth spot on 10 under with Irishman Raymond Burns, Swede Klas Eriksson and Briton Malcolm Mackenzie.</p>
<p>&quot;That was the worst score I could have shot,&quot; Norman said. &quot;I left a few makeable putts out there.</p>
<p>&quot;But coming over here to play before the Doral Classic in Florida next week was a very good move for me. It has helped with my chipping, my putting and my visualisation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This is Norman's first full tournament since he won his fifth Australian Open title in November, though he turned out to win a million dollars in the world championship of golf finals early in January.</p>
<p>Spaniard Jose Maria Olazabal continued his fine comeback after 18 months away with chronic foot problems by posting a seven-under-par 65, which drew plaudits from the others.</p>
<p>&quot;It was excellent. He's out there to win. He's walking well and you can see he wants to win, nothing else,&quot; Woosnam said.</p>
<p>Olazabal is tied for 11th, five shots off the lead.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't expect a 65, that's for sure,&quot; said Olazabal, who was only two shots off the lead when he finished with the big names still to start.</p>
<p>He expected them to score well and they did. &quot;But I think it would be difficult to win anyway. To win in this situation you have to feel more confident with yourself.</p>
<p>&quot;This is my first tournament and I still don't feel all that comfortable over the ball and when the pressure is there that's when it takes a toll.</p>
<p>&quot;I need a few more weeks and a few more tournaments to get the swing I want and the confidence that is needed to win,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Overnight leader Domingo Hospital of Spain slipped back to a joint 11th after a 74.</p>
<p>The high point of Langer's round came at the long 13th, where he hit a three-iron second left of the green on to a sandy path.</p>
<p>&quot;I had to get it over a little hedge bordering the cart path and under the branches of the palm trees through a gap of about two or three feet and pitch it in the rough with a little backswing and a little roll on it.</p>
<p>&quot;I got it to 15 feet and made the putt for my birdie. That was the highlight of my day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Green had seven birdies on Saturday including one from 25 feet at the 16th and a 10-footer at the last. He made bogey at the eighth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
