<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412781" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK actress Vanessa Redgrave on neo-Nazi hitlist.</title>
<headline>UK actress Vanessa Redgrave on neo-Nazi hitlist.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>British actress Vanessa Redgrave revealed on Saturday that she has been placed on a celebrity hit-list by the shadowy neo-Nazi group Combat 18.</p>
<p>Redgrave, 60, who is known for supporting left-wing causes and was recently reported to have a close friendship with black actor David Harewood, said she had been targeted for physical attack by the group.</p>
<p>&quot;In April last year, Scotland Yard (police) installed a safety alarm and panic button in my home because I and a number of celebrities, had been targeted for physical attack by Combat 18, the British fascist group,&quot; Redgrave said in a letter to the Daily Mail newspaper.</p>
<p>Other celebrities said to have been appeared on the hit list include soccer club and computer boss Alan Sugar, members of parliament Paddy Ashdown and Peter Hain and journalists Anna Ford and Bernard Levin.</p>
<p>British police declined to confirm or deny the report for security reasons but it followed a Danish letter bomb campaign in January aimed at British sports stars in mixed race marriages.</p>
<p>Combat 18 was linked to the Danish campaign in which police in Denmark seized three letter bombs hidden in video cassettes and posted to addresses in London.</p>
<p>Combat 18, formed in 1992, is named after the first and eighth letters of the alphabet A and H -- the initials of Adolf Hitler. Police sources believe the group has about 100 members and have linked it to a number of apparently random attacks on Jews and blacks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
