<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412779" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Diana settles libel dress row with newspaper.</title>
<headline>Diana settles libel dress row with newspaper.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Express Newspapers have agreed an out-of-court settlement with Princess Diana and withdrawn a claim that she planned to keep half the proceeds from a charity auction of her dresses.</p>
<p>The paper published a front-page apology in its Sunday edition, saying it had been unwittingly deceived by an elaborate forgery.</p>
<p>The Express on Sunday had claimed to have seen documents purporting to show that that only half the money raised from the auction would go to charity.</p>
<p>That prompted Princess Diana's lawyers to issue a libel writ last Monday.</p>
<p>In its front-page apology, the paper said: &quot;It is now clear that the documents were forged although we believed they were from a reliable source.&quot;</p>
<p>The paper apologised and said: &quot;We have agreed to pay a substantial sum, by way of compensation, and her legal costs.&quot;</p>
<p>The dresses were worn by one of the world's most photographed women at royal and state occasions between 1981 and 1996. Her eldest son, Prince William, first suggested the charity auction.</p>
<p>The collection is to go on view in London at Christie's the auctioneers in June before being shipped to New York for the eagerly awaited sale.</p>
<p>The paper pledged in an editorial to launch its own investigation and said: &quot;Yes, we made a mistake and we do not shrink from admitting it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
