<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412778" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - March 8.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - March 8.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on March 8 in history.</p>
<p>1702 - Queen Anne acceded to the throne in England after the death of William III.</p>
<p>1717 - English iron master Abraham Darby, the first to use coke for iron smelting, died.</p>
<p>1844 - Charles XIV John, king of Sweden and Norway, died and was succeeded by his son Oscar I.</p>
<p>1869 - Hector Berlioz, French composer of the &quot;Symphonie fantastique&quot;, died.</p>
<p>1874 - Millard Fillmore, 13th president of the United States, died.</p>
<p>1879 - Otto Hahn, German Nobel prize winner for chemistry (1944) and co-discoverer of nuclear fission, born.</p>
<p>1889 - John Ericsson, Swedish-born U.S. ship designer and inventor of the first successful screw propeller, died.</p>
<p>1910 - The Royal Aero Club issued the first British pilot's licence to J.T.C Moore Brabazon.</p>
<p>1917 - (23rd February, old style date). Riots and strikes in St. Petersburg marked the start of the 'February Revolution' in Russia.</p>
<p>1917 - Count Ferdinand von Zeppelin, German soldier, inventor and pioneer in airship development, died.</p>
<p>1920 - Denmark joined the League of Nations.</p>
<p>1921 - Spanish Prime Minister Eduardo Dato was assassinated by anarchists near his home in Madrid.</p>
<p>1921 - French troops occupied Duesseldorf and other towns in the Ruhr after Germany failed to pay reparations.</p>
<p>1930 - William Howard Taft, 27th president of the United States (1909-13), died.</p>
<p>1942 - Rangoon fell to the Japanese after being evacuated by British forces.</p>
<p>1948 - The U.S. Supreme Court ruled that religious instruction in public schools violated the constitution.</p>
<p>1950 - The Soviet Union claimed to be in possession of the atomic bomb.</p>
<p>1961 - Sir Thomas Beecham, conductor and founder of several British orchestras including the London Philharmonic and the Royal Philharmonic, died.</p>
<p>1963 - A group of officers led by Colonel Ziad Hariri overthrew the Syrian government and established a National Council of Revolution.</p>
<p>1966 - The Nelson Column in Dublin was destroyed in an Irish Republican Army (IRA) bomb explosion.</p>
<p>1971 - Harold Lloyd, U.S. silent film star and comedian, died. Best remembered for the scene in &quot;Safety Last&quot; in which he was seen dangling from a skyscraper with nothing to hold on to but the hand of a clock.</p>
<p>1973 - IRA car bombs exploded outside the Old Bailey courthouse and Scotland Yard police headquarters in London, killing one and injuring 238. On the same day a referendum in Northern Ireland favoured maintaining ties with the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>1978 - Belgian millionaire Charles Bracht was kidnapped. His body was found on April 10.</p>
<p>1983 - British composer William Walton died. His &quot;Facade&quot; music is regarded as his most popular success.</p>
<p>1993 - Radical leader Gulbuddin Hekmatyar accepted the post of prime minister of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>1994 - 64 people were killed and 370 injured when a train packed with mainly black commuters was derailed near Durban, South Africa.</p>
<p>1996 - The U.N. flag was lowered to mark the end of the United Nations peacekeeping mandate in Rwanda (UNAMIR).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
