<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412785" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British political skirmishing turns nasty.</title>
<headline>British political skirmishing turns nasty.</headline>
<byline>Lyndsay Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scare tactics looked set to shape Britain's pre-election skirmishing after Prime Minister John Major warned voters of &quot;a midsummer nightmare&quot; if they backed the opposition Labour Party.</p>
<p>With an election due within weeks, Major's biting tone -- backed by strong language from some of his party's top officials -- showed the gloves are off in the British election campaign before the polling day has even been named.</p>
<p>Senior Conservatives said Major, well behind in the opinion polls, is making a last-ditch bid to hold onto power by telling voters a Labour government would lead to new taxes, a constitutional crisis and a damaging social policy.</p>
<p>&quot;We shouldn't pretend we haven't been warned. The signs are all there,&quot; Major said in a speech in Scotland on Friday night. &quot;Britain could be just weeks away from a midsummer nightmare.&quot;</p>
<p>Major is always at his best under pressure, and the pressure piled on this week when Labour trounced the ruling Conservatives in a key by-election in northwest England.</p>
<p>Labour candidate Ben Chapman overturned a Conservative majority of 8,183 votes on Thursday to win the affluent commuter-belt constituency of Wirral South by 7,888 votes.</p>
<p>Were the Wirral result to be repeated in the general election, which is expected on May 1, Labour would win by a landslide. But Major sought to portray Wirral as a dress rehearsal that went wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;One cross in the wrong box and we could have more spending, new social burdens on business, new union rights, the end of choice in education and the end of new health opportunities. The beginning of the breakup of Britain,&quot; he said. &quot;All this is on Labour's menu. It could all happen. So, next time it's serious.&quot;</p>
<p>The Conservatives came from behind to win the 1992 election, but face a far tougher fight to claw back Labour's 20-point lead in today's opinion polls and win a fifth straight term.</p>
<p>Reverting to tried and tested tactics, Major declared an end to the &quot;phoney war&quot; of late and said &quot;new Labour&quot; was just like old Labour: the party of higher taxes and higher interest rates.</p>
<p>His top lieutenants painted the same nightmare scenario in what was clearly a coordinated new front in the campaign.</p>
<p>Home Secretary Michael Howard declared that his party's &quot;fight back begins here today...We shall fight over the next few weeks as we've never fought before.&quot;</p>
<p>Conservative Party Chairman Brian Mawhinney said &quot;the countdown has begun&quot; against a party that will always &quot;tax and spend their way to economic crisis&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Who pays? You pay,&quot; he told executives on Friday night in Yorskhire, northern England.</p>
<p>But the soundbite of the day went to an unnamed Conservative who was quoted in London's Evening Standard newspaper as saying his party's approach to voters was &quot;to scare them shitless&quot; about Labour's plans for the nation.</p>
<p>Labour snapped right back.</p>
<p>&quot;The Tories are now plumbing new depths of abuse as they desperately thrash about after the disaster of the Wirral by-election,&quot; said prominent Labour politician Brian Wilson.</p>
<p>&quot;The senior Tory (Conservative) quoted has let the cat out of the bag. He has confirmed that the Tories will sink to any level of lie and smear in order to win.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
