<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412793" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: U.N. pulls out aid workers from key Zaire town.</title>
<headline>U.N. pulls out aid workers from key Zaire town.</headline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations evacuated on Saturday all foreign aid workers from the key east Zaire town of Kisangani because of growing insecurity caused by the advance of Zairean rebels, the U.N. refugee agency said.</p>
<p>&quot;The third (and last) plane has just left Kisangani. A total of 57 expatriates have been evacuated,&quot; said Paul Stromberg, UNHCR regional spokesman.</p>
<p>&quot;Reports say Kisangani is very tense and the evacuation is because of general insecurity in the area which makes it impossible to work,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The last of three U.N. World Food Programme (WFP) flights left Kisangani at 12.15 p.m. (1015 GMT), WFP spokeswoman Michele Quintaglie said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a tremendous setback for our operation and it comes at a time when we have firmly established food routes into the area,&quot; Quintaglie said.</p>
<p>A week's worth of food stocks for a distribution were being left on the ground at Kisangani and Tingi Tingi, she said.</p>
<p>Aid workers with the U.N. and non-governmental organisations were being relocated to Kinshasa from Kisangani and Tingi Tingi, Quintaglie said.</p>
<p>She said the operation was technically a relocation rather than an evacuation since the aid workers were being moved within the same country.</p>
<p>Hutu refugees started moving from Tingi Tingi camp on Friday and WFP advised its staff to return to Kisangani for security reasons.</p>
<p>Zaire rebels said on Goma's rebel Radio of the People they took the strategic east Zairean town of Kindu 400 km (250 miles) south of Kisangani on Friday.</p>
<p>Kisangani is considered the greatest obstacle to control of east Zaire for the rebels, who have captured a swath of territory in east Zaire in a campaign starting last October.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
