<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412768" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: NORDIC SKIING-VIALBE ENDS BRILLIANT RUN WITH FIFTH GOLD.</title>
<headline>NORDIC SKIING-VIALBE ENDS BRILLIANT RUN WITH FIFTH GOLD.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Vignal</byline>
<dateline>TRONDHEIM, Norway 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Yelena Vialbe collected her fifth gold medal in as many races at the Nordic skiing world championships by winning the closing women's event, Saturday's classical style, 30-km cross-country race.</p>
<p>Vialbe raised her arms and screamed after crossing the line in a winning time of one hour 23 minutes 4.90 seconds.</p>
<p>She could have done without the gold in the 5-km race, which was awarded to her after compatriot Lyubov Yegorova was stripped of the world title for testing positive for the banned stimulant Bromantan.</p>
<p>But Vialbe's wins in the 15-km, the 10-km pursuit and the relay, not to mention her final demonstration in the 30-km, amounted to a brilliant overall showing.</p>
<p>No woman had won all the titles in one single world championships since Galina Kulakova of the Soviet Union did in 1974 in Falun, Sweden, where only three women's race were held.</p>
<p>There have been five women's events in world championships since 1989 in Lahti, Finland, where Vialbe burst into the limelight by winning two golds and one silver.</p>
<p>After helping Russia to win the relay on Thursday, Vialbe said she was still shocked by the news of Yegorova's positive test, which broke the previous day.</p>
<p>But on Saturday she was genuinely happy and bore a permanent smile during the post-race news conference.</p>
<p>Vialbe made a strong start and completed the first of two laps of a hilly, 15-km circuit 41 seconds ahead of Italian Stefania Belmondo.</p>
<p>Knowing she was comfortably in the lead, Vialbe did not give her all in the second lap as she came home 28.30 seconds ahead of Belmondo, who had to be content with her fourth silver medal in the championships.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew what the times were and I was not worried,&quot; said Vialbe. &quot;The most important thing to me was the win, not the time difference.&quot;</p>
<p>Belmondo said she had felt helpless.</p>
<p>&quot;I wanted gold and I was going as fast as I could but Yelena was simply too strong,&quot; she said. &quot;She's a formidable athlete.&quot;</p>
<p>Marit Mikkelsplass of Norway sprinted to the line, believing Larisa Lasutina of Russia was well ahead of her and hoping to take fourth place from compatriot Anita Moen Guidon.</p>
<p>But Lasutina collapsed in the last few kilometres to end up fourth and Mikkelsplass took bronze, 1:50.80 behind the winner. Guidon finished fifth.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought I was fighting with Anita for fourth or fifth place,&quot; Mikkelsplass said. &quot;The bronze medal came as a surprise, a very good surprise.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TRONDHEIM, Norway"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
