<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412786" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWAZILAND: Golf-Druian takes third-round lead in Swazi Open.</title>
<headline>Golf-Druian takes third-round lead in Swazi Open.</headline>
<byline>Mark Stokes</byline>
<dateline>MBABANE 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's Warrick Druian, borrowing a little from the Tiger Woods philosophy on golf, opened up a two-stroke lead after the third round of the Royal Swazi Open on Saturday.</p>
<p>The 27-year-old Druian, still without a win after six years as a professional, fired a seven-under-par 65 for a 54-hole total of 199 - 17-under for the tournament.</p>
<p>He effectively made up four shots on overnight leader and playing partner Nic Henning of South Africa, who carded a third round 69 to slip back into second place on 201.</p>
<p>England-born Chris Davison struggled a little with his putting for a 69 and third place on 203 while Scotland's Derek Crawford, who plays out of Norway club Trondheim, carded the low round of the day with an eight-under 64 to share fourth place on 205</p>
<p>Druian, who picked up an eagle-three, six birdies and one bogey during his round, said later that he had learned a bit about dominating on the golf course from American sensation Tiger Woods.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been watching a lot of Tiger Woods on television and he always looks like he owns the golf course when he plays,&quot; Druian said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the past, I always used to think like a winner on the golf course but, if I then wasn't as good as other players, got frustrated and performed way below potential.</p>
<p>&quot;But I now feel that I belong on the tour and tomorrow I just want to go out there and dominate on the course.&quot;</p>
<p>Englishman Michael Archer, playing at the back of the field in the morning, made a rare albatross-two at the 484-metre par-five fifth hole at the Royal Swazi Sun Golf Club.</p>
<p>After holing his three-wood approach, Archer went on to card a 68 for a 54-hole total of 213.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWAZD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MBABANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWAZILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
