<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412758" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER SHOWCASE-DEPLETED JUVENTUS FORGE AHEAD.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-DEPLETED JUVENTUS FORGE AHEAD.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>TURIN, Italy 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Michele Padovano, the spearhead of a depleted Juventus attack, helped the European Cup holders go eight points clear at the top of the Italian league on Saturday with a 2-0 home win against Vicenza.</p>
<p>Padovano, usually a &quot;super-sub&quot; but starting out at the Delle Alpi stadium in the absence of injured Italian international Alessandro Del Piero and Croat Alen Boksic, scored the second goal from the penalty spot in the 64th minute.</p>
<p>Christian Vieri, the other main Juventus attacker, had been felled in the area by Vicenza captain Giovanni Lopez.</p>
<p>In a match that highlighted the strength in depth that Juventus can boast, with the largely second string team still managing to look a cut above their opponents, midfielder Angelo Di Livio opened the scoring in the 23rd minute.</p>
<p>Di Livio's rare league goal came after veteran Attilio Lombardo crossed, for Padovano and Vieri to get touches before Italian international Di Livio lobbed in a well-angled shot that soared over goalkeeper Luca Mondini and into the net.</p>
<p>Vicenza, who left star Uruguayan striker Marcelo Otero on the bench for the entire first half, had far fewer chances but could have scored in the 33rd minute when Uruguayan defender Gustavo Mendez had a shot parried by Michelangelo Rampulla.</p>
<p>The win left Juventus on 44 points from 22 matches, ahead of second placed Sampdoria on 36 points.</p>
<p>Sampdoria play Bologna in Genoa on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Juventus match was brought forward because the Turin club travels to Norway for a European Cup quarter-final against Trondheim club Rosenborg, who beat AC Milan in an earlier Europan Cup match, on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>For the statisticians, it was the 20th time Juventus had beaten Vicenza in serie A in Turin in 27 matches.</p>
<p>Vicenza, who reached the Italian Cup final for the first time in their 95 year history this week, had won the two last encounters -- both in Vicenza. Juventus won the last match between the two in Turin in September 1995 1-0.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TURIN, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
