<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412792" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Aid workers leave Zaire's 3rd city citing security.</title>
<headline>Aid workers leave Zaire's 3rd city citing security.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign aid workers left Zaire's third city of Kisangani on Saturday, citing insecurity and a lack of safe conduct permits from the army that is fighting to stem rebel advances in the area.</p>
<p>Zaire's defence ministry said government troops still controlled Kindu, a regional transport hub and army operational base to the south, but independent sources said the town appeared to have fallen to rebels on Friday afternoon.</p>
<p>Hubert Edongo, Kinshasa representative of the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, said 57 relief workers from the U.N. and non-governmental organisations (NGOs) were being evacuated from Kisangani to the capital on three flights.</p>
<p>&quot;Since we were proving unable to work and had no security guarantees in an operational zone, it was decided to withdraw our staff temporarily to Kinshasa,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The other element, and it's extremely important, is the suspension of safe conduct permits which have been blocked since the beginning of the week,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Edongo said refugees had started leaving Tingi Tingi, the largest refugee camp left in eastern Zaire with up to 200,000 Hutus, many of whom fled Rwanda in 1994 fearing reprisals after the genocide of minority Tutsis by hardline Hutus.</p>
<p>Kisangani, on the Zaire River, is the headquarters for army operations in the war zone where government forces launched a counter-offensive on January 20.</p>
<p>The rebels, who took up arms in October and hold towns and territory in the east, responded by attacking on several fronts, throwing the notoriously ill-disciplined army on the defensive.</p>
<p>The government, after its regular Friday cabinet meeting, ordered army commanders to shoot anyone looting in the war zone on sight -- whether they were civilians or soldiers.</p>
<p>Government spokesman Jean-Claude Biebie, said that the government deplored &quot;pillaging and other acts of vandalism carried out by soldiers&quot;.</p>
<p>The rebels say they have captured Kindu, up-river from Kisangani. Defence officials hotly deny this, saying extra troops went in on Friday with the regional commander.</p>
<p>&quot;General Kalume Numbi landed at Kindu yesterday,&quot; one said on Saturday. &quot;We are sending further reinforcements in today.&quot;</p>
<p>Kindu is about 400 km (250 miles) south of Kisangani, which the Tutsi-led rebels have identified as a target.</p>
<p>&quot;The security situation at Kindu does not permit us to deliver aid,&quot; Edongo said.</p>
<p>&quot;At Tingi Tingi extreme tension has meant that our staff have had to leave in the past few days,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Witnesses say armed Hutu hardliners were among the refugees.</p>
<p>Edongo said refugees had started to leave Tingi Tingi, which also shelters Burundian Hutus, on Friday. Tingi Tingi is about 200 km (125 miles) south of Kisangani.</p>
<p>Zaire accuses neighbouring Rwanda, Burundi and Uganda of invading in support of the rebels. It has rejected direct peace talks with the rebels, something South Africa's President Nelson Mandela has been trying to organise.</p>
<p>It says it is prepared to join regional peace talks in Nairobi, once all foreign troops have left its territory, and an Organisation of African Unity summit in Togo on March 26 on the crisis in Central Africa's volatile Great Lakes region.</p>
<p>&quot;The search for peace in Zaire should follow this path alone for the settlement of the crisis in Zaire in particular and the Great Lakes sub-region in general,&quot; government spokesman Biebie said late on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
