<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412780" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Labour Party details plan to cut unemployment.</title>
<headline>UK's Labour Party details plan to cut unemployment.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's opposition Labour Party, riding high after a crushing by-election victory, pledged on Saturday to eradicate the nightmare of young people facing a lifetime without work.</p>
<p>In a keynote speech detailing Labour's early spending plans should it win national elections within three months time, Party leader Tony Blair said a Labour government's first budget would focus on measures to get the unemployed off state aid and into work.</p>
<p>&quot;For today's school leavers there will be no lifetime on the dole (state aid) under Labour,&quot; Blair said. &quot;We simply cannot continue with a situation where today unemployment costs the country more than education.&quot;</p>
<p>But Blair, anxious to bury Labour's past image as a high tax and spend party, said the aim of the programme was not to raise public spending but to reduce it.</p>
<p>He said a new Labour government would use a one-off windfall on the profits of recently-privatised utility companies to fund a system of hand-outs to employers who provide new jobs for young people and the long-term unemployed.</p>
<p>&quot;A windfall levy today to cut the bills of social security tomorrow,&quot; Blair said, detailing plans to get 250,000 young people off welfare and into work.</p>
<p>Blair, whose party is some 20 points ahead of Prime Minister John Major's Conservatives in opinion polls, said it had a been a &quot;landmark week&quot; for Labour thanks to its victory in the affluent Wirral South by-election.</p>
<p>Major was forced to admit after the poll that his days in office were numbered unless the Conservatives could stem the tide of support for Labour, which has been out of power since 1979.</p>
<p>&quot;If opinion does not change then we are going to have a Labour government,&quot; Major said on Friday.</p>
<p>Major is widely expected to call the election for May 1 and if the Wirral South result was repeated it would lead to a landslide win for Labour.</p>
<p>Chancellor of the Exchequer (finance minister) Kenneth Clarke was quick to rubbish Labour's back-to-work proposals, saying it was disingenuous to suppose they would produce a reduction in welfare spending.</p>
<p>&quot;It is Mickey Mouse arithmetic,&quot; Clarke told Britain's Sky News. &quot;It is a large public spending package. It is a large new tax...that has the effect of driving up industrial costs,&quot; Clarke added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
