<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412732" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-BARCELONA CRASH TO 4-0 DEFEAT AT TENERIFE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BARCELONA CRASH TO 4-0 DEFEAT AT TENERIFE.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Barcelona's beleaguered coach Bobby Robson saw his plight worsen on Saturday when two of his players were sent off in a 4-0 Spanish league defeat at Tenerife.</p>
<p>Former England manager Robson refused to discuss his position at the club in a post-match press conference.</p>
<p>Second-placed Barcelona were left six points adrift of leaders Real Madrid, who would go nine points clear with a win at Espanyol on Sunday.</p>
<p>Wins for Deportivo Coruna and Atletico Madrid -- who move to within three and four points of Barcelona respectively -- have also reopened the race for Spain's second European Cup Champions' League place.</p>
<p>Robson blamed his team's bad run on poor refereeing.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we had a penalty -- that's important ... we need those decisions, at the moment we get bad decisions against us, we need good decisions for us,&quot; said Robson afterwards.</p>
<p>Barcelona went behind to a Felipe Minambres goal after just six minutes, and could find no way back after losing defenders Miguel Angel Nadal and Abelardo Fernandez to red cards for last-ditch challenges.</p>
<p>Slavisa Jokanovic scored from a penalty as a result of one of the fouls, and converted another before completing his hat-trick seven minutes from time.</p>
<p>&quot;(With) the red card for Abelardo, the game was over,&quot; said Robson, who took off several key players to rest ahead of next week's European Cup Winners' Cup game with AEK Stockhom</p>
<p>In other games, international midfielder Jose Luis Caminero scored twice to lead Atletico Madrid to an important 3-2 victory over Sevilla.</p>
<p>But Caminero went to bed immediately after the game because of stomach problems and is doubtful for Wednesday's vital European Cup tie at Ajax.</p>
<p>Another point in front ahead of Atletico are Deportivo Coruna, who continued their recovery by winning 2-1 at Rayo Vallecano with goals from midfielders Corentin Martins and Rivaldo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
