<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412796" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>COTE D'IVOIRE: Ivory Coast hosts African performing arts festival.</title>
<headline>Ivory Coast hosts African performing arts festival.</headline>
<dateline>ABIDJAN 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Veteran South African singer Miriam Makeba launched Ivory Coast's third festival of African performing arts on Saturday, with a string of up-and-coming stars hoping it will put them on the road to fame and fortune.</p>
<p>Organisers say several dozen talent spotters from the United States and Europe are attending the Market for African Performing Arts MASA 97, which will put 47 acts from 21 countries on show in the West African nation.</p>
<p>&quot;Aside from its restricted commercial wheeling and dealings, MASA is also the biggest festival of music, dance and theatre in Africa,&quot; they add in the programme for the week-long extravanganza.</p>
<p>The festival, held every two years, features musicians, dance troupes and theatre groups.</p>
<p>Makeba and a host of supporting stars launched the festival with an open-air concert.</p>
<p>The festival's 500 or so performers will appear at different times and different venues throughout Ivory Coast's commercial capital Abidjan until March 8.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABIDJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COTE D'IVOIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
