<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412812" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Internet no threat to broker business - PSA panel.</title>
<headline>Internet no threat to broker business - PSA panel.</headline>
<dateline>PHOENIX, Ariz 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The emergence of the internet may take a slice of business away from stock brokers, but the securities industry is in no danger of being put out of business, industry executives said Saturday.</p>
<p>A panel of experts said the cyberworld will likely garner a small segment of customers, but it may open up the doors for the securities firms to provide more information to customers.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question we will have to provide customers over the next few years the opportunity to see their account and access the information,&quot; said Irving Weiser, chairman and chief executive officer of Interra Financial Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe the role of the investment adviser is something that I believe will be here for decades to come,&quot; he told the PSA Bond Market Trade Association annual meeting here.</p>
<p>The panel was composed of Weiser, James Boris, chairman and chief executive of EVEREN Securities Inc., Howard Clark, Jr., vice chairman of Lehman Brothers Inc and James Dimon, chairman and chief executive of Smith Barney Inc.</p>
<p>The panel also addressed other changes scattered accross the landscape of the securities industry.</p>
<p>Distributors face a tougher time in today's securities world but should find a welcome audience for their services. In addition, small firms also should be able to fill a special niche for their products and services, the panel said.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not believe that everybody can be all things to all people,&quot; Weiser said. There will be lots of opportunities for distributors to find originators to want them to distribute their products.</p>
<p>&quot;For those to stick to their knitting and stay focused on doing what they do well, there are always enormous opportunties.&quot;</p>
<p>The panel said this despite the recent big time merger of Morgan Stanley and Dean Witter Discover &amp; Co and the alliance between Salomon Brothers and Fidelity Investments.</p>
<p>They also urged the securities industires firms to establish a clear corporate culture that still leaves room for individuality.</p>
<p>Overall, the panel members said regulators need to be more flexible than perhaps ever before.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHOENIX, Ariz"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
