<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412862" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Three killed, 10 wounded in fresh Albania clashes.</title>
<headline>Three killed, 10 wounded in fresh Albania clashes.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three people were reported killed and at least 10 wounded on Friday after exchanges of gunfire between protesters and police in the southern Albanian town of Vlore.</p>
<p>Shooting broke out after police clashed with crowds of protesters, who feared the officers were about to storm a university building where students have been on hunger strike for 10 days, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Two people died in the shoot-out and a secret police officer was also killed, but it was unclear whether he was beaten to death by protesters or burnt in the police headquarters after the building was set alight, said one witness in Vlore contacted by Reuters in Tirana by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;Two were hit by gunfire...one Shik (secret policeman) was killed,&quot; the witness added. A hospital official earlier said three people had been shot dead.</p>
<p>According to the hospital official, the victims included a 34-year-old man and a 17-year-old. She did not immediately know if the teenager was male or female.</p>
<p>&quot;There are now two rivers in Vlore -- one is called Vjose and the other our children's blood,&quot; one man told a reporter at the university building.</p>
<p>Scores of people piled into cars to try to secure a road bridge at Mifoli, 20 km (12 miles) north of Vlore -- the only route into the ancient Adriatic port town in an apparent attempt to halt any police reinforcements from the north reaching Vlore.</p>
<p>Townsfolk found an arsenal of weapons in a police building, including handguns, Kalashnikov rifles, automatic machine guns, hand grenades and ammunition, one witness said.</p>
<p>Armed protesters were now protecting students in the university with three people posted at each window, he said.</p>
<p>At around midnight, reporters in Tirana saw five army trucks driving into the capital, where the opposition Forum for Democracy, grouping 11 opposition parties, planned to hold an anti-government rally on Saturday.</p>
<p>A reporter in the southern town of Gjirokaster, 230 km (145 miles) south of Tirana, where students have also staged a hunger strike in solidarity with Vlore, said police had been put on alert there .</p>
<p>Albanian state-run television said on Friday that Gjirokaster police had declared the student protest legal, but the television later said its report was erroneous and police still considered the hunger strike to be an illegal action.</p>
<p>The Vlore student hunger strikers, who have become a beacon for a wave of protests by university students and high school pupils across the Balkan state, were not hurt in the shoot-out.</p>
<p>Violent clashes have spread across Albania since January when hundreds of thousands of investors learnt they had lost all their money after fraudulent pyramid investment schemes collapsed.</p>
<p>Impoverished Albanians turned their wrath on President Sali Berisha and his right-wing Democratic Party government, blaming them for failing to control the savings funds or to alert savers that they could be highly risky.</p>
<p>Protesters and students have called for the resignation of Prime Minister Aleksander Meksi's government and a return of cash poured into the funds. A group of at least 13 dissident deputies within the ruling Democrats also want Meksi to quit.</p>
<p>The unrest is the biggest crisis facing Berisha since he came to power in 1992. He is due to be re-elected for a fresh five-year term in a parliamentary vote on Monday. No other political party is contesting the election.</p>
<p>The Democrats held their first face-to-face talks with the main opposition Socialists on Friday since last May's disputed general election but they failed to find common ground on how to end the current disorder.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
