<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412837" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania's Berisha under pressure to yield more.</title>
<headline>Albania's Berisha under pressure to yield more.</headline>
<byline>Paul Holmes</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's President Sali Berisha ditched his prime minister in response to widespread and sometimes violent popular protests but opposition parties and demonstrators said he must do more.</p>
<p>&quot;Sali, it's your turn now,&quot; shouted one student on hunger strike in the southern port of Vlore after Berisha announced on state television that Prime Minister Aleksander Meksi's right-wing government was resigning.</p>
<p>The main opposition Socialists, successors to the communists who ruled Albania with Stalinist rigour until 1990, also reacted coolly to Berisha's move.</p>
<p>They disputed his position that his Democratic Party could form a new government after other forces had been consulted.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider the only way to get Albania out of deep crisis is the formation of a technocrat government which rules the country until early elections,&quot; one of the Socialist Party leaders, Namik Dokle, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Berisha has already lost credibility among Albanians, who have called on him to quit, too&quot; Dokle said.</p>
<p>Berisha, whose party holds almost all the seats in parliament and is set for re-election there on Monday, made his surprise concession after the most ferocious bout of violence in Europe's poorest state since 40 people died in food riots in 1991.</p>
<p>Up to nine people were reported killed in an exchange of gunfire between residents and the Balkan country's Shik secret police during a night of bloody anarchy in Vlore.</p>
<p>Hospital sources in the town, a hotbed of anti-government protest since shady pyramid savings schemes failed in January, said a 10th person was killed by a shot fired in the air.</p>
<p>In Tirana, at least 10 people were injured in clashes between riot police and stone-throwing demonstrators, while villagers threw up barricades at several points along the road between the capital and Vlore.</p>
<p>Thousands of Albanians lost their meagre life savings in the collapse of the investment funds. Many of them believe, despite vehement denials by Berisha and Meksi, that the funds helped to finance the Democrats' 1996 election campaign.</p>
<p>At the university in Vlore, where one of the biggest funds was based, students on hunger strike for 10 days toasted Meksi's resignation in sparkling wine and danced the macarena.</p>
<p>But they said investors in the Gjallica fund must be re-imbursed for their losses.</p>
<p>&quot;We can assume we will quit the strike tomorrow (Sunday) if all political forces agree to repay Gjallica's debts,&quot; said student Arben Rama. &quot;If they fail to fulfill our main condition, then we will push ahead with our demands.&quot;</p>
<p>Students on hunger strike in the southern town of Gjirokaster were also unimpressed by Meksi's removal.</p>
<p>&quot;We are continuing our hunger strike until all our demands are met. The resignation is a facade,&quot; said one of the student leaders, Shkelqim Mecoriapaz.</p>
<p>Meksi's government won re-election last year in controversial polls boycotted by the main opposition parties, which accused the Democrats of intimidation, widespread irregularities and ballot stuffing.</p>
<p>The Socialists have so far refused to take part in parliament, where Berisha's party holds 122 of the 140 seats.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
