<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412859" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia, Belarus agree on union referendums - agency.</title>
<headline>Russia, Belarus agree on union referendums - agency.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin and Belarus leader Alexander Lukashenko have agreed in principle to hold simultaneous national referendums on closer integration between their countries, Interfax news agency said on Saturday.</p>
<p>It quoted sources close to Yeltsin as saying he would touch on the issue in a speech to the Russian parliament next Thursday, but gave no details and did not give a date for the referendums.</p>
<p>Yeltsin raised the idea of holding referendums on closer integration between the two former Soviet republics in January in a letter to Lukashenko, who welcomed the suggestion.</p>
<p>&quot;The presidents of Russia and Belarus, Boris Yeltsin and Alexander Lukashenko, have decided in principle on holding simultaneous nationwide referendums on integration,&quot; Interfax said.</p>
<p>It said Yeltsin, demanding more resolute moves, believed a state of &quot;semi-unification&quot; was more expensive than the cost of fuller political and economic integration.</p>
<p>Yeltsin and Lukashenko signed a pact last year on creating a &quot;community&quot; between the two Slav states but few moves have been made towards closer integration.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's letter to Lukashenko in January raised the possibility of Russia and its small western neigbour of 10 million people having one government with a single budget and currency taxation laws and united fuel and energy systems.</p>
<p>Calls for re-integration with former Soviet republics are supported by many Russians.</p>
<p>Closer integration with Belarus is widely seen as a rebuff to NATO's plans to offer membership to countries of eastern and central Europe, although the Kremlin denies this is the intention in seeking closer ties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
