<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412805" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALI: Mali opts for April legislative election.</title>
<headline>Mali opts for April legislative election.</headline>
<dateline>BAMAKO 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mali will hold parliamentary elections on April 13, over a month later than planned, state television reported, quoting a letter from its prime minister to the head of the independent electoral commission.</p>
<p>The second round of the elections, which will kick off Mali's second multi-party national elections, would take place on April 27, it added late on Friday.</p>
<p>The Independent National Electoral Commission CENI had requested that the elections be put back from March 9 and March 23, citing organisational delays.</p>
<p>Presidential elections will take place as originally planned on May 4 and 18, municipal elections on June 1.</p>
<p>President Alpha Oumar Konare, a historian, won a five-year term in Mali's widely praised 1992 democratic transition and is seeking a second term.</p>
<p>His supporters, grouped in the Alliance for Democracy in Mali or ADEMA, had a majority in the old 116-seat national assembly. The new assembly will have 147 seats.</p>
<p>There are two main opposition alliances, the Rally of Patriotic Forces (RFP) and Front for Change and Democracy (FCD).</p>
<p>Thirteen opposition deputes placed a motion of no confidence before parliament, accusing the government of being unable to organise elections within the constitutional deadline. Parliament rejected the motion on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Parliament's mandate ends on April 17, Konare's on June 8.</p>
<p>Mali's last elections followed the 1991 overthrow of dictator Moussa Traore by soldiers, led by General Amadou Toumani Toure, who ushered in civilian rule and stepped down.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAMAKO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
