<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412850" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnian Moslems question Serb cooperation pact.</title>
<headline>Bosnian Moslems question Serb cooperation pact.</headline>
<byline>Dan De Luce</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Bosnian Moslem official on Saturday accused the Serb member of the country's collective presidency of exceeding his authority by signing a cooperation agreement with neighbouring Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>The cooperation pact between Bosnia's Serb republic and rump Yugoslavia was signed on Friday by Yugoslav president Zoran Lillic and Momcilo Krajisnik, the Serb representative on the Bosnian presidency.</p>
<p>&quot;Without going into the details of the agreement, Krajisnik cannot sign anything that he is not authorised to sign by the (collective) presidency of Bosnia-Herzegovina,&quot; Mirza Hajric, an aide to the Moslem chairman of the presidency, Alija Izetbegovic, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot sign anything either without his consent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Krajisnik serves as the Serb member on the three-man presidency, which includes Izetbegovic and a Croat member, Kresimir Zubak.</p>
<p>Hajric said the collective presidency did not approve of the agreement and a representative of Bosnia's Serb administration should have signed the agreement, not Krajisnik.</p>
<p>Under terms of a 1995 peace agreement, Bosnia is comprised of a Serb republic and a Moslem-Croat federation which have representatives serving in a central presidency, cabinet and parliament.</p>
<p>A dispute over the cooperation accord was sure to complicate already strained relations within the peacetime central government between rival Serb, Moslem and Croat leaders.</p>
<p>The joint institutions have been virtually paralysed since national elections were held last September.</p>
<p>Hajric said federation officials were reviewing the agreement, which called for the Serb entity and Yugoslavia to pursue common economic, foreign and legal policies and to grant citizens free movement across the common border.</p>
<p>Although the Dayton peace agreement allows Bosnian entities to forge relations with neighbouring states, the Serb pact could be premature as the new central government has yet to establish laws on citizenship, Hajric said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm reluctant to believe it is in line with state policy. The joint institutions are still discussing these measures and haven't even resolved policies on citizenship and passports,&quot; Hajric said.</p>
<p>Leaders of the Bosnian Serb republic have been eager to strengthen links with the Yugoslav republics of Serbia and Montenegro, which supported their rebellion against Bosnia's bid for independence.</p>
<p>A clause on defence said neither side would allow its territory to be used for aggression against the other. If one territory came under an attack, the two sides agreed to act to halt the aggression in accordance with the United Nations charter.</p>
<p>The office of the international High Representative to Bosnia said its lawyers were carefully studying the agreement and had yet to deliver a decision.</p>
<p>The High Represenative's office ruled earlier this month that Serb authorities could not authorise Krajisnik to sign international agreements solely on behalf of the Serb republic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
