<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412809" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Placer says Las Cristinas tenure secure.</title>
<headline>Placer says Las Cristinas tenure secure.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Placer Dome Inc on Friday dismissed market rumors that its tenure rights at the Las Cristinas gold deposits in Venezuela were not secure.</p>
<p>&quot;We have heard these stories before and they are without merit. We recently once again reviewed our position, and with the concurrence of our joint venturer Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana (CVG), concluded our ownership is safe and secure. Furthermore, we are not in any discussions with any party over ownership of Las Cristinas,&quot; Placer President John Willson said.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the rumors circulated in the market on Friday but doubted they were a significant influence on Placer's share price, which slipped 0.30 to 29.35 in Toronto.</p>
<p>But the talk buoyed the stock of junior miner Crystallex International Corp, which rose 1.05 to 4.15.</p>
<p>According to market rumors, a prior owner of Las Cristinas is seeking to challenge Placer's right to the property and Crystallex, which has operations nearby, has struck a deal to take over the property if the prior owner is successful, said one analyst who declined to be identified.  </p>
<p>Details were sketchy but the analyst said there were reports that the prior owner had lost a similar challenge in the Venezuelan courts in the 1980s.</p>
<p>Telephone calls to Crystallex's Vancouver headquarters office were not answered.</p>
<p>A Placer spokesman said Placer was awarded a contract for Las Cristinas by the Venezuelan government in 1991 and there were no liens or prior claims on the property. He declined to discuss the property's history before that time, saying the company did not want to feed market speculation.</p>
<p>Placer has 70 percent of the property and Venezuelan state-owned CVG the rest.</p>
<p>((Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
