<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412811" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Herbert Lanese on list for WMX CEO job.</title>
<headline>Herbert Lanese on list for WMX CEO job.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The board committee that is searching for a new WMX Technologies Inc chief executive is considering Herbert Lanese, former president of McDonnell Douglas Corp's aerospace division, as well as several other candidates, said director Peter Huizenga.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Lanese) certainly is on the list. His name has been suggested,&quot; Huizenga told Reuters Saturday in an interview.</p>
<p>Huizenga said several names were under consideration and that the committee has not set a decision deadline.</p>
<p>WMX began looking for a new CEO after the surprise resignation from that post February 18 of Phillip Rooney.</p>
<p>Rooney's ouster had been sought by major investors, including an investment group led by financier George Soros.</p>
<p>Lanese resigned in October from McDonnell Douglas, the St. Louis-based aircraft and aerospace concern that has since agreed to merge with Boeing Co.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Lanese was among four WMX board nominees proposed by the Soros group, which owns a 5.2-percent WMX stake and is pressuring the company to improve its performance. The Soros group said February 20 it would not pursue getting its slate elected after it said WMX pledged to bring two independent directors onto the board and to hire a top-quality chief executive.</p>
<p>((--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I92110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
