<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412892" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico attacks U.S. drug certification process.</title>
<headline>Mexico attacks U.S. drug certification process.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican lawmakers and officials on Friday snarled at Washington's decision to certify it as an ally in the drug war, saying the annual evaluation process was interventionist and unfair.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright ended an agonizing week for Mexico by announcing that -- contrary to some rumours -- Washington would grant Mexico certification despite a series of embarrassing drug corruption scandals.</p>
<p>More than three hours after the U.S. decision, the Mexican government had not issued a planned reaction statement and a promised news conference with Foreign Minister Jose Angel Gurria was cancelled.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want to give this too much prominence,&quot; one government official told Reuters. &quot;Independent of the actual decision, we insist that the process of certification is unilateral and interventionist and that it does not help promote cooperation between governments.&quot;</p>
<p>Augusto Gomez Villanueva, president of the congressional foreign relations committee, attacked certification as &quot;a smokescreen to hide that there are 40 million consumers of drugs in our neighbour to the North and that 80 percent of the money laundered in the world is washed there&quot;.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Zedillo made no mention of the topic in afternoon speeches and three senior officials at the presidency declined to take calls on the topic.</p>
<p>The official disdain for the certification decision belied the enormous importance of the topic to Mexico.</p>
<p>The presidency, the foreign ministry and the Mexican embassy in Washington spent the last few days in an effort to convince Americans of their achievements in the drug war.</p>
<p>In Mexico, normally unavailable officials offered interviews on the successes of Mexico's drug fight and traditionally hard-to-get narcotics war data was suddenly faxed to foreign correspondents in detail.</p>
<p>Mexican authorities announced the arrest of a top drug lord on Thursday night, the eve of the certification decision. They said Oscar Malherbe was running the Mexico Gulf drug cartel, one of the country's biggest, when he was detained.</p>
<p>Some Mexican newspapers reported that Malherbe had been under arrest for at least two days, suggesting that the announcement had been &quot;saved up&quot; for certification day.</p>
<p>It was later confirmed that he was arrested one day before the announcement.</p>
<p>Navy chiefs in the Yucatan peninsula, a key staging point in the smuggling of cocaine north to the United States, organised a burning of a big haul of drugs in front of invited reporters on Thursday.</p>
<p>But Mexican financial markets wobbled nastily in the past two days as rumours spread that Washington might this year for the first time deny Mexico its seal of drug approval.</p>
<p>On Thursday the peso tumbled by 2.2 percent against the dollar -- its biggest one-day fall since November 1995 -- and interest rates jumped as traders fretted about the possible economic impact of a decertification.</p>
<p>Finance minister Guillermo Ortiz gave a veiled warning that decertification of Mexico might affect the U.S.'s billions of dollars of investments in Mexico and hurt booming bilateral trade.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the peso fall was a decisive factor,&quot; one Mexican official told Reuters. &quot;The Americans just couldn't take the risk of doing anything which might blow the Mexican economy off course again just when it was recovering&quot;.</p>
<p>Mexico has just finished paying back $12.5 billion of U.S. emergency aid to bail it out after the economy almost collapsed in the wake of a December 1994 peso devaluation.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton was expected to visit in April and Mexican officials worried that a decertification would whip up anti-American feeling ahead of the visit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
