<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412803" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Liberia warlords hit election trail.</title>
<headline>Liberia warlords hit election trail.</headline>
<byline>Jackson Kanneh</byline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Liberia's three main warlords, whose rivalry helped fuel seven years of civil war, have resigned from the ruling council of state and hit the election trail with their eyes on winning presidency on May 30.</p>
<p>Faction leader Charles Taylor, the man who launched the war in 1989, Alhaji Kromah and George Boley all resigned late on Friday, ahead of a midnight deadline imposed under a peace plan brokered by Liberia's West African neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;The next three months will be the most difficult time in this republic and the democratic process must take shape and remain firm,&quot; Taylor told reporters, adding that he was coming round to the idea of U.N.-organised elections.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm beginning to think that the U.N. idea which I previously opposed on the issue of our sovereignty might have to be welcomed if elections are to be transparent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His remarks follow a dispute over the composition of an independent electoral commission, which is due to be installed on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We must have a neutral body that everyone can trust,&quot; Taylor said. &quot;I may just consider having the United Nations come in an take over these elections and declare the results.&quot;</p>
<p>Taylor and Kromah were allies against Boley and fellow Krahn faction leader Roosevelt Johnson in a bloody flare up in the civil war in the capital Monrovia last April and May.</p>
<p>All say they are committed to a peaceful solution to the conflict, which has killed well over 150,000 people and smashed the West African nation's iron ore, diamonds, rubber and timber producing economy.</p>
<p>&quot;We are leaving the transitonal government because we believe the people of Liberia want us to take the leadership of this country through the ballots, not bullets,&quot; Kromah said.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only will I support the peace process but I'm going to ensure that the process works,&quot; Boley said.</p>
<p>Johnson has said he plans to go into business.</p>
<p>Taylor, Kromah and Boley were vice-chairman on the ruling council. Each has nominated a replacement.</p>
<p>Taylor's National Patriotic Front of Liberia grouped descendents of freed American slaves, who set up Liberia in 1847, and some indigenous tribes.</p>
<p>The decendants of the slaves dominated the nation until a 1980 coup by Krahn Master Sergeant Samuel Doe altered the balance of power. Taylor invaded from Ivory Coast in 1989.</p>
<p>The Krahn and Kromah's Mandingo joined forces initially within ULIMO to oppose Taylor, whose attempts to take the capital were repeatedly frustrated by Nigerian-led West African peacekeepers. ULIMO split into Krhomah and Johnson factions.</p>
<p>Peacekeepers restored order after last year's flare-up in Monrovia, preparing the ground for the peace deal, which West African leaders brokered in Nigeria's capital Abuja in August. A dozen previous deals collapsed.</p>
<p>Liberia's faction fighters handed in weapons and demobilised in an operation that ended in early February. Peacekeeping force commander General Victor Malu has expressed satisfaction with the operation, saying it cleared the way for the elections.</p>
<p>Several ministers, senior civil servants and members of the transitional assembly also resigned their posts to contest seats in parliamentary polls, which also take place on May 30.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
