<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412880" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Castro puffs celebrated Cohiba with cigar buffs.</title>
<headline>Castro puffs celebrated Cohiba with cigar buffs.</headline>
<byline>Frances Kerry</byline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Amid fine wines and swirls of luxuriant smoke on Friday night, Fidel Castro joined more than 700 cigar aficionados at a gala dinner to celebrate the 30th anniversary of Cuba's most prestigious brand, the Cohiba.</p>
<p>The guests, including some 130 U.S. citizens, paid $500 a head for a black-tie dinner of turkey consomme, lobster and cigars at Havana's Tropicana nightclub.</p>
<p>Successful bidders paid a total of $232,000 for six cabinets of between 25 and 75 Cohibas, and a humidor signed by Castro. The proceeds went to Cuba's health service.</p>
<p>The Cuban president, a former cigar smoker who ordered the making of the Cohiba for his personal use three decades ago, appeared to a burst of camera flashes and sat at a front table at the open-air club where cabaret shows were famous before the 1959 revolution.</p>
<p>Castro, wearing his trademark olive green uniform, took the stage on several occasions, putting his more usual anti-capitalist rhetoric aside in a speech extolling Cuban cigars, and particularly Cohibas.</p>
<p>Castro, 70, said he gave up cigars a few years ago after almost 50 years of smoking them because, at the time authorities were running an anti-smoking campaign and he felt he had to set an example. &quot;But don't think I stopped dreaming of cigars,&quot; he said to applause.</p>
<p>Mindful of the U.S. contingent in the audience, he threw in some digs at the U.S. economic embargo on the island, which includes travel restrictions on U.S. citizens.</p>
<p>Even John F. Kennedy had to find a way round the embargo, the Cuban leader said.</p>
<p>The day before the late U.S. president signed the embargo into law in February 1962, Castro said, Kennedy was reputed to have asked an aide to scour Washington for Cuban cigars to ensure he was well stocked up.</p>
<p>&quot;(President Bill) Clinton also likes cigars. But Hillary (Rodham Clinton) won't let him smoke,&quot; Castro said to laughter.</p>
<p>Castro, one of the last remaining communist leaders, said he was astounded by the auction, calling it an &quot;unimaginable spectacle&quot; and saying he had until now only seen such events in films.</p>
<p>During the auction, a cabinet containing 90 Cohiba cigars with a painting by Ecuadorian artist Oswaldo Guayasamin, also autographed by Castro and by the artist, fetched $130,000.</p>
<p>Castro left before the cabaret show, at about midnight.</p>
<p>Guests included foreign cigar importers, keen smokers, business people and specialist journalists.</p>
<p>Absent were a clutch of Hollywood stars such as Jack Nicholson and Arnold Schwarzenegger, orginally billed by some foreign media as due to attend. Peter Weller, star of Robocop films, did attend. It was uncertain whether stars stayed away because of the U.S. travel restrictions.</p>
<p>John Kavulich, an American who heads a New York-based information center called the U.S.-Cuba Trade and Economic Council, told reporters 137 U.S. citizens attended the dinner. He said the majority of them came legally.</p>
<p>They were either on &quot;hosted&quot; trips that they did not pay for, or obtained licences to visit, for example as journalists with cigar magazines. But some U.S. guests shielded their faces from reporters as they arrived at the Tropicana.</p>
<p>Cigars are currently Cuba's fifth-largest export, earning it more than $100 million a year.</p>
<p>But the island is not yet satisfying world demand, estimated at some 120 million cigars a year. Cuba produced 70 million cigars last year and aims to boost output to 100 million this year, steadily increasing output to some 200 million units by the year 2000. This is up from a low of about 50 million cigars produced in 1993, when Cuba was suffering the worst of economic crisis caused by the demise of the former Soviet Union.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
