<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412832" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Nine reported dead in Albania clash, roads blocked.</title>
<headline>Nine reported dead in Albania clash, roads blocked.</headline>
<byline>Benet Koleka</byline>
<dateline>VLORE, Albania 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Protesters armed with pistols and rifles on Saturday appeared to take control of the Albanian town of Vlore where some nine people were killed in an overnight gun battle, while villagers blocked roads to the south.</p>
<p>In increasing signs of spreading rebellion, civilians on the road between the southern town of Vlore and Tirana threw up blockades and halted vehicles travelling between the two towns.</p>
<p>In Lushnje, 80 km (50 miles) south of Tirana, a reporter saw two army trucks on fire on the outskirts of the town. Residents said soldiers fled on seeing their blockade but the reports could not be independently confirmed.</p>
<p>A reporter in the southern town of Gjirokaster said roads had also been blocked there.</p>
<p>In Vlore, thousands of people armed with guns and rifles paraded through the town and gathered at the university where 42 students entered their 10th day on hunger strike in an anti-government protest sparked by the collapse of pyramid investment schemes in January.</p>
<p>Armed civilians had taken up position in the university building. Some young men shot into the air from moving cars.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been a macabre and tragic night...in Vlore,&quot; the town's hospital director Servet Kojdheli told reporters. &quot;I've never seen anything like this before in Albania.&quot;</p>
<p>Witnesses saw civilians carrying armfuls of weapons from a military arms depot on the outskirts of the Adriatic port. Arms where also seized from the local headquarters of the National Information Service, the secret police, also known as the Shik.</p>
<p>Albanian television quoted a Shik statement as saying six of its officers had been killed in the shooting, three from bullet wounds. Two died after being caught in a blaze at the headquarters and another was apparently beaten to death after being dragged out of the building by a mob.</p>
<p>Reporters who visited the town mortuary saw the bodies of four men, three of them protesters, Fatmir Tozaj, 34, Shkelqim Bogdani, 33, and 17-year-old Artur Zotaj, who had all been shot. The fourth appeared to be one of the police victims, 36-year-old Lek Coku.</p>
<p>About 30 people were injured in the violence. Six were in serious condition in hospital suffering from gunshot wounds.</p>
<p>&quot;Armed terrorist bands, with more than 27 cars and about 60 to 70 people, attacked the building of the Information Service... at about 9 p.m. (2000 GMT), without any warning, opening fire from four sides of the building with automatic arms and explosive grenades,&quot; the Shik said in a statement.</p>
<p>But witnesses in the town said the fierce clashes erupted after a Shik officer allegedly stabbed one man outside the university. He survived the attack.</p>
<p>Protesters then pursued the Shik officers to their headquarters where the shoot-out took place. The building was still smouldering on Saturday morning and had been ransacked.</p>
<p>Vlore residents observed a minute's silence for the three dead protesters, described by one protest leader Luftar Petoshati as martyrs of democracy.</p>
<p>Slogans in the town read: &quot;Vlore people do not recognise Berisha as President&quot; and &quot;We cut links with Berisha's state and communicate only with the Forum for Democracy&quot;.</p>
<p>The Forum, comprising 11 opposition parties, had been due to hold a rally at a soccer field outside Tirana city centre later on Saturday. But the Interior Ministry said it had informed the Forum that the rally had been cancelled because of the tense situation in the country.</p>
<p>Army trucks were seen at night entering the town but there was no sign of soldiers on the streets of the capital. Riot police trucks and vans were seen near the centre at dawn.</p>
<p>Parliament, consisting mainly of President Sali Berisha's right-wing Democrats, was due to meet in emergency session to discuss the Vlore crisis. Berisha was certain to be re-elected to a new five-year term as president on Monday in a parliamentary vote. No opposition party is contesting the poll.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VLORE, Albania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
