<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412868" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico drugs capo escapes, probe ordered.</title>
<headline>Mexico drugs capo escapes, probe ordered.</headline>
<byline>Martin Langfield</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top Mexican drug lord escaped from police custody just as the United States was deciding whether to certify if Mexico was cooperating in the fight against drugs, authorities said on Friday.</p>
<p>Humberto Garcia Abrego, who is accused of money-laundering and is the brother of jailed Mexico Gulf cartel chief Juan Garcia Abrego, walked out of installations of the National Institute for Combatting Drugs late on Thursday or early on Friday, the Attorney General's Office said in a statement.</p>
<p>The announcement was made on Friday evening, several hours after Washington certified that Mexico was cooperating as an ally in the war on drugs despite strong opposition from critics of Mexican corruption.</p>
<p>The Attorney General's Office statement said Garcia was initially legally released from custody on Tuesday night after winning a court order protecting him from illegal arrest, from a judge in Tamaulipas.</p>
<p>Authorities immediately took him back into custody, however, to answer a &quot;presentation order&quot; requiring him to testify about other outstanding money-laundering and criminal association charges.</p>
<p>&quot;Inexplicably, the official in charge of the investigation told his superiors that Humberto Garcia Abrego had 'gone from the National Institute for Combatting Drugs' before the investigation was completed,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The official in question and his colleagues -- who are now being interrogated -- had 48 hours to question Garcia from the time of his detention before having to release or arrest him, and by failing to do so allowed him to walk free.</p>
<p>Garcia's escape appeared to have coincided almost exactly with Mexico's announcement late on Thursday that it had arrested Oscar Malherbe de Leon, the acting leader of the Gulf drug cartel.</p>
<p>Malherbe's arrest -- announced more than 24 hours after he was seized, and just as Washington was in the final hours of deliberation on the certification issue -- won praise from the U.S. government and may have helped President Bill Clinton face down opponents of certifying Mexico.</p>
<p>Malherbe took over the Gulf cartel following the January 1996 arrest of its leader Juan Garcia Abrego, Humberto's brother.</p>
<p>Juan Garcia is now serving 11 life sentences without parole in the United States after being convicted in a Houston court of drug trafficking.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
