<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412826" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albanian government to quit after protest deaths.</title>
<headline>Albanian government to quit after protest deaths.</headline>
<byline>Paul Holmes</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's embattled President Sali Berisha bowed to pressure on Saturday for the resignation of his Democratic Party government after the bloodiest violence in two months of angry protests.</p>
<p>Berisha, speaking after up to nine people were reported killed in armed clashes in the southern port of Vlore, said the removal of Prime Minister Aleksander Meksi and his ministers had been agreed at talks with opposition leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;To resolve the problems that have been created the leaders of the political parties...came to the conclusion that the Meksi government will resign,&quot; Berisha told state television. &quot;Meksi himself said he considered it reasonable to quit without any (confidence) vote,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Berisha said his party, which holds virtually all the seats in parliament after disputed elections last year, could form a new cabinet but would consult broadly with opposition forces.</p>
<p>The surprise announcement was Berisha's first major concession in two months of mushrooming disorder in his impoverished former Stalinist state over the collapse of dubious &quot;get-rick-quick&quot; pyramid investment schemes.</p>
<p>Furious Albanians who had sunk their meagre life savings into the schemes have turned their wrath on Berisha and his right-wing party for failing to control the funds.</p>
<p>Violent protests shook the tiny Balkan state on Saturday after the Vlore deaths, the fiercest confrontation in Albania since 40 people died in food riots in 1991.</p>
<p>In Tirana, riot police were put to flight by stone-throwers in a crowd of some 5,000 demonstrators marching in defiance of a police ban to the city's university campus.</p>
<p>Witnesses said at least 10 police and protesters were injured in the clashes in the capital, ended when hundreds of riot police regrouped and broke up the gathering by force.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, scores of villagers erected road blocks at at least five places on the only road connecting Tirana with Vlore 150 km (95 miles) to the south, reporters said.</p>
<p>Protesters blocked the road outside southern Albania's main town, Gjirokaster, with a barrier of tree trunks and the Albanian news agency ATA said protests had also taken place in the textile town of Berat and the Adriatic port of Durres.</p>
<p>In Vlore, the hotbed of anti-government resentment and scene of a student hunger strike, townsfolk prepared to bury three civilians, one a boy aged 17, shot dead on Friday night in a gunfight between residents and the Shik secret police.</p>
<p>Reporters saw the three corpses and the body of a Shik police officer in the town mortuary. The Shik said five more of its men were killed but the corpses have not been seen.</p>
<p>Huge numbers of men and youths armed with pistols and rifles paraded in the town through the day after seizing arms at the Shik headquarters before the building was torched.</p>
<p>The latest violence prompted renewed calls for restraint from the international community, with Pope John Paul, France and the United States embassy in Tirana all urging dialogue.</p>
<p>Berisha, standing unopposed for re-election to a second five-year term in a parliamentary vote scheduled for Monday, had appeared determined to ride out the investment scheme crisis until his agreement that Meksi should go.</p>
<p>The opposition, grouped in the 11-party Forum for Democracy, had called for the government's ouster and wants a technocrat cabinet to run the country pending early elections.</p>
<p>The Meksi government won its second general election victory in June last year in polls boycotted by the main opposition parties, which accused the Democrats of fraud.</p>
<p>They won 122 of the chamber's 140 seats in a ballot whose conduct was criticised by foreign observers as inconsistent with international standards.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
