<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412838" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albanian prime minister resigns-state agency.</title>
<headline>Albanian prime minister resigns-state agency.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian President Sali Berisha accepted Prime Minister Aleksander Meksi's resignation on Saturday, the state-run news agency ATA said.</p>
<p>It quoted a presidential office statement as saying Berisha had asked him to stay on in a caretaker role until a successor was named following consultations among political parties. Berisha had announced earlier that Meksi would quit.  </p>
<p>The resignation of the Democratic Party government was agreed at talks with opposition leaders on the protests that have racked impoverished Albania since the collapse in January of dubious pyramid investment schemes.</p>
<p>Berisha's meeting with the opposition followed a gun battle between townspeople and the secret police overnight in the southern port of Vlore in which up to nine people were reported to have been killed.</p>
<p>Berisha told state television that Meksi's cabinet could be succeeded by another Democratic Party government after consultations with opposition forces.</p>
<p>His stance was swiftly rejected by the main opposition Socialist Party. One of its leaders, Namik Dokle, told Reuters the only way out of the crisis was to set up a technocrat government to run affairs until early elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
