<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412827" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania government to quit after popular protests.</title>
<headline>Albania government to quit after popular protests.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian President Sali Berisha said on Saturday Prime Minister Aleksander Meksi's government would resign after a wave of popular protests swept the country over the past two months.</p>
<p>Berisha made the surprise announcement after holding crisis talks with leaders of opposition political parties following 24 hours of violent clashes in the southern Adriatic port of Vlore and in the capital, Tirana.</p>
<p>&quot;To resolve the problems that have been created the leaders of the political parties...came to the conclusion that the Meksi government will resign,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Meksi himself said he considered it reasonable to quit without any (confidence) vote.&quot;</p>
<p>Nine people were reported killed and about 30 wounded in a gun battle in Vlore while at least 10 civilians and police were injured in a clash between protesters and riot police in Tirana.</p>
<p>Berisha, who is to seek a second five-year term in a parliamentary vote on Monday, met the opposition leaders to discuss the crisis racking the impoverished Balkan country since get-rick-quick pyramid investment schemes failed in January.</p>
<p>&quot;I suggested to the political parties, though no consensus was reached, to form an inter-party committee of experts to tackle the pyramid scheme problems and the consequences it triggered to provide ideas for a (future) government,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said his ruling Democratic Party could form a successor cabinet but would hold broad consultations with the opposition.</p>
<p>Albanians left penniless by the collapse of the savings schemes, which had soaked up their life savings, have turned their anger on the government, accusing Meksi and his ministers of failing to bring the funds under control.</p>
<p>Meksi's government won its second general election victory in June last year in controversial polls boycotted by the main opposition parties, which accused the Democrats of intimidation, widespread irregularities and ballot stuffing.</p>
<p>The Democrats won 122 seats in the 140-member parliament, reflecting an increase on the vote they received in a landslide victory against the Socialists in 1992.</p>
<p>They vigorously denied the opposition's charges but foreign observers, including the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe, described the conduct of the election as inconsistent with international standards.</p>
<p>Berisha appeared to have heeded appeals from Western governments, as well as a call from Pope John Paul, to open a dialogue across the political spectrum to solve the crisis.</p>
<p>The main Socialist Party, heirs to the former communists who ran a harsh Stalinist regime for 45 years until 1990, on Friday held their first face-to-face talks with the right-wing Democrats since the election but the two parties failed to find common ground to tackle the crisis.</p>
<p>But the Socialists' decision to meet the Democrats again on Saturday appeared to be a measure of their commitment to reintegrate themselves into the political life of the country.</p>
<p>The Socialists have so far refused to take up their seats in parliament but Meksi's resignation might persuade them to return to parliament for the first time in nine months.</p>
<p>Berisha was also likely to win back support from at least 13 of his deputies who called last week for Meksi to quit and is now even more certain to win Monday's presidential vote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
