<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412830" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania unrest spreads after nine reported killed.</title>
<headline>Albania unrest spreads after nine reported killed.</headline>
<byline>Benet Koleka</byline>
<dateline>VLORE, Albania 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania was racked by violent protests on Saturday as demonstrators clashed with riot police in Tirana hours after a fierce gun battle in the town of Vlore, where armed protesters appeared to have taken control.</p>
<p>Townsfolk prepared to bury three slain civilians in the southern Adriatic port of Vlore, where up to nine people were reported killed in an exchange of gunfire between civilians and the Shik secret police on Friday night..</p>
<p>Scores of villagers erected road blocks at at least five points on the only road connecting Tirana with Vlore 150 km (95 miles) to the south. Reporters saw a large crowd of people manning a barricade at the town of Lushnje where clashes erupted three weeks ago.</p>
<p>Protests excalated in the impoverished Balkan state in January after thousands of investors learnt they had probably lost all their cash in dubious pyramid savings schemes.</p>
<p>Furious Albanians have turned their wrath on President Sali Berisha and the ruling Democratic Party government for failing to control the investment funds.</p>
<p>In Tirana, some 5,000 demonstrators hurled stones at police and overturned police vehicles as they marched to the capital's university campus where they were joined by some students.</p>
<p>Riot police later withdrew as opposition party leaders attempted to persuade the protesters against moving towards central Skanderbeg Square.</p>
<p>The opposition Forum for Democracy earlier called off their planned rally in Tirana after the interior ministry withdrew permission, citing increased tension in the country.</p>
<p>France said it deplored the violence and urged all political parties to begin talks to end the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;The new outbreaks of violence show that the financial and political crisis that has gripped this country for the past several weeks is far from over,&quot; the foreign ministry said.</p>
<p>The United States embassy in Tirana, expressing its condolences to the victims and their families, called for restraint.</p>
<p>&quot;While the government has a special responsibility for ensuring civil liberties, all sides must show restraint in speech and action to lessen the potential for violence,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>In Vlore, townsfolk began funeral ceremonies for three civilians shot dead in gunfire on Friday night, the fiercest confrontation in Albania since 40 died in food riots in 1991.</p>
<p>Reporters saw the bodies of three protesters and one Shik secret police officer in the town mortuary. The Shik said five more of its men were killed but the corpses have not been seen.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been a macabre and tragic night...in Vlore,&quot; town hospital director Servet Kojdheli said. &quot;I've never seen anything like this before in Albania.&quot;</p>
<p>The coffin of Artur Zotaj, 17, was borne aloft by his friends the three km (two miles) to Vlore cemetery and mourners applauded as they passed.</p>
<p>All three coffins were placed first at the steps of the monument of independence where speeches and poems were read.</p>
<p>Some men bearing arms shot rounds in the air but one young speaker urged them to lay down their weapons.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't you think the blood we have shed is enough? I appeal to you that...the last round of shots be at the graveside.&quot;</p>
<p>The appeal appeared to fall on deaf ears. Huge numbers of men and youths armed with pistols and rifles have paraded through the town through the day. Weapons were seized at the Shik headquarters before the building was torched. Others were seen carrying armfuls of rifles from a military depot just outside the town.</p>
<p>Around 40 university students in Vlore, who entered their 10th day on hunger strike, have become a beacon for anti-government protest, and students and high school pupils in Tirana and the southern town of Gjirokaster have staged action in solidarity.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VLORE, Albania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
