<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412890" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Paranapanema protests Peru option loss.</title>
<headline>Paranapanema protests Peru option loss.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's Paranapanema has protested to Peruvian state mining firm Centromin the loss of an option to buy polymetallic miner Empresa Minera Yauliyacu.</p>
<p>&quot;We have presented a complaint to Centromin and we are going to follow an administrative course,&quot; Cesar Vabo, the Brazilian mining firm's local representative, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;If that is not successful, the company will have to take a legal path.&quot;  </p>
<p>Earlier this week, Centromin said Paranapanema had lost its option because it did not provide paperwork and the necessary guarantee, saying that the mine would now be awarded to local company Minera Casapalca S.A..</p>
<p>Paranapanema won the auction for Yauliyacu for $12.7 million last December. It also offered to invest $100 million over a five year period.</p>
<p>Centromin spokesman Enrique Olivares said Centromin would respond to the formal protest soon.  </p>
<p>But he added that Paranapanema failed to meet two deadlines for submitting necessary documents to Centromin's privatization committee (CEPRI).</p>
<p>As a result, &quot;the Cepri, acting within the established rules of the auction, simply revoked the granting of the option,&quot; Olivares said, adding the Cepri had described the Feb. 24 deadline as &quot;final and unpostponable.&quot;</p>
<p>Vabo said he visited Centromin on Friday to explain that Paranapanema had a check and letter of guarantee ready 10 days ago and that the check had been deposited in Peru's Banco de Credito.  </p>
<p>Paranapanema officials said earlier this week that the bank sent a letter to Centromin on Feb 24, saying that it had received the funds and a stand-by bank guarantee from Banco do Brasil.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made all efforts and fulfilled all conditions and we will take legal action for what we think are our rights,&quot; a company director, Antonio Miguel, said.</p>
<p>The Paranapanema group which was formed last year includes copper producer Caraiba Metais, zinc unit Companhia Paraibuna de Metais and tin producer Mamore (formerly known as Paranapanema).</p>
<p>According to Centromin, the Yauliyacu reserve has proven and probable reserves of silver, zinc, lead and copper totalling 7.3 million tonnes while the unit's potential reserves total 14.7 million tonnes.</p>
<p>In 1995, 746,000 tonnes of mineral were extracted from the site.</p>
<p>((--Eduardo Orozco, Lima newsroom 511 221 2130))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
