<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412808" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Liberia warlords resign to meet election deadline.</title>
<headline>Liberia warlords resign to meet election deadline.</headline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Faction leader Charles Taylor, the man who launched Liberia's civil war, resigned from the ruling state council on Friday so that he could stand in presidential elections on May 30, his radio station said.</p>
<p>Taylor, vice-chairman on the council, said earlier that he would resign ahead of the midnight Friday deadline imposed under a peace plan brokered by Liberia's neighbours to end seven years of war.</p>
<p>&quot;The next three months will be the most difficult time in this republic and the democratic process must take shape and remain firm,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Taylor's ethnic Krahn rival George Boley, of the Liberia Peace Council, told reporters that he too had quit the council of state. &quot;I have resigned,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The third main faction leader, Alhaji Kromah, told reporters earlier he would resign before the deadline expired.</p>
<p>Taylor and Kromah were allies against Boley and fellow Krahn Roosevelt Johnson in a bloody flare up in the civil war in the capital Monrovia last April and May.</p>
<p>West African peacekeepers restored order, preparing the ground for the peace deal, which was agreed in Nigeria's capital Abuja last August.</p>
<p>The commander of the Nigerian-led peacekeeping force, General Victor Malu, said more than two months of disarmament that ended in early February had laid the groundwork for elections.</p>
<p>Freed American slaves set up Liberia in 1847.</p>
<p>The war, which has killed well over 150,000 people, began in December 1989 with Taylor attempting to overthrow dictator Samuel Doe. Doe was captured and killed by another faction the following year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
