<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412836" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Three reported shot dead in Albania protest town.</title>
<headline>Three reported shot dead in Albania protest town.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three people were reported killed and at least 10 wounded on Friday when shooting broke out in the southern town of Vlore where demonstrators have staged anti-government protests for weeks.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear who started the shooting but one witness said the local headquarters of the secret police, known as the Shik, was set ablaze.</p>
<p>One of the dead was believed to be a secret police officer and the other two were a 34-year-old man and a 17-year-old. Two other secret police officers were in a critical condition.</p>
<p>According to a hospital official in Vlore, thousands of protesters swarmed into the streets after secret police units attempted to force a group of students on hunger strike for the past 10 days to vacate the university room they had occupied.</p>
<p>&quot;Three people were shot dead and 10 are wounded, four or five of them are in serious condition,&quot; the official told Reuters in Tirana by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;The Shik (secret police) wanted to get the hunger strikers out and they clashed with thousands of people who were there to protect the students,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>One other witness in the Adriatic port said outraged protesters stormed the secret police headquarters and dragged three officers out and took them to the university building.</p>
<p>A group of regular policemen were seen to be inside the university but students on hunger strike were not believed to have been affected by the violence.</p>
<p>The student hunger strikers have acted as a beacon for student protests and other demonstrations across the Balkan state.</p>
<p>Albania has been hit by a wave of violent protests in the past two months after thousands of people learnt they had lost all their savings in fraudulent pyramid investment schemes. They blame the government for failing to alert them to the dangers of the savings funds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
