<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412922" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Suharto urges Indonesians to vote - paper.</title>
<headline>Suharto urges Indonesians to vote - paper.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Suharto urged Indonesians to seize the opportunity to help determine the course of national development by voting in the May 29 general election, the Jakarta Post newspaper reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;The election gives people the chance to renew their representatives,&quot; he was quoted as saying in Boyolali, Central Java, on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;That's why it is imperative that the upcoming election must be held in the best possible way,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The paper said Suharto's remarks came amid a debate over whether or not Indonesians should be required to vote in the general election.</p>
<p>Many younger Indonesians are known to have refused to vote in past elections in protest against the policies of Suharto's government.</p>
<p>&quot;It's their own fault if they regret it later that they cannot influence the course of development,&quot; Suharto was quoted as saying. The paper gave no further details.</p>
<p>Suharto also said he was ready to step down if that was what people wanted, but warned that any moves to unseat him should be made only through the People's Consultative Assembly (MPR), which meets every five years solely to work with the House of Representatives to choose the president.</p>
<p>&quot;If the people want Suharto to step down, I'll say thank you,&quot; Suharto said. &quot;I'll accept the decision for the sake of the people and the constitution.</p>
<p>&quot;But if they do it (by means other than through the MPR)...I will clobber them because they are violating the constitution.&quot;</p>
<p>Suharto, 75, has not revealed whether he will step down after his sixth five-year term ends in March 1998. But the ruling Golkar party, of which he is leader, has begun pushing for him to stay in office another five years.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Yogie Suardi Memet said this week the country's six million civil servants were required to vote for Golkar.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
