<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412918" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China courts reject American's garbage appeal.</title>
<headline>China courts reject American's garbage appeal.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>An American businessman has lost his appeal against a 10-year jail sentence imposed by a Chinese court for illegally importing garbage into China, the Liberation Daily reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>William Ping Chen had appealed against the jail term and a fine of 500,000 yuan ($60,000) imposed by Shanghai Number One Intermediate Court last December for smuggling 238 tonnes of garbage and medical waste to Shanghai, it said.</p>
<p>The original court verdict also ordered Chen to be deported, but it was unclear when that was to take effect.</p>
<p>Born in Shanghai, Chen, 56, is a resident of Oakland, California.</p>
<p>Until his arrest last June he was president of Shanghai Tongyi Paper Co Ltd, which had been banned by the Chinese government from importing garbage, it said.</p>
<p>He had listed the imported material as waste paper and mixed paper and had gone ahead with the shipment despite warnings from Shanghai environmental officials and opposition from his Chinese joint-venture partners, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>It said Chen had based his appeal on a claim that he was not the shipper of the garbage and therefore could not be accused of smuggling it into China.</p>
<p>The Shanghai Higher People's Court rejected the claim and upheld the sentence, it said.</p>
<p>Chen's arrest was the climax of an emotional campaign by China, launched in mid-1996, against illegal shipments of U.S. garbage listed as waste paper for recycling but found to contain old clothes, rubber gloves and disposable syringes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
