<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412912" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodian ruling party accuses rival of interfering.</title>
<headline>Cambodian ruling party accuses rival of interfering.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The powerful Cambodian People's Party (CPP) has accused its main coalition government partner of trying to undermine it.</p>
<p>The CPP charge came in a statement received on Saturday that definitively rejected joining an alliance launched on Thursday between the royalist FUNCINPEC party and three other parties to pursue common ideals ahead of general elections next year.</p>
<p>The CPP of Second Prime Minister Hun Sen and FUNCINPEC, led by co-premier Prince Norodom Ranariddh, rule Cambodia together in a coalition government formed after U.N.-run general elections in 1993.</p>
<p>The CPP statement criticised Ranariddh for reportedly saying he wanted to meet CPP President Chea Sim and present him with the 14-point platform of the National United Front even though Hun Sen had already rejected an offer to join.</p>
<p>This was &quot;an act in order to destroy the internal affairs of the Cambodian People's Party&quot;, it said.</p>
<p>Analysts said Hun Sen might have believed Ranariddh was trying to woo Chea Sim and create a wedge in the CPP.</p>
<p>The statement reiterated the CPP would not join Ranariddh's National United Front and would not study its platform.</p>
<p>&quot;The Cambodian People's Party respects the rights of political parties but does not need advice from people who use demagogic tactics,&quot; said an unofficial translation of the statement.</p>
<p>The National United Front brings together FUNCINPEC, the officially unrecognised opposition Khmer Nation Party (KNP), a wing of the divided Buddhist Liberal Democratic Party and the Khmer Neutral Party.</p>
<p>The front faces a burgeoning alliance of small parties also gathering around the CPP.</p>
<p>Ties have worsened over Ranariddh's demand last year for a greater share of power to reflect his party's narrow 1993 election win and efforts to win the allegiance of thousands of defectors from the Khmer Rouge guerrilla group.</p>
<p>Analysts said the existence of the rival alliances was likely to exacerbate relations ahead of the local and general elections, due to take place in 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
