<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412950" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indofood sees 97 net exceeds 5 trln rph.</title>
<headline>Indofood sees 97 net exceeds 5 trln rph.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's largest noodle maker PT Indofood Sukses Makmur said on Saturday its 1997 consolidated net sales would exceed five trillion rupiah in line with its plan to acquire six companies controlled by tycoon Liem Sioe Liong.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result of these acquisitions and barring any unforseen circumstances, Indofood consolidated net sales will exceed five trillion rupiah in 1997,&quot; Indofood chief executive officer, Eva Riyanti Hutapea, said in a statement faxed to Reuters.  </p>
<p>&quot;Consolidated net profit after tax will increase over 45 percent. Earnings per share in 1997, on a fully diluted basis, will increase close to 20 percent,&quot; Hutapea said.</p>
<p>The acqusitions, announced last November, are subject to approval by shareholders who will meet on March 17. After the acquisitions are completed the company would focus on branded packed food and cooking oil. Indofood has said the acquisitions would cost an estimated 1.750 trillion rupiah, of which just over 70 percent would be financed by a rights issue and the rest through loans.</p>
<p>The companies to be acquired include PT Salim Ivomas, which owns palm oil plantations, PT Intiboga Sejahtera, which produces cooking oil and fats, and palm oil trader PT Salim Oil Grains. Indofood gave no further details. ($1 = 2,400 rupiah) -- Jakarta Newsroom + 6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
