<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412920" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Philippines to go without IMF guidance - minister.</title>
<headline>Philippines to go without IMF guidance - minister.</headline>
<dateline>PHUKET, Thailand 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine Finance Minister Roberto de Ocampo said on Saturday the Philippines would meet obligations to help end 34 years of International Monetary Fund guidance of its economy this year.</p>
<p>De Ocampo told Reuters Financial Television he expected the Philippine parliament to pass domestic tax restructuring laws as recommended by the IMF by May 1 and achieve other 1997 economic targets set in the IMF's three-year Extended Fund Facility programme.  </p>
<p>The Philippines hopes to graduate from the IMF in late June under this programme, its 22nd, after 34 years of IMF involvement. The programme sets out a series of reforms and economic targets to wean the Philippines away from its dependence on foreign assistance.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now I find it has minimal risk because the IMF team has just left Manila about a week ago. And by their own review, we either have met or exceeded every important economic target that we set out in our Expanded Fund Facility programme,&quot; said de Ocampo, who is here attending the first finance ministers' meeting of the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN).</p>
<p>&quot;The only remaining issue is the passage of the comprehensive tax reform programme on elements of individual and corporate tax systems as well as the strengthening of administrative and enforcement provisions...at this point I am optimistic,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The minister said the Philippine parliament had approved the most contentious elements of the reforms, on tobacco and alcoholic excise taxes, and remaining issues are non-controversial nor prone to intense lobbying.</p>
<p>Philippine central bank officials said earlier that gross domestic product growth was expected to rise to just above six percent in 1997 against 5.5 in 1996, while inflation would be restrained at about six to seven percent this year against 8.4 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>De Ocampo said he sees a wider-than-expected trade deficit this year partly due to a one-time purchase of aircraft by Philippines Airlines but added that he is confident the 1997 deficit would be well within levels experienced by countries enjoying bullish economies.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHUKET, Thailand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
