<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412924" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Central bank backs Finance One, Thai Danu merger.</title>
<headline>Central bank backs Finance One, Thai Danu merger.</headline>
<dateline>PHUKET, Thailand 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Thailand governor Rerngchai Marakanond said on Saturday the central bank agreed with the planned merger between Finance One Plc and Thai Danu Bank Plc.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been informed verbally of Finance One and Thai Danu merger and I am waiting to hear their final agreement,&quot; Rerngchai told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally agree with the move which is basically a normal commercial merger designed for strengthening their business and efficiency as well as for trimming their expenses,&quot; the governor said.</p>
<p>He was in Phuket attending a one-day meeting of finance ministers from the seven-member Association of South East Asian Nations.</p>
<p>Earlier on Saturday, finance ministry sources and local newspapers said Finance One and medium-sized Thai Danu had agreed to merge. Finance One is Thailand's largest finance company.</p>
<p>Details of the proposed merger, the biggest shake-up in the domestic financial sector in more than a decade, would likely be announced on Monday and take time to be completed, they added.  </p>
<p>Rerngchai also dismissed speculation that Finance One faced financial problems, which some analysts say has prompted it to merge with Thai Danu.</p>
<p>&quot;We must distinguish the fact that Finance One has not faced any problems, although maybe some of its affiliates may have some short-term liquidity problems which have been taken care of by the central bank,&quot; Rerngchai said.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, rumours circulated that Finance One had faced a run on deposits from major clients and has had to pay high premiums to secure funds.</p>
<p>The company denied the rumours on Friday.</p>
<p>Suspicions about Finance One's health triggered heavy selloff of finance stocks this past week and helped pull down the overall market, brokers said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHUKET, Thailand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
