<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412967" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Arafat and Mubarak hold talks on Jerusalem.</title>
<headline>Arafat and Mubarak hold talks on Jerusalem.</headline>
<byline>Miral Fahmy</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat held talks in Cairo on Saturday with Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak on Israel's decision to build a Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Israel's approval last week of a plan to build 6,500 houses in Jabal Abu Ghneim, or Har Homa, has sparked criticism from its key ally the United States and Palestinian warnings that it could unleash bloodshed.</p>
<p>Official sources said Arafat and Mubarak, who consult regularly on the Middle East peace process, met at the Ittihadiya palace in Cairo. Arafat is expected to fly on to Washington for a meeting with President Bill Clinton on Monday.</p>
<p>Palestinian aides said Israel's settlement plan was expected to top Arafat's agenda at talks with Mubarak and Clinton.</p>
<p>Mubarak said on Thursday that Israel's decision to build the homes for Jews in Arab East Jerusalem could worsen the already tense situation in the occupied territories.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is dangerous and I warn of a deterioration of this situation and of increased difficulties for the peace process,&quot; Mubarak said.</p>
<p>The Egyptian leader said he told Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu in a telephone conversation on Wednesday not to take any decision about Jerusalem without first consulting Palestinians. He is expected to meet Netanyahu next week.</p>
<p>The Palestinian cabinet warned that the Israeli plan could threaten Middle East peace.</p>
<p>&quot;The peace process cannot go on under the continuation of this settlement assault which aims to swallow Jerusalem,&quot; the cabinet said in a statement issued on Saturday.</p>
<p>It issued an appeal to world leaders to oppose the Israeli project they fear blocks Palestinian aspirations to turn East Jerusalem into the capital of a future state. In the 1993 Oslo accords Israel and the PLO agreed to discuss the final status of the city at peace talks, slated to end by 1999.</p>
<p>Palestinians have held a series of demonstrations at the pine-covered Jabal Abu Ghneim, known by Israelis as Har Homa, where Israel decided to build 6,500 homes for Jews.</p>
<p>Israel captured East Jerusalem in the 1967 Middle East war and regards all of the city as its eternal capital, a view unrecognised by the international community.</p>
<p>Arafat on Thursday attacked Israel's decision as a breach of peace agreements, but he heeded U.S. warnings to keep the lid on violent protests.</p>
<p>The Cairo-based Arab League said it would hold an emergency meeting of its permanent representatives to discuss the plan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
