<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412926" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Berjaya sells Pantai stake.</title>
<headline>Berjaya sells Pantai stake.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's diversified Berjaya Group announced on Saturday that it had sold its entire 35.53 percent stake in Hospital Pantai Bhd to Tongkah Holdings chief executive Mokhzani Mahathir.</p>
<p>Berjaya said the 22.272 million shares were sold at 13.75 ringgit a share for a total 306.3 million ringgit.  </p>
<p>Berjaya said the sale to Mokhzani, who is also Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad's son, was effected through its subsidiaries, Berjaya Leisure Bhd and Berjaya Capital Bhd.</p>
<p>Berjaya also said a total of 11.678 million nominal amount of 5 percent irredeemable convertible loan stocks (ICULS) would be placed out to Kestrel Securities Sdn Bhd. The stock, priced at 4.38 ringgit each, would raise 51.15 million ringgit.</p>
<p>In all, Berjaya said it would realise a total of 357.4 million ringgit at group level and an extraordinary gain of 162.1 million ringgit at the company level.</p>
<p>Berjaya said in the 20 months it had run Hospital Pantai the medical group's market capitalisation grew four-fold to 850.5 million ringgit.</p>
<p>It said Tongkah had a 21 percent stake of its own in Hospital Pantai and Mokhzani would buy another 3.65 percent in the medical group from Berjaya General Insurance Sdn Bhd and Prime Credit Leasing, both subsidiaries of Berjaya Capital.  </p>
<p>Following the acquisitions, Mokhzani would be obliged to undertake a general offer for all remaining shares in Hospital Pantai, Berjaya said.</p>
<p>It said the share price of 13.75 ringgit represented a premium of 7.42 percent over the average weighted price and 2.61 percent over the closing price of 13.40 ringgit on February 27.</p>
<p>The placement price of 4.38 ringgit for each ICULS represented a premium of 2.8 percent over the average weighted price, but was a discount of 0.45 percent over the closing price.</p>
<p>Berjaya Leisure will realise a total of 180.61 million ringgit from the sale. ($1 = 2.48 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
