<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412909" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia Sime buys Thai Morakot.</title>
<headline>Malaysia Sime buys Thai Morakot.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian conglomerate Sime Darby Bhd has bought a 50.6 percent stake in Thailand's Morakot Industries PLC for around 76 million ringgit, the national Bernama news agency reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>The acquisition was an important part of Sime's strategy to increase its investments and presence in Thailand, and subsequently into Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos and Burma, Sime group chief executive Nik Mohamed Yaacob was quoted as saying by Bernama.</p>
<p>Morakot is a leading manufacturer of cooking oil in Thailand and commands more than 30 percent market share of the estimated 5.0 billion baht or 500 million ringgit cooking oil market in Thailand.</p>
<p>Plans are underway for Morakot to diversify into soft oils and construction has commenced on a crushing and refining plant for soya bean and sunflower seeds, Sime said.</p>
<p>Sime said it presently runs a subsidiary, Mecomb (Thailand) Ltd, which is licenced to trade and distribute most manufactured products.</p>
<p>The geographical scope of Sime's plantations activities complements the wide range of products distributed by Mecomb (Thailand) Ltd., and makes Malaysian group's presence in Thailand meaningful, said the statement.</p>
<p>It said Sime has become a significant palm oil producer and downstream player, managing over 99,500 hectares of palm oil, rubber and fruit crop plantations in Malaysia and West Kalimantan, Indonesia.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-2307509)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
