<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412946" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan-China trade rises 5.8 pct in 1996.</title>
<headline>Taiwan-China trade rises 5.8 pct in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's trade with China grew only 5.8 percent to US$22.208 billion in 1996, the Board of Foreign Trade said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The trade growth was the lowest in recent years, it said.</p>
<p>Taiwan's exports to China rose 7.0 percent last year to $19.148 billion from 1995, while imports edged down 1.0 percent to $3.06 billion, the board said in a statement.</p>
<p>The board attributed the sluggish growth to China's poorly performing export sector in 1996, which helped curb demand for Taiwan processing materials.</p>
<p>The upgrading of China capacity for self-supply of parts and components also played a role in slowing Taiwan exports to the mainland, it said.</p>
<p>The persistent move offshore of production capacity by Taiwan firms helped the island's imports from China to decline slightly, the board said.</p>
<p>The board also attributed the slower trade to tensions between the two sides in the first half of last year.</p>
<p>In December alone, two-way trade rose 26.5 percent to $2.33 billion from a year earlier, with exports to China up 27.4 percent to $2.063 billion and imports up 19.7 percent to $267 million, it said.  </p>
<p>In 1996, Taiwan enjoyed a trade surplus of $16.088 billion with China, up a year-on-year 8.7 percent, it said.</p>
<p>Beijing, which has considered Taiwan a renegade province since the Chinese civil war separated them in 1949, held war games in the Taiwan Strait ahead of the island's presidential election in March 1996, to warn voters not to drop the pledge to reunify with China.</p>
<p>Officials have said the war games made Taiwan people less willing to invest in the mainland.</p>
<p>Taiwan bans direct contact with China. All trade with China must be conducted through a third region, usually Hong Kong. Some 30,000 Taiwan firms have invested more than $20 billion in China.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (2-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
