<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412966" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran says quake kills 350, injures 1,600.</title>
<headline>Iran says quake kills 350, injures 1,600.</headline>
<byline>Sharif Imam-Jomeh</byline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rescue teams struggled in freezing winter temperatures on Saturday to save victims of an earthquake that left more than 350 dead and 1,600 injured in northwestern Iran.</p>
<p>The earthquake, measuring 5.5 on the Richter scale, hit the city of Ardabil and the town of Meshkinshahr at 4.27 p.m. (1257 GMT) on Friday, causing heavy damage to some 110 neighbouring villages, the Iranian news agency IRNA said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Iranian state television said the earthquake claimed at least 350 lives and injured 1,600. But relief officials said they feared the toll in the mountainous region could rise when rescue teams arrived on foot in villages cut off by the earthquake.</p>
<p>&quot;Most probably there are more bodies there lying beneath the rubble,&quot; a local Red Crescent official told Reuters. &quot;They could not reach them by car so they had to walk all night until they got there today (Saturday).&quot;</p>
<p>Relief workers set up 2,500 tents to shelter thousands of families made homeless and distributed blankets, food, heaters and lanterns, IRNA added.</p>
<p>State-run Tehran radio said local authorities called for three days of mourning in the province of Ardabil and urged Iranians to donate money to help buy relief supplies.</p>
<p>Ardabil is an agricultural province inhabited mainly by Iran's Azeri minority. It is one of Iran's coldest regions, with freezing temperatures during the winter. Tehran Radio said snow in mountaineous areas was hampering rescue operations.</p>
<p>Doctors in Ardabil said hospitals and clinics were swamped with victims, forcing many patients to seek medical care in nearby areas. Aftershocks continued to shake the region.</p>
<p>&quot;My family and I could not sleep last night because of the aftershocks,&quot; one resident told Reuters by telephone. &quot;And we could not go outside to sleep because it was too cold with temperatures just below freezing.&quot;</p>
<p>The tremor hit the Ardabil area some 16 hours after a strong earthquake killed nearly 50 people in and around the town of Quetta in Pakistan's Baluchistan province across Iran's southeastern border.</p>
<p>A Pakistani government seismic centre in the northwestern town of Peshawar measured that earthquake at 6.2 on the Richter scale.</p>
<p>IRNA earlier said a quake also measuring 5.5 on the Richter scale hit the western Iranian city of Sanandaj at about the same time as the tremor hit Ardabil, some 350 km (220 miles) away.</p>
<p>There were no casualties or damage in Sanandaj, a Kurdish-populated provincial capital, it said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Iran's northern province of Gilan on the Caspian Sea was also shaken by a tremor measuring about four on the Richter scale, but there was no damage, IRNA added.</p>
<p>Force four and five tremors are powerful enough to cause heavy damage in populated areas.</p>
<p>In early February, two earthquakes measuring 6.1 and 5.4 on the Richter scale killed at least 79 people and injured 260 in a mountainous region in northeastern Iran.</p>
<p>Earthquakes hit Iran regularly. The worst recorded one, measuring 7.3 on the Richter scale, killed 35,000 people in Gilan and neighbouring Zanjan province in 1990.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
