<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412919" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Anti-Japanese protesters rally in Seoul.</title>
<headline>Anti-Japanese protesters rally in Seoul.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>About 500 South Korean protesters gathered in Seoul on Saturday to demand that Tokyo pay compensation to victims of Japan's World War Two atrocities, witnesses said.</p>
<p>&quot;Compensate for 'comfort women',&quot; angry protesters shouted.</p>
<p>South Koreans have demanded that Japan compensate women, known euphemistically as &quot;comfort women&quot;, whom it forced into prostitution during World War Two.</p>
<p>Historians say as many as 200,000 women, many of them Korean, were rounded up and forced to serve as wartime sex slaves for the Japanese Imperial Army.</p>
<p>Japan has maintained that the issue was settled in post-war treaties.</p>
<p>Saturday's rally at a park in central Seoul marked the 78th anniversary of the March 1, 1919 Independence Movement against Japanese colonial rule in Korea.</p>
<p>Japan's 1910-1945 colonisation of the peninsula has left deep scars in the relationship between the two peoples.</p>
<p>The Seoul protesters also waved pickets and banners that read &quot;Stop claiming sovereignty of Tokto&quot; and &quot;Stop distorting history&quot;.</p>
<p>The two small Sea of Japan islets known as Tokto in Korea and Takeshima in Japan are at the centre of a territorial dispute that also has inflamed anti-Japanese opinion in South Korea.</p>
<p>Riot police confronted protesters as they tried to march towards the Japanese embassy, but there were no reports of violence.</p>
<p>Several protesters managed to reach the mission, where they hung a large white cloth bearing anti-Japanese slogans on the embassy gate. The cloth was quickly removed by police.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
