<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412927" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Deng already a fading image as China moves on.</title>
<headline>Deng already a fading image as China moves on.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>They bowed their heads, marked a scant 30 seconds of silence, then got right down to business.</p>
<p>With a quick tribute to the man who transformed the most populous nation on earth, China's parliament swept into the post-Deng Xiaoping era on Saturday with scarcely a backward glance.</p>
<p>Deng, who died on February 19 after ruling China for close to two decades, was a definite presence at the Great Hall of the People on Saturday -- but a presence that already seemed to be fading.</p>
<p>In the same vaulting auditorium where earlier in the week China's leaders choked back tears at memorial rites over Deng's ashes, legislators opened parliament's annual session with a &quot;moment of silence&quot; that seemed over almost before it began.</p>
<p>&quot;The passing away of Deng Xiaoping has been an immeasurable loss,&quot; parliamentary chief Qiao Shi said in his remarks calling the meeting to order. &quot;We must turn grief into strength.&quot;</p>
<p>Most legislators seemed to do just that. Pencils flew into action as Premier Li Peng's work report plunged into a thicket of statistics, strategy proposals and progress assessments.</p>
<p>Deng's name surfaced occasionally as the inspiration for China's market reforms and its coming resumption of control over Hong Kong, but Li's brief nods to the man who built modern China seemed more politesse than policy.</p>
<p>To be fair to Li, he did wrap up with a paragraph of praise for the former patriarch, saying China's job now was &quot;to further the great cause initiated by Comrade Deng Xiaoping&quot;.</p>
<p>And to be fair to the legislators, it is true that Deng hadn't put in a personal appearance in parliament for years, sidelined by deteriorating health before his death at 92 from Parkinson's disease and a lung infection.</p>
<p>But the parliament did not seem to be alone as it began to leave the &quot;chief architect&quot; behind.</p>
<p>While Hong Kong news reports said China's propaganda chiefs have ordered newspapers to stick to the black mastheads of mourning at least until the end of the legislative session in mid-March, the slew of Deng articles that followed his death was drying up.</p>
<p>State television news broadcasts, which during the six-day official mourning period were full of sobbing testimonies to Deng's leadership, are reverting to their normal fare of reports on the interminable meetings of China's bureaucracy.</p>
<p>China's ease with putting the Deng era to rest might well have pleased Deng himself, who abhorred the personality cult that surrounded his powerful predecessor, Chairman Mao Zedong.</p>
<p>Mao's body still lies embalmed in Beijing's Tiananmen Square, a morbid memento of China's history of fanatical hero worship. Deng's ashes, by contrast, seemed to have disappeared -- although officials say they will be thrown into the sea in accordance with his last wishes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
