<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412978" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Gaza students demand passage to West Bank.</title>
<headline>Gaza students demand passage to West Bank.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian students from the Gaza Strip called on Israel on Saturday to permit them passage across the Jewish state to their West Bank universities.</p>
<p>A statement issued by the West Bank's Bir Zeit University said Israel was preventing 1,300 Gaza students from travelling through Israel to the West Bank under restrictions tightened since a series of Palestinian bombs in Israeli cities a year ago.</p>
<p>Spokesman Shlomo Dror, from the office of Israel's coordinator of policy in the occupied territories, said the students pose a &quot;security risk.&quot;</p>
<p>He said violent confrontations between Israelis and Palestinians last September that left 76 people dead started with student protests at Bir Zeit.</p>
<p>&quot;Many students participated in terrorism and violence and we have reached the conclusion for security reasons the Gaza students should stay in Gaza,&quot; Dror said.</p>
<p>He added anti-Israeli material had been found at universities.</p>
<p>The Palestinian human rights group al-Haq said in a separate statement the Israeli restrictions violated international law as well as Palestinian-Israeli peace agreements. It called for an international campaign against the Israeli policy.</p>
<p>Dror said Israel was examining the restrictions and &quot;thinking how to ease the conditions.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
