<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412939" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan central bank warns caution on stock rally.</title>
<headline>Taiwan central bank warns caution on stock rally.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's Central Bank Deputy Governor Hsu Chia-tung said on Saturday individual investors, especially those using margin loans in trading, should exercise caution following recent stock market rallies.  </p>
<p>&quot;Individual investors, especially those using margin loans in trading, should 'think about danger when reaching highs',&quot; Hsu told journalsts when replying questions about his comments. He was speaking after the stock market closed 1.38 percent higher on Saturday at a six-year high.</p>
<p>The index ended up 108.39 points to 7,983.71, off an intraday high of 8,000.32.</p>
<p>It was the market's highest close since it ended at 8,059.14 on May 16, 1990.  </p>
<p>Hsu declined to directly say whether the central bank will adjust its monetary policy due to the market's rally.</p>
<p>&quot;We will review our monetary policy according to the consumer price situation, financial stability and the condition of the economic recovery,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hsu said inflation has so far remained under control, while there are &quot;mixed viewpoints on how well the domestic economy is recovering.&quot;</p>
<p>Taiwan's consumer price index rose 1.96 percent year-on-year in January.  </p>
<p>The central bank has forecast 1997 CPI growth of 3.31 percent year-on-year, while the cabinet's Council for Economic Planning and Development has set a 1997 CPI target of 3.0 percent.</p>
<p>The island's gross domestic product rose 6.62 percent year-on-year in the fourth quarter of 1996. This showed a gradual recovery compared with GDP growth of 5.12, 5.42 and 5.61 percent, respectively, in the first, second and third quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
