<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412917" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China to invest US$12 bln to boost car industry.</title>
<headline>China to invest US$12 bln to boost car industry.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>China will invest RMB 100 billion (US$12 billion) in the next five years in eight major car-making enterprises specialising in sedans and mini-cars, the China News Service said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim is the development of the automobile sector into a major industry by the early 21st century with an annual output in excess of RMB 1,000 billion (US$120 billion),&quot; a news release issued by the Beijing-funded China News Service said.  </p>
<p>Quoting a source from the State Planning Commission, the China News Service said China intends to produce 2.7 million vehicles and nine million motorcycles &quot;to shrug off over-reliance on imported cars and parts, the result of China's lack of research and development in this sector.&quot;</p>
<p>This will account for a 1.8-percent share of gross domestic product by year 2000 and an increase in the number of key car manufacturers with a production capability in excess of 400,000 vehicles annually, the source told CNS.  </p>
<p>By 2010, the source said the value of China's automobile output will increase to three percent of GDP from about one million vehicles produced by three or four major car builders.</p>
<p>&quot;The ability to develop new models to compete with the foreign brands at international level wil also contribute to this figure,&quot; CNS said.</p>
<p>Among the eight enterprises to benefit from the US$12 billion in financial support are Shanghai Volkswagen Auto Company, a unit of Volkwagen AG, the No.1 Auto Group's Volkswagen Automobile Plant and the Shenlong Automobile Plant in Wuhan, all of whom specialise in the production of sedans.</p>
<p>Beijing Jeep, Tianjin Daihatsu and Guangzhou Peugeot will also receive some of the financial support, as will the Chang an Automobile Plant in Chongqing and the Yunque Automobile Plant in Guizhou, both of which were converted from military industry to minicar manufacturing plants.</p>
<p>Starting this year, the state authorities will no longer endorse the establishment of new light vehicle and sedan automobile plants. The eight car manufacturers will be encouraged to merge, takeover or hold shares in these companies to cover wider areas and a larger market. To do this, they will be entitled to tax exemptions, concessions and special loans.  </p>
<p>&quot;They will, however, still be encouraged to introduce foreign capital to speed up the production of completed cars and components as well as spare parts,&quot; the news release said.</p>
<p>State support will also be given to four light vehicle manufacturers, namely the No.1 Light Trucks Plant, Nanjing Automobile Plant, Beijing Light Vehicles Company and Jiangling Automobile Plant, to enable them to produce an annual volume of 100,000 light vehicles, CNS said.</p>
<p>The release said that industry experts expect China to reach production of three million vehicles a year if it carries through with plans to build large automobile enterprise groups.</p>
<p>To achieve its strategic goals, the State Planning Commission source told CNS that the State will provide active financial support for major car manufacturers to boost further development; place a strong emphasis on development abilities when potential manufacturing projects are approved; establish and develop a number of sizeable car manufacturers through healthy competition and appropriate government support; intensively develop the spare part and accessory manufacturing industry, and, explore new markets both at home and abroad.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
