<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412930" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK's Tung plans a U.S. roadshow before handover.</title>
<headline>HK's Tung plans a U.S. roadshow before handover.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's future leader Tung Chee-hwa plans to visit the United States ahead of the territory's reversion to China on July 1 to soothe fears for civil liberties under his rule.</p>
<p>News of the roadshow follows Tung's recent criticism of Hong Kong's outspoken Democratic Party leader Martin Lee, whom he accused of spreading &quot;gloom and doom&quot; abroad about the territory's future.</p>
<p>Tung, a former shipping magnate chosen by a China-appointed caucus to rule Hong Kong after the British colonial governor leaves, would use the visit &quot;to tell the Hong Kong story&quot;, Stanley Shen, a spokesman for Tung's office, said by telephone.</p>
<p>Shen gave no details of the trip, which would be Tung's first outside China since being named last December, nor did he say who Tung would meet during the visit.</p>
<p>Tung, 59, said at a business dinner on Friday that he was unhappy with some individuals for painting a negative image of Hong Kong's future under Chinese rule.</p>
<p>&quot;There were rumours recently about Hong Kong that have created a poor image about the territory,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tung, who will have the title of chief executive of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of China, was also critical of Western media for, in his view, mispresenting Hong Kong overseas on issues such as human rights.</p>
<p>He was taking aim at recent reports on China's plan to amend some parts of the territory's laws, including those dealing with civil liberties.</p>
<p>During an interview with Cable News Network which aired on Friday night, he said bread-and-butter issues were of more concern to the territory's 6.4 million people than political liberties.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a spiralling cost of housing... mismatch of skills, education... these are the real problems which people care about,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
