<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412902" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran says quake kills at least 200, injures 1,000.</title>
<headline>Iran says quake kills at least 200, injures 1,000.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 200 people were killed and 1,000 injured by an earthquake that hit northwestern Iran on Friday, Iranian state television reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>The earthquake, measuring 5.5 on the Richter scale, hit the city of Ardabil and the town of Meshkinshahr at 4.27 p.m. (1257 GMT) on Friday, causing heavy damage to 52 neighbouring villages, the Iranian state news agency IRNA quoted the television as saying.</p>
<p>It said rescue operations were continuing in the stricken areas near Iran's border with Azerbaijan.</p>
<p>Iranian television, monitored by the British Broadcasting Corporation, had said late on Friday 100 people were killed and 250 were injured in the quake that lasted 30 seconds.</p>
<p>Ardabil is an agricultural province inhabited mainly by Iran's Azeri minority. It is one of Iran's coldests regions, with regularly freezing temperatures during the winter.</p>
<p>The tremor hit the Ardabil area some 16 hours after a strong earthquake killed nearly 50 people in and around the town of Quetta in Pakistan's Baluchistan province across Iran's southeastern border.</p>
<p>A Pakistani government seismic centre in the northwestern town of Peshawar measured that earthquake at 6.2 on the Richter scale.</p>
<p>IRNA earlier said a quake also measuring 5.5 on the Richter scale hit the western Iranian city of Sanandaj at about the same time as the tremor hit Ardabil, some 350 km (220 miles) away.</p>
<p>There were no immediate reports of casualties or damage in Sanandaj, a Kurdish-populated provincial capital, it said.</p>
<p>Iran's northern province of Gilan on the Caspian Sea coast was also shaken by a tremor measuring about four on the Richter scale, but there was no damage, IRNA added.</p>
<p>Force four and five tremors are powerful enough to cause heavy damage in populated areas.</p>
<p>In early February, two earthquakes measuring 6.1 and 5.4 on the Richter scale killed at least 79 people and injured 260 in a mountainous region in northeastern Iran.</p>
<p>Earthquakes hit Iran regularly. The worst recorded one, measuring 7.3 on the Richter scale, killed 35,000 people in Gilan and neighbouring Zanjan province in 1990.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
