<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412953" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea's Kim maintains hardline against North.</title>
<headline>S.Korea's Kim maintains hardline against North.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean President Kim Young-sam on Saturday maintained his hardline stance toward rival North Korea, emphasising the South's need for a &quot;complete and perfect&quot; national security regime.</p>
<p>&quot;No one can predict when an eventuality may develop on the Korean peninsula. If peace on the peninsula is broken once again, it would bring an enormous disaster that would be hard to bear,&quot; Kim said in a live televised speech at a ceremony marking Independence Movement Day.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to preclude such a national calamity, we must build up and maintain a national security posture that is complete and perfect,&quot; Kim said.</p>
<p>South and North Korea remain technically at war after the 1950-53 Korean War ended without a formal peace treaty.</p>
<p>On Saturday South Korea marked the 78th anniversary of a civil uprising in March 1919 to demand an end to Japanese colonial rule which did not come until August 1945.</p>
<p>&quot;Once again I call upon the North Korean authorities to discard confrontation and, instead, follow the path to reconciliation and cooperation. Doing so is the only way to extract itself from its difficulties,&quot; Kim said.</p>
<p>Communist North Korea has been on the brink of famine after severe floods in the past two years devastated croplands in a nation already suffering from chronic food shortages.</p>
<p>Kim's remarks came as South Korean and Chinese diplomats were working to break a deadlock over the fate of Hwang Jang-yop, the most senior North Korean official ever to flee North Korea. Hwang has sought shelter in Seoul's embassy in Beijing.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the embassy on Friday said no progress had been achieved in the talks to bring Hwang, Pyongyang's top theoretician, to Seoul.</p>
<p>Hwang walked into Seoul's mission in Beijing on February 12 and has been there ever since, surrounded by a Chinese security cordon of police with assault rifles, anti-riot trucks mounted with water cannon and armoured personnel carriers.</p>
<p>Hwang's defection, which President Kim said &quot;eloquently illustrates the grave situation North Korea finds itself in&quot;, has further strained ties between the two Koreas, but there have been signs in recent days that the crisis may be easing.</p>
<p>Pyongyang, which at first insisted that Hwang had been kidnapped by South Korean agents, softened its stance last week by vowing to dismiss the ideologue if he had in fact defected.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
