<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412907" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: ASEAN falls short of currency stabilisation plan.</title>
<headline>ASEAN falls short of currency stabilisation plan.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>PHUKET, Thailand 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance ministers of the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) on Saturday fell short of announcing a new currency stabilising scheme to help fight future speculative attacks on their currencies.</p>
<p>A communique issued at the end of a one-day ASEAN finance ministers meeting said briefly that the seven-member group would review what role its dormant ASEAN Swap Arrangement (ASA) could play in helping members out of future balance of payments problems.</p>
<p>The Thai baht recently faced sustained selling pressure from speculators concerned that the country's sizeable current account deficit, sluggish exports and mounting short-term private sector debt, may prompt its government to devalue its currency.</p>
<p>Recent pressure on the baht also grew as the currency, tied about 82 percent to the strong U.S. dollar, appreciated against the yen and mark.</p>
<p>Thai Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan said ASEAN members would likely extend the $200 million ASA next August when the agreement would come up for renewal.</p>
<p>The communique failed to mention whether ASA's small resources would be expanded to cope with growing currency trading activities in the region. The agreement was originally made back in 1977.</p>
<p>Amnuay said Thailand currently also had separate bilateral repurchase agreements with six to seven regional countries that could offer up to $3.5 billion of emergency funds to help defend their currencies.</p>
<p>&quot;These mechanisms are useful in providing good psychological assurance although I do not foresee a need for Thailand to rely on them,&quot; Amnuay told a press conference.</p>
<p>Thai officials said the country's $39.2 billion foreign reserves were sufficiently large to ward off further market assaults on the baht.</p>
<p>The Thai minister said Michel Camdessus, Managing Director of the International Monetary Fund, did not offer ASEAN members any assistance or advice on how to defend their currencies.</p>
<p>The IMF chief briefed the ministers on world economic conditions in a closed door session.</p>
<p>Three ASEAN members--Thailand, Malaysia and Singapore--are potential participants of IMF's New Arrangements to Borrow (NAB), a new $48 billion emergency credit line to be used in situations that could threaten the stability of the world monetary system.</p>
<p>Other ASEAN members include Indonesia, the Philippines, Brunei and Vietnam.</p>
<p>Philippine Finance Minister Roberto de Ocampo said at the same press conference that ASEAN members agreed to keep in close touch with one another so that they could help head off speculative currency attacks when assistance is required by one of its members. He did not elaborate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHUKET, Thailand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
