<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412905" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Singapore says currency stable despite U.S. dollar.</title>
<headline>Singapore says currency stable despite U.S. dollar.</headline>
<byline>Richard Hubbard</byline>
<dateline>PHUKET, Thailand 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore dollar's current value against a basket of currencies of its major trading partners is fairly stable and of no cause for concern, the Singapore finance minister Richard Hu said on Saturday.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters at the first official ASEAN finance ministers conference, Hu denied the government had been talking down the value of the Singapore dollar in recent public comments.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not been talking the Singapore dollar down. We have been asked why the Singapore dollar has weakened against the U.S. dollar. We have said it is weakening against the U.S. dollar like all other currencies,&quot; Hu said.</p>
<p>&quot;We monitor the Singapore dollar against a basket of currencies of our major trading partners. Against this basket the Singapore dollar has been fairly stable so there is no special reason for concern,&quot; the finance minister said.</p>
<p>Hu said the government coninues to review the amount of Singapore dollar borrowing by foreign banks, which forms the basis for trading the Singapore dollar in the currency markets.</p>
<p>At present banks are only allowed to borrow up to Singapore $150 million.</p>
<p>&quot;As our economy grows we can afford to be more liberal on foreign bank's access to Singapore dollar borrowing,&quot; Hu said. The limit is reviewed every year, he added.</p>
<p>Asked about the economic outlook for Singaporre in 1997, Hu said the government was &quot;cautiously optimistic&quot;. He added that the government saw no reason to change its official forecast for five to seven percent GDP growth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHUKET, Thailand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
