<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412986" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan's engineers protest over pay accord.</title>
<headline>Jordan's engineers protest over pay accord.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Around 500 Jordanian engineers protested outside Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti's office on Saturday over pay demands they said the government has failed to meet.</p>
<p>The engineers, who marched peacefully from their union headquarters to Kabariti's office, waved banners calling on the government to implement a pay accord agreed by the two sides more than four months ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Most government agencies have done nothing (to implement the accord,&quot; said Laith Shubailat, head of the Engineers Union. The Islamist-dominated union has 26,000 members and is by far the most powerful and vocal in Jordan.</p>
<p>Shubailat said the union's general assembly would meet on Tuesday to decide on whether to escalate the campaign next Saturday to a partial work stoppage. The campaign started last week with demonstrations outside the Ministry of Public Works.</p>
<p>Shubailat, a leading Islamist opposition figure, was released in November from prison where he had been serving time for slandering King Hussein. He had accused the king of treason over Jordan's 1994 peace treaty with Israel</p>
<p>The engineers have threatened an all-out strike on March 22 if their October pay accord with the government is not implemented by then.</p>
<p>&quot;Engineers cash 26 percent less than they used to in 1988, and the dinar doesn't buy what it did in 1988,&quot; Shubailat said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of our engineers with under 10 years experience are from the poor class...The middle class is being eroded in Jordan and the engineers are the example of that,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
