<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412965" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish press welcomes top council's warnings.</title>
<headline>Turkish press welcomes top council's warnings.</headline>
<byline>Ercan Ersoy</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish newspapers on Saturday welcomed a set of decisions by a military-dominated council that has warned the Islamist-led government not to stray from official state secularism and democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;Historic decision,&quot; flagged the mass-circulation daily Hurriyet in its banner headline, referring to the warnings by the influential National Security Council (NSC) after its nine-hour meeting that ended on Friday midnight.</p>
<p>Liberal daily Milliyet's headline hailed the NSC decisions, saying: &quot;Fine tuning for the regime.&quot;</p>
<p>It said the NSC had used strong expressions and included the word &quot;sanctions&quot; in its statement. &quot;For the first time a warning for sanctions is given in NSC decisions unless the recommendations are heeded,&quot; Milliyet said.</p>
<p>The NSC said after the meeting in an unusually strongly-worded statement that Turkey's secular and democratic system could not be compromised for any alternative system.</p>
<p>&quot;Concessions must never be given on the applications of the republic's laws and constitution that guarantee the democratic system,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The council -- chaired by President Suleyman Demirel and attended by Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan, ministers and army generals -- met for nine hours until midnight on Friday. Its pronouncements traditionally reflect the will of the army.</p>
<p>&quot;The meeting decided to inform the cabinet of measures that need to be taken in respect to these issues,&quot; the statement said. It did not elaborate on the measures.</p>
<p>&quot;All kinds of speculation that could harm Turkey's image and respect abroad and create doubts about its democracy...must be ended. Discussions about the regime cause damages for Turkey rather than benefits,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is evaluated that actions against the aforementioned points will lead to new tensions and cause sanctions.&quot;</p>
<p>Strains have escalated since the army sent tanks on manoeuvres through Ankara's Sincan district early in February after an Islamist protest there attended by the Iranian ambassador.</p>
<p>Erbakan, using similar expressions from the NSC statement, told his party meeting in Ankara on Saturday that all &quot;declarations&quot; that cast shadow on Turkey's democracy should be stopped to protect Turkish democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been seen that all members of the NSC are in full agreement and it has been decided that all divisive and separatist activities causing unrest should be ceased,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His government this week survived a censure motion challenge from two leftist parties that said the coalition was a threat to Turkey's secularism. Next week it will face another censure motion debate in parliament proposed by the opposition.</p>
<p>Analysts said the military's displeasure at Erbakan's efforts to push ahead with Islam-based policies was not expected to result in anything like the three army interventions seen in Turkey since 1960.</p>
<p>Turks welcomed the warnings by the NSC.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this is a timely decision and the government had better heed it,&quot; said Birol Sen, 28, a storekeeper.</p>
<p>Zeynep Halvasi, 20, a musician, said: &quot;We don't want military coups but this warning was needed.&quot;</p>
<p>The army is upset at comments in favour of sharia, or Islamic law, made by Islamists and by the Iranian ambassador at the anti-Israel protest in Sincan.</p>
<p>But the small, leftist Freedom and Solidarity Party said in a statement that the NSC was not in a position to attempt to solve political problems of Turkey.</p>
<p>&quot;Enough is enough! The NSC cannot do the fine-tuning of the regime,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
