<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412963" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran says quake killed 500, injured 2,000.</title>
<headline>Iran says quake killed 500, injured 2,000.</headline>
<byline>Sharif Imam-Jomeh</byline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rescue teams on Saturday completed operations in freezing winter temperatures to save victims of an earthquake that left 500 dead and 2,000 injured in northwestern Iran, a senior official said.</p>
<p>Deputy Interior Minister Rasoul Zargar told Iranian television the 3,000 relief workers had completed their rescue efforts this afternoon and within 12 hours would set up temporary shelters for the 35,000 people left homeless in the mountainous region.</p>
<p>The earthquake, measuring 5.5 on the Richter scale, hit the city of Ardabil and the town of Meshkinshahr at 4.27 p.m. (1257 GMT) on Friday, causing heavy damage to some 83 neighbouring villages, Zargar said.</p>
<p>Zargar, who heads the relief operation, said 719 of the injured had been hospitalised.</p>
<p>Iranian President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani called on authorities to bring speedy relief to the quake-stricken areas and urged people to send aid for the victims.</p>
<p>Relief workers have set up 2,500 tents to shelter thousands of families made homeless and distributed blankets, food, heaters and lanterns, the Iranian news agency IRNA said earlier.</p>
<p>State-run Tehran radio said local authorities announced three days of mourning in the province of Ardabil.</p>
<p>Ardabil is an agricultural province inhabited mainly by Iran's Azeri minority. It is one of Iran's coldest regions, with freezing temperatures during the winter. Tehran Radio earlier said snow in mountainous areas was hampering rescue operations.</p>
<p>&quot;My family and I could not sleep last night because of the aftershocks,&quot; one resident told Reuters by telephone. &quot;And we could not go outside to sleep because it was too cold with temperatures just below freezing.&quot;</p>
<p>Early on Saturday, a tremor measuring about four on the Richter scale jolted an area near Bojnourd in northeastern Iran but caused no casualties or damages, IRNA said.</p>
<p>In early February, two earthquakes measuring 6.1 and 5.4 on the Richter scale killed at least 79 people and injured 260 in and around Bojnourd.</p>
<p>The tremor hit the Ardabil area some 16 hours after a strong earthquake killed nearly 50 people in and around the town of Quetta in Pakistan's Baluchistan province across Iran's southeastern border.</p>
<p>A Pakistani state seismic centre in the northwestern town of Peshawar measured that earthquake at 6.2 on the Richter scale.</p>
<p>IRNA earlier said a quake also measuring 5.5 on the Richter scale hit the western Iranian city of Sanandaj at about the same time as the tremor hit Ardabil, some 350 km (220 miles) away. It did not report any casualties.</p>
<p>Iran's northern province of Gilan on the Caspian Sea was also shaken by a tremor measuring about four on the Richter scale, but there was no damage, IRNA added.</p>
<p>Force four and five tremors are powerful enough to cause heavy damage in populated areas.</p>
<p>Earthquakes hit Iran regularly. The worst recorded one, measuring 7.3 on the Richter scale, killed 35,000 people in Gilan and neighbouring Zanjan province in 1990.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
