<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412962" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran orders out Turkish ambassador, consul.</title>
<headline>Iran orders out Turkish ambassador, consul.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran said on Saturday it had ordered Turkey's ambassador in Tehran and another Turkish diplomat to leave, two days after Turkey expelled an Iranian consul.</p>
<p>The ambassador and Turkey's consul-general in Orumiyeh were given one week to leave Iran because of &quot;activities incompatible with diplomatic norms&quot;, said a Foreign Ministry statement read on Tehran radio.</p>
<p>Turkey on Thursday declared Iran's Erzurum chief consul Saeede Zare 'persona non grata' after he accused a senior Turkish military commander of &quot;irresponsibility&quot; for apparently describing Iran as a &quot;terrorist&quot; state.</p>
<p>&quot;Iran considers statements by some Turkish officials against Iran as unacceptable and incompatible with friendly ties between the two countries,&quot; the Iranian statement said.</p>
<p>It was referring to remarks by the deputy chief of the Turkish armed forces, Cevik Bir, who criticised Iran for allegedly backing Turkey's Kurdish rebels. Tehran protested to Turkey over the remarks last Monday.</p>
<p>The Turkish Foreign Ministry said on Friday Tehran had asked Ankara to withdraw the two diplomats from Iran and that the Turkish government was considering the demand.</p>
<p>Diplomatic relations between the 18-year-old Islamic republic and its secularist neighbour have experienced many periods of strain, but the expulsions cap the first major row since an Islamic government came to power in Ankara last June.</p>
<p>The Iranian statement indicated that Tehran did not want the expulsions to harm relations beyond repair, but that strengthening bilateral ties required efforts by both sides.</p>
<p>&quot;As earlier, Iran wants good relations with all its neighbours including Turkey and is willing to share equal efforts towards this aim,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>A Turkish official said on Friday Ankara was going ahead with a 23-year, $23-billion accord to buy gas from Iran despite the row and efforts by the United States to stop the deal.</p>
<p>The hardline Iranian daily Kayhan accused Israel and the United States of provoking the dispute.</p>
<p>&quot;The Zionist regime (Israel) and the United States have undertaken a wide effort to disrupt the good ties between Tehran and the Islamist government of (Prime Minister Necmettin) Erbakan,&quot; it said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The row started when Ankara protested to Tehran early in February about Iranian ambassador Mohammad Reza Bagheri's comments in favour of Islamic law at an Islamist rally in the Ankara district of Sincan.</p>
<p>Tanks toured Sincan several days after the protest in an apparent warning to Islamists from the secularist army.</p>
<p>Iran later withdrew Bagheri and a consul from Turkey.</p>
<p>After a meeting on Friday, Turkey's military-dominated National Security Council warned Erbakan's government not to stray from the path of democracy and official secularism.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
