<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412940" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURMA: Burma blames West for supporting Karen guerrillas.</title>
<headline>Burma blames West for supporting Karen guerrillas.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Charles</byline>
<dateline>RANGOON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burma's top generals accused the West and traitors at home of influencing the ethnic Karen guerrilla organisation to prolong its rebellion against Rangoon's rule, official media reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>State-run newspapers said General Maung Aye, vice chairman of Burma's ruling military body, the State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC), made the comments in a speech on Friday.</p>
<p>He said the armed Karen National Union (KNU) -- some of whose members have indicated they want peace talks with Rangoon -- had fallen under the influence of Western nations and &quot;axe-handles&quot;, or traitors, within Burma.</p>
<p>&quot;As those of the West bloc who could not bear to see peace and development in our country persuaded them with arms and dollars, they rebuffed the peace,&quot; Maung Aye was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;The axe-handles within the country also opposed peace, orchestrating with the neo-colonialists,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Lieutenant General Tin Oo, Secretary Two of SLORC, made similar comments in a separate speech, saying the KNU has ignored government peace overtures at the instigation of Western elements.</p>
<p>&quot;All armed (rebel) groups except the KNU are already within the peaceful political system,&quot; he said. &quot;The KNU has turned its back due to the instigation of neo-colonialists and internal traitorous elements who are pining for the West.&quot;</p>
<p>Tin Oo then repeated his usual call for the people of Burma to crush the &quot;destructionists&quot;.</p>
<p>The KNU was formed in 1948 to fight for an ethnic Karen homeland in eastern Burma. It has rejected several peace overtures from Rangoon and is the last major ethnic rebel movement that has not signed a ceasefire agreement with SLORC.</p>
<p>But the KNU has suffered a series of military setbacks in recent years that have prompted many senior members to declare the movement's end is near. The latest wave of fighting forced thousands of Karen to flee into Thailand last month.</p>
<p>The U.S. State Department and human rights groups claim that Thailand was forcibly repatriating the refugees.</p>
<p>The United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) said on Friday it would seek clarification from Thailand on reports from its staff that some refugees were being forcibly sent back and that males aged over 15 were prevented from entering Thailand.</p>
<p>But Thai officials deny the claims, saying entry had been refused only to some armed men trying to cross into Thailand with the refugees.</p>
<p>Karen refugee officials at border camps in Thailand, which have housed about 70,000 refugees since the early 1980s, also denied the reports of forced repatriation.</p>
<p>Maung Aye met last week with Thailand's army chief to discuss the border problem.</p>
<p>Burma has said it is willing to take back any Karen refugees wanting to return home.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RANGOON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
