<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412961" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Arafat says Israeli settlements pulverise peace.</title>
<headline>Arafat says Israeli settlements pulverise peace.</headline>
<byline>Miral Fahmy</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat said on Saturday that Israeli plans to build a Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem would &quot;blast to smithereens&quot; its peace accords with Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;This settlement issue is an attempt by Israel to blast to smithereens the peace process,&quot; Arafat told an emergency session of the Cairo-based Arab League, referring to plans for building 6,500 homes for Jewish settlers in Jabal Abu Ghneim, or Har Homa, in East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>&quot;We say that there can be no peace without Jerusalem and no peace with settlements. Settlements and peace do not go together and there will be no peace as long as Israel violates our right in Jerusalem.&quot;</p>
<p>Israel regards Jerusalem as its eternal capital while the Palestinians want its eastern part, occupied by the Jewish state since the 1967 Arab-Israel war, as the capital of a future Palestinian state.</p>
<p>&quot;According to the agreement I had with (former Israeli prime minister Yitzhak) Rabin, no one single house to be added in Jerusalem...the status of the city is to be discussed and no one side can change it in any way (before that),&quot; Arafat said in English.</p>
<p>Israel's approval on Wednesday of a plan to construct the homes has sparked criticism from its key ally the United States and Palestinian warnings that it could unleash bloodshed.</p>
<p>In Ramallah, Palestinian lawmakers called a general strike in the West Bank and Gaza Strip for Monday to protest against the plan.</p>
<p>Arafat, who is due to hold talks with U.S. President Bill Clinton in Washington on Monday, told the meeting of Arab League's permanent representatives that he had several political weapons to use against Israel if it did not change its position on settlements.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu last year lifted a ban on building Jewish settlements on occupied Arab lands.</p>
<p>&quot;We are supposed to declare the setting up of a Palestinian state in five years but what would happen if I declare it right here? What would he (Netanyahu) do then? It's tit-for-tat and we have our weapons too,&quot; Arafat said.</p>
<p>Arafat said that the Har Homa settlement was part of a conspiracy to divide the West Bank into northern and southern zones and also to create an &quot;alternative to Bethlehem, which lies on its outskirts, so that the world can celebrate Christmas in the year 2000 there and not in the birthplace of Christ&quot;.</p>
<p>Bethlehem is one of eight West Bank towns which Israel has handed over to the Palestinians since 1994.</p>
<p>The 22-member Arab League issued a statement after the meeting, asking &quot;countries that give economic and financial aid to Israel to stop this aid because it will be used in settlement plans on occupied Arab lands.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The session strongly condemns the Israeli measures and considers them contrary to the basis of the Middle East peace process and also to the spirit and letter of the peace agreements signed by both sides,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The statement asked the United Nations to pressure Israel to repeal its decision.</p>
<p>Arafat held talks earlier with Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak which focussed on the Har Homa settlement plans.</p>
<p>Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa told reporters at the Ittihadia palace while Arafat and Mubarak were meeting on Saturday that Israel's settlement policies contravened Israeli-Arab agreements and threatened the peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue of Jerusalem is very, very touchy. One cannot toy with it,&quot; Moussa said. &quot;I don't think the settlement policy would lead to anything but destruction and adversely affect the peace process.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
