<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412932" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Mandela dodges Machel issue in Philippines.</title>
<headline>Mandela dodges Machel issue in Philippines.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela on Saturday dodged questions about his female companion Graca Machel, who is travelling with him on an eight-day Asian tour.</p>
<p>&quot;My cultural background does not permit me to discuss this question with people young enough to be my children or grandchildren,&quot; the 78-year old Mandela said when asked if a wedding was in the offing during a press conference in Manila.</p>
<p>Philippine President Fidel Ramos laughed and clapped at the question and answer.</p>
<p>It was the first time Graca, the widow of former Mozambican president Somora Machel, has accompanied Mandela on a state visit. The South African leader will visit Brunei, Singapore and Malaysia next week.</p>
<p>Mandela acknowledged last year that he and Graca were in love. He has said they have no plans to marry.</p>
<p>Mandela formally divorced his second wife Winnie last year.</p>
<p>One of the world's most popular and charismatic leaders, Mandela was accompanied by his daughter Zenani on his triumphant tour last July to Britain and France. Since he left Winnie in 1992, he has travelled with Zenani or grand-daughter Rochelle.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
