<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413030" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Prosecutors will not use handwriting in Okla case.</title>
<headline>Prosecutors will not use handwriting in Okla case.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prosecutors in the Oklahoma City bombing case have dropped plans to have an expert testify that Timothy McVeigh's handwriting is on documents that allegedly link him to the crime, a source told Reuters on Friday.</p>
<p>Instead, the Justice Department prosecutors plan to rely on a FBI expert to testify that handwriting on the documents is similiar to McVeigh's handwriting, the source said.</p>
<p>The bombing case judge earlier this month told prosecutors he would not allow jurors to hear the FBI lab examiner testify about handwriting conclusions unless prosecutors convinced him that the conclusions were scientifically reliable.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there is any basis in science for that kind of opinion,&quot; U.S. District Judge Richard Matsch said at a pre-trial hearing.</p>
<p>Prosecutor James Orenstein said the government would reconsider its plan in light of Matsch's admonition to &quot;think twice&quot; before trying to convince him about the reliability of drawing handwriting conclusions.</p>
<p>Prosecutors recently informed Matsch in a closed-door court conference that they will not pursue that kind of testimony, a source said.</p>
<p>Authorities have scores of examples of handwriting they could use to try to link McVeigh to the bombing by testimony about similiarities to his handwriting, the source said.</p>
<p>The examples include the contract to rent the Ryder truck allegedly used to hold the bomb.</p>
<p>McVeigh and former Army buddy Terry Nichols are accused of bombing the Alfred P. Murrah Federal Building on April 19, 1995 that claimed the lives of 168 people.</p>
<p>McVeigh is scheduled to go on trial March 31. Nichols' trial date has not been set.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
