<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413029" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US West Coast crudes drop, Canadian crude watched.</title>
<headline>US West Coast crudes drop, Canadian crude watched.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Outright prices for U.S West Coast light crude dropped in line with technical selling of crude futures and a weaker fundamental outlook for heating oil, traders said, but buyers watched foreign sources closely.</p>
<p>West Coast buyers of Alaska North Slope (ANS) crude avoided the grade Friday, after two late-week deals tightened the differential 10 cents for April cargoes.</p>
<p>Buyers said they would look overseas, with one bringing in 400,000 barrels of Colombia South Blend in April. The cargo was priced on a WTI-related formula, the trader said.</p>
<p>They said ANS might hit last year's level of -$0.60 cents.  </p>
<p>Although a Washington refiner said they feared Canadian light crude imports would drop, removing an important ANS alternative, some traders said March supplies were high.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to be higher than a lot of people were expecting,&quot; a Canadian trader said, noting the price for light sweet grades could range $1.15 to $1.25 over WTI.</p>
<p>While the ANS price remains high, traders said the only alternative grade which could contain ANS, is Indonesian.</p>
<p>&quot;It's even pricier than Canada,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Talk circulated that imports into Chicago and eastern Canada would ease demand on the Interprovincial Pipe Line and allow more Canadian grades to move West.</p>
<p>Desite the tighter discount, ANS outright prices fell to $19.30/19.50 a barrel, off 50 cents from Thursday.</p>
<p>Line 63 prices stood unchanged at postings plus $0.95 - $1.05.</p>
<p>Kern River heavy crude prices fell, after two major California oil companies lowered postings.</p>
<p>A deal was heard done earlier this week at 0.45 cents a barrel under heavy postings, a sharp increase over previous discounts.</p>
<p>((David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau 213 380 2014))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
