<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413010" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: L.A. shootout on TV; viewers see robbers killed.</title>
<headline>L.A. shootout on TV; viewers see robbers killed.</headline>
<byline>Steve James</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>In scenes reminiscent of a Hollywood movie, two bank robbers dressed in black fatigues and wearing body armour were killed by police on Friday in a wild shootout captured on live television.</p>
<p>Ten police officers and five civilians were wounded before police in riot gear, armed with automatic weapons and backed by armoured vehicles, fanned out looking for at least one other suspect.</p>
<p>Several hours later a man was seen being handcuffed and taken to the police command centre, but it was not known if he was one of the bank robbery suspects who got away.</p>
<p>&quot;They were shooting at anything. Anything that moved,&quot; said one man who got caught in the crossfire.</p>
<p>Witnesses said as many as six robbers dressed in black fatigues and ski masks had walked into a bank in North Hollywood around 9 a.m. local time (1700 GMT) firing automatic weapons. They apparently triggered an alarm and when police arrived, they began shooting at officers.</p>
<p>The entire incident, including bursts of automatic weapons fire, was captured on videotape by news helicopters and shown live on local television stations.</p>
<p>&quot;A firefight occured that was horrendous. The suspects continued to fire at officers who were undergunned for over an hour,&quot; police spokesman Cmdr. Tim McBride said. They had &quot;no sense of conscience, no sense of dignity, no sense of respect for life,&quot; McBride said.</p>
<p>He said the gunmen wore full body armour and were armed with AK-47 automatic weapons with armour piercing bullets that can penetrate bullet-proof vests at 200 yards (metres).</p>
<p>Earlier outside the bank one of the suspects was seen on TV nonchalantly firing with an automatic rifle at police in the parking lot as another suspect in a white car drove off with the trunk and driver's side door open.</p>
<p>In one graphic image, a robber was seen firing a handgun at police and then falling dead on the sidewalk after he was hit in the head by police fire.</p>
<p>Another gunman was seen firing an automatic rifle through the windscreen of a car at three officers crouching behind their squad car. He then surrendered to police in the residential neighbourhood and was believed to have died later.</p>
<p>McBride said two of the suspects, believed to have carried out previous bank robberies in Los Angeles, were killed by police. &quot;There is one additional suspect, there may be more, and they are extremely dangerous,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>At least eight officers had injuries, he said, but none was life-threatening. Police later said 10 officers were hurt, including one shot in the parking lot and shown on TV being dragged to safety by fellow officers and bundled into a squad car.</p>
<p>Five civilians were injured -- three by gunshots and one in a traffic accident with a police car.</p>
<p>Armando Jimenez, who was entering the bank as the robbery occurred, said many people did not realise anything untoward was happening in an area where filmmaking is not unusual.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone thought it was a (car) backfire. People were still using the (ATM) as the automatic fire was going on.</p>
<p>&quot;I was so scared. There were six men and two cars. They covered their faces and then they shot. As soon as they shot I knew it was a robbery,&quot; Jimenez told local KABC television.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
