<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413063" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Scandal-torn Belgian PS socialists re-elect leader.</title>
<headline>Scandal-torn Belgian PS socialists re-elect leader.</headline>
<byline>Nieck Ammerlaan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The largest French-speaking partner in Belgium's four party coalition re-elected its chairman on Saturday, but did little to dispel lingering worries among the other partners over its dented credibility.</p>
<p>The Parti Socialiste (PS) re-appointed Philippe Busquin by 361 votes against 80 and with 37 abstentions.</p>
<p>Busquin told the congress of the scandal-torn party that at the moment when the party was in the eye of the storm it had a unique opportunity for change, but he also denied any party responsibility for a bribes-for-orders affair.</p>
<p>After years of scandals, not only over alleged corruption but also the unsolved case of a 1991 mafia-style killing of a senior party figure, the patience of the other parties in the centre-left coalition is wearing thin.</p>
<p>But Busquin gave no clear signals at the congress a purge would be started, instead re-affirming his faith in an aide -- Patrick Moriau, who on Thursday lost his parliamentary immunity.</p>
<p>Moriau has been accused of receiving stolen goods, fraud and money laundering, charges which have been laid in connection with bank accounts found in the tax haven of Luxembourg and allegedly containing bribes paid by a French defence firm.</p>
<p>Moriau, who denies any wrongdoing, is the fifth PS official to have fallen victim in recent weeks in the Dassault case named after the French firm which allegedly paid 600 million Belgian francs in the late 1980s to win a major Belgian contract.</p>
<p>Dassault, whose chief Serge Dassault is the subject of an international arrest warrant issued by Belgium, has denied any wrongdoing.</p>
<p>Of the Dassault money, 45 million francs ($1.3 million) has been traced to the PS, which supplied the defence minister in the government of the time.</p>
<p>Three PS officials -- Merry Hermanus, Francois Pirot and Fernand Detaille -- have been in jail for weeks on charges related to the Dassault case.</p>
<p>Guy Spitaels, an ex-PS chairman, who held high office in the regional government of Wallonia, Belgium's francophone southern half, and headed a body controlling a major bank, resigned these posts on Thursday over his alleged involvement in the scandal.</p>
<p>In his speech to congress Busquin said, &quot;During the 20 years of my parliamentary life I have had many contacts with the economic and financial world. But I know that Merry Hermanus never spoke about Dassault.&quot;</p>
<p>Many commentators, however, doubt that Spitaels did not brief Busquin fully on the state of the party's finances where Busquin took over the chairmanship in 1992.</p>
<p>Busquin has already admitted having met officials of Italian helicopter firm Agusta in 1988, before the company won an army contract, a deal also being scrutinised by police.</p>
<p>Agusta has denied any wrongdoing.</p>
<p>The other coalition partners -- Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene's Flemish christian democrats in the vanguard -- wasted little time in putting pressure on the PS to put its house in order when the Dassault affair first broke.</p>
<p>Some commentators are now bound to repeat warnings of an implosion of the PS at a time when the federal government is concentrating fully on making the economy fit for Belgium's entry into Europe's economic and monetary union by 1999.</p>
<p>Financial markets are likely to stay nervous about the coalition's future, fearing that Busquin and the PS with him will stumble over fresh skeletons still in the party's cupboard.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
