<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413047" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German extremists clash over Hitler's army exhibit.</title>
<headline>German extremists clash over Hitler's army exhibit.</headline>
<byline>John Gilardi</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Left-wing activists on Saturday threw eggs, bottles and stones at neo-Nazis protesting in Munich against a controversial exhibition on German army crimes committed in the Nazi era.</p>
<p>But a two-hour standoff between around 8,000 left-wing activists and around 4,500 right-wing extremists ended peacefully without any major clashes between the two groups.</p>
<p>Police said 55 people were detained during the day of rallies in the capital of the southern state of Bavaria and three people were injured, including one of the 2,000 police in the city centre.</p>
<p>Thousands of local residents mixed with left-wing activists, blowing whistles and shouting &quot;Nazis Out!&quot; while blocking Munich's central Marienplatz where right-wing extremists had scheduled a rally.</p>
<p>Police formed a human barricade between the two groups about 100 meters from the Marianplatz, where the controversial exhibition is being staged, and allowed right-wing leaders to conduct their rally on the street.</p>
<p>Neo-Nazis carried pictures of soldiers and placards reading &quot;We are proud of our Grandfathers&quot; and waved the red, white and black flags of the National Democratic Party (NPD).</p>
<p>Demonstrators were detained for offences including wearing outlawed Nazi badges and military uniform. Others were detained for carrying iron bars and wooden poles.</p>
<p>After the rallies Munich police chief Roland Koller said government officials must consider whether to allow such events to be held in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;These rallies today cost the taxpayer a lot of money in overtime payments for the police and aggravation for everyone else,&quot; Koller said. &quot;We have to reflect whether such spectacles should be allowed.&quot;</p>
<p>The rallies were called after emotions boiled over in conservative Bavaria over the exhibition, which challenges the notion that ordinary German soldiers had nothing to do with Nazi crimes during World War Two.</p>
<p>Left-wing groups including members of the major political opposition parties, the Social Democrats (SPD) and the Greens, organised counter-protests in Munich -- which had the status of &quot;Capital city of the Movement&quot; during the Nazi era.</p>
<p>The exhibition's organiser, historian Hannes Heer, said the Wehrmacht had been the second pillar of Hitler's violent regime and was responsible for millions of deaths, although that did not mean that every ordinary soldier was a criminal.</p>
<p>The exhibition stirred debate when it was unveiled in Hamburg two years ago by billionaire Jan Philipp Reemstma, who once owned one of Germany's biggest tobacco firms.</p>
<p>But it had provoked little controversy in a dozen German cities until the Bavarian Christan Social Union (CSU), sister party to German Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) mounted a campaign against it.</p>
<p>The exhibition uses photographs and letters from soldiers themselves to back up its premise that the regular army, as well as the SS units usually blamed for war crimes, participated in mass killings of Jews and other atrocities.</p>
<p>Right-wing extremists, carrying placards reading &quot;No defamation of our brave Wehrmacht soldiers&quot;, scuffled with left-wing supporters of the exhibition when it opened in Munich this week.</p>
<p>A group of left-wing protesters also stormed a meeting of the local CSU party late last Monday in Munich's town hall, poured beer over CSU officials and accused the party of pandering to right-wing extremists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
