<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413082" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany expects clashes over Hitler's army exhibit.</title>
<headline>Germany expects clashes over Hitler's army exhibit.</headline>
<byline>John Gilardi</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>German police took to the streets in force on Saturday to prevent clashes between neo-Nazis and left-wing activists protesting at a controversial exhibition on German army crimes committed in the Nazi era.</p>
<p>Authorities said they were expecting up to 5,000 protestors in four separate demonstrations and police erected metre-high steel barriers to keep oppositing demonstrators apart.</p>
<p>Police said they had detained eight people ahead of the marches, some for wearing Nazi badges, others for carrying iron bars and wooden poles. They said they were monitoring vehicles entering the Munich area and turning away known extremists.</p>
<p>Neo-Nazis called a midday rally under the slogan, &quot;Our grandfathers were no criminals and we are proud of them!&quot;</p>
<p>Munich police chief Roland Koller told the city's Abend Zeitung in an interview on Saturday that he feared massive clashes would take place between right-wing and left-wing groups but that police would use force to keep them apart.</p>
<p>&quot;It could lead to massive physical confrontation between right-wing and left-wing groups,&quot; Koller told the newspaper.</p>
<p>Police said at least 2,500 right-wing extremists were expected to attend a rally and protest march on the citys main shopping street called the Marienplatz.</p>
<p>Another 2,500 people were expected to attend three other rallies and marches organised by the DGB union as well as members of the major political opposition parties, the Social Democrats (SPD) and the Greens, and left-wing groups.</p>
<p>Some left-wing demonstrators were expected to march to buildings in Munich -- which had the status of &quot;Capital city of the Movement&quot; during the Nazi era -- that were sites of Nazi meetings or atrocities.</p>
<p>The rallies were called after emotions erupted in the conservative southern state of Bavaria over the exhibition, which challenges the notion that ordinary German soldiers had noting to do with Nazi crimes during World War Two.</p>
<p>The exhibitions organiser, historian Hannes Heer, said the Wehrmacht had been the second pillar of Hitler's violent regime and was responsible for millions of deaths, although that did not mean that every ordinary soldier was a criminal.</p>
<p>The exhibition stirred debate when it was unveiled in Hamburg two years ago by billionaire Jan Philipp Reemstma, who once owned one of Germany's biggest tobacco firms.</p>
<p>But it had provoked little controversy in a dozen German cities until the Bavarian Christan Social Union (CSU), sister party to German Chancellor Helmut Kohls Christian Democrats (CDU) mounted a campaign against it.</p>
<p>The exhibition uses photographs and letters from soldiers themselves to back up its premise that the regular army participated in mass killings of Jews and other atrocities, as well as the SS units usually blamed for war crimes.</p>
<p>Right-wing extremists, carrying placards reading &quot;Honour for the Wehrmacht&quot; and &quot;No defamation of our brave Wehrmacht soldiers&quot;, scuffled with left-wing supporters of the exhibition in recent days after the exhibition opened in Munich.</p>
<p>A group of left-wing protesters also stormed a meeting of opponents of the exhibition from the local CSU party late last Monday in Munichs town hall, accusing the party of pandering to right-wing extremists.</p>
<p>Police, who detained 24 people that night, said demonstrators poured beer over the heads of CSU officials.</p>
<p>Reemstma said the controversy in Munich was a sobering experience. &quot;The reaction throws an interesting light onto the condition of our society,&quot; he said at the exhibitions opening ceremony on Monday night.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
