<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413070" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Renault has little hope for Belgian plant workers.</title>
<headline>Renault has little hope for Belgian plant workers.</headline>
<byline>Nieck Ammerlaan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>French car maker Renault on Saturday held out little hope for thousands of Belgian workers due to lose their jobs in a restructuring aimed at helping the French group improve profitability.</p>
<p>Louis Schweitzer, chief executive officer of Renault, said after talks in Brussels that Renault would not go back on its decision to close its car assembly plant at Vilvoorde.</p>
<p>Asked by waiting journalists if he would review the decision to close the plant, he said, &quot;No.&quot;</p>
<p>He had been called to Brussels by Luc Van den Brande, regional Prime Minister of Flanders, where Vilvoorde is located.</p>
<p>Van den Brande said after the 90-minute meeting that the talks had been tough and grim. Schweitzer had refused to alleviate the impact of the closure on the 3,100 Vilvoorde staff and at least 1,000 workers at suppliers and subcontractors.</p>
<p>Before the meeting Flemish economics minister Eric Van Rompuy had called the unilateral decision &quot;a terrorist act.&quot;</p>
<p>There now appears to be little the regional, and federal, government can now do to stop Renault from closing the plant apart from bemoaning the brutal way in which the decision was announced and attacking Renault for procedural breaches.</p>
<p>Federal Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene told Labour Minister Miet Smet on Friday to investigate whether Belgian, European Union and Organisation of Economic Cooperation and Development rules on information and consultation of employees had been breached and which sanctions could be taken.</p>
<p>Dehaene, who lives in Vilvoorde, on Friday had denounced the decision, taken by &quot;a head office...far away from the locality affected and independent of its social consequences.&quot;</p>
<p>The European Commission said on Friday it was looking at the Renault case, but had no powers itself to intervene.</p>
<p>In the worst case Renault will face a heavy fine, but its decision to close Vilvoorde will remain intact.</p>
<p>Schweitzer said he was not aware of any breaches of rules on staff information and consultation.</p>
<p>Staff and regional authorities received no warning of the planned closure in July.</p>
<p>Van den Brande reiterated that Renault's decision was unacceptable and unlawful and demanded that in line with Belgian law Renault start talks with the Vilvoorde unions to investigate options which could have prevented the closure.</p>
<p>Under Belgian law such talks must be held before key decisions on a company's future are taken.</p>
<p>Some two dozen Renault workers picketed the talks, but apart from vocal calls for &quot;jobs, no dole&quot; there were no incidents.</p>
<p>Vilvoorde staff continued to occupy the plant on Saturday, preventing finished cars worth some four billion Belgian francs from leaving the site and being supplied to customers.</p>
<p>Workers will hold a general assembly on Monday and plan to march on Brussels.</p>
<p>Dehaene said on Friday he would take up the matter with his French counterpart Alain Juppe again on Monday. On Thursday Juppe told him by telephone he would discuss the closure with the management of the partly state-owned carmaker.</p>
<p>France has a 46 percent stake in Renault, which expects to have suffered its first loss in 10 years in 1996 because of weak markets, high costs -- despite the launch of new models.</p>
<p>Renault said the Vilvoorde closure was part of a wider reorganisation and would save the company 825 million French francs ($144.5 million) a year, once completed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
