<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413027" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Former Mexican official asks to depose Raul Salinas.</title>
<headline>Former Mexican official asks to depose Raul Salinas.</headline>
<byline>Jeff Franks</byline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defence attorneys for a former Mexican official accused of taking money from drug traffickers filed a motion seeking to question Raul Salinas, the jailed brother of former Mexican President Carlos Salinas de Gortari, according to court documents posted on Friday.</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Nancy Atlas still must rule on the motion, which was listed in the case docket for the U.S. government's civil action against former Mexican deputy attorney general Mario Ruiz Massieu.</p>
<p>The full contents of the motion, which was submitted to the court on Thursday, were not available because court workers could not find the case file. The listing on the docket, which is essentially a table of contents for motions filed in the case, said &quot;Motion for leave to take the deposition of Raul Salinas de Gortari by Mario Ruiz Massieu.&quot;</p>
<p>Presumably, Raul Salinas would be deposed in Mexico, where he has been in jail for two years, which would explain the motion for leave. Neither prosecutors nor defence attorney Tony Canales could be reached for comment.</p>
<p>U.S. prosecutors are seeking to confiscate $9 million from a Houston bank account held by Ruiz Massieu on grounds that he got the money from drug traffickers seeking protection. The case is set for trial on March 10 in Houston.</p>
<p>A recent report in Mexican magazine Proceso quoted court documents in which prosecutors said Ruiz Massieu had received $4 million from drug traffickers in the presence of Raul Salinas in a 1993 meeting at Salinas' ranch.</p>
<p>The payoff was allegedly part of a larger conspiracy involving Salinas, his father Raul Salinas Lozano, and others to provide protection for drug traffickers in exchange for millions of dollars in payoffs, the report said.</p>
<p>All the Salinas denied the reports, which presumably is why the defence wants to depose Raul Salinas.</p>
<p>Salinas has been held without trial since February 1995 on charges that he masterminded the murder of Jose Francisco Ruiz Massieu, a former top ruling party official who was gunned down on a Mexico City street in September 1994. Jose Francisco was the brother of Mario Ruiz Massieu.</p>
<p>Salinas is also accused of illegally compiling a huge fortune while holding a government job during brother Carlos' six-year term in office.</p>
<p>Ruiz Massieu has said in pre-trial depositions that the money being sought by the U.S. government was family money deposited in the United States to protect it from economic and political uncertainty in Mexico.</p>
<p>Ruiz Massieu also was named by then-President Carlos Salinas to head the investigation into his brother's death. He concluded that Jose Francisco had been murdered by anti-reform elements, but Mexican prosecutors say that he was covering for Raul Salinas.</p>
<p>Ruiz Massieu fled from Mexico in March 1995 but was arrested at the Newark, New Jersey, airport for failing to declare that he was carrying $46,000 in cash.</p>
<p>He is under house arrest in New Jersey.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
