<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413007" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Former Clinton finance chief questions memo.</title>
<headline>Former Clinton finance chief questions memo.</headline>
<byline>Michael Posner</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The former finance chairman of President Clinton's election campaign said Saturday he came up with the idea of coffees between donors and Clinton and did not care if they were held in the White House or McDonald's.</p>
<p>Terry McAuliffe said on CNN, however, he did not suggest overnight stays in the Lincoln Bedroom at the White House and assumed that idea came from the White House legal counsel.</p>
<p>There were more than a hundred coffees, many with contributors, and news of overnight stays in the Lincoln Bedroom embarrassed the White House.</p>
<p>When asked who came up with the coffee suggestion, he said &quot;I did&quot; as a way for donors to meet Clinton.</p>
<p>As for overnight stays in the Lincoln Bedroom, he said, &quot;I assume the White House legal counsel came up with it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I sent a simple memo in that said we need to get our past supporters in to see you, Mr. President,&quot; he said. &quot;I don't care if we had to meet them at McDonald's. It didn't matter to me. What mattered to me is that I could get supporters in front of the candidate -- the president.&quot;</p>
<p>McAuliffe described the fund-raising operation after he left the committee as a &quot;rogue operation&quot; by a small group.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you had two or three individuals which has now come out in the press that ran afoul -- a rogue operation that were bringing people in that nobody knew that were illegal contributions,&quot; he said on CNN. &quot;It's unfortunate that that happened.&quot;</p>
<p>A 1995 memo from McAuliffe grabbed attention earlier this week when the White House released a batch of documents. One was from McAuliffe that gave Clinton names of 10 Democratic donors and ways to encourage donors with White House perks.</p>
<p>While McAuliffe did not mention overnight stays in the Lincoln Bedroom in his note, a handwritten addition from Clinton suggested &quot;ready to start overnight stays right away&quot; and added that other names should be added of donors giving dollars of &quot;100,000 or more, 50,000 or more.&quot;</p>
<p>On the programme, McAuliffe denied that these were new donors being wooed in that memo to give money for White House access but instead said he wanted to reach past supporters and &quot;energize&quot; them for the coming campaign.</p>
<p>On Friday, Democratic National Committee officials announced the party was returning another $1.5 million in illegal or questionable donations, bringing to $3 million the amount returned.</p>
<p>The party officials said 75 percent of the money was solicited by three Asian-American fund-raisers currently under investigation by the Justice Department and congressional committees.</p>
<p>McAuliffe, a former Democratic National Committee finance chairman before he joined the separate Clinton/Gore campaign team as its finance chief in 1995, referred to a fax of the memo that was sent to former White House Deputy Chief of Staff Harold Ickes.</p>
<p>McAuliffe of the 1994 unsigned memo addressed to former Democratic National Committee (DNC) official Martha Phipps: &quot;It almost looks like a set-up to me. I've never seen a memo that is to without a from.&quot;</p>
<p>That memo was turned over with other documents from Ickes to a House committee investigating improper campaign fund raising for Democrats.</p>
<p>The memo, circulated in Washington Friday, listed a number of suggested perks that could be offered to induce big contributions to Democratic coffers as part of a drive to raise $40 million.</p>
<p>They included attendance at dinners with Clinton and privileges at the White House restaurant.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
