<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413008" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clintons treat Chelsea to a night in New York.</title>
<headline>Clintons treat Chelsea to a night in New York.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton and his wife Hillary Saturday flew their daughter Chelsea and three of her friends to New York to see Broadway shows to celebrate her 17th birthday.</p>
<p>The first family and Chelsea's friends attended an afternoon showing of &quot;Rent,&quot; an award-winning musical about love, drugs, AIDS and poverty.</p>
<p>During a break in the entertainment, the president said he thought the hit show was &quot;powerful&quot; and that it had a &quot;real grip on people.&quot;</p>
<p>After the show, the presidential party climbed on stage to shake hands with cast members and to go backstage to meet the parents of the author, Jonathan Larson, who died unexpectedly in January, 1996, of an aortic aneurysm.</p>
<p>The cast of &quot;Rent&quot; performed the show's anthem &quot;Seasons of Love&quot; at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago.</p>
<p>In the evening, Chelsea and her friends planned to see &quot;Bring In 'Da Noise, Bring In 'Da Funk&quot; while her parents took in &quot;Chicago.&quot;</p>
<p>Chelsea turned 17 Thursday but spent the day quietly, going to classes as usual at Sidwell Friends, an exclusive private school where she is in her senior year.</p>
<p>The president and first lady flew to New York on a small C-20 Gulfstream, while Chelsea and her friends flew on the White House press plane, a slightly larger C-9.</p>
<p>Since her father became president, Chelsea has been to New York at least twice. In December 1995 she and her mother attended the Radio City Music Hall Christmas show. Last August, Chelsea attended her father's birthday party and a fund-raising celebration at Radio City.</p>
<p>In March she plans to accompany her mother on a tour of several African countries during her spring break from school.</p>
<p>White House officials familiar with her studies say she is showing an interest in taking pre-med classes when she starts college next autumn.</p>
<p>Chelsea visited a variety of Ivy League schools, including Harvard, Brown and Yale, as well as Stanford in California.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
