<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413057" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Icopal bids for Phoenix.</title>
<headline>Icopal bids for Phoenix.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish building materials company Icopal on Saturday became the fourth bidder for roadbuilder Phoenix Contractors with an offer of 875 million crowns, national news agancy Ritzau said.  </p>
<p>The offer trumped a bid of 820 million Danish crowns by Norway's Rieber and Son, the preferred suitor of Phoenix management.</p>
<p>Institutional investors in Phoenix favour a rival bidder, Danish construction and chemicals group Superfos which has said that it will not raise its offer of 808 million crowns but nevertheless says it is still in the race.</p>
<p>A committee of Phoenix shareholders backing the Rieber bid said on Saturday that it would report Icopal to Danish competition watchdogs, saying that the firm was working with Superfos to neutralise Phoenix as a business rival.  </p>
<p>&quot;With hindsight we can now understand that Icopal hid itself behind Superfos all the time, in their attempts to kill a succesful competitor in the roofing and asphalt market,&quot; a committee statement said.</p>
<p>Icopal on Friday denied rumours that it was working in concert with Superfos, saying that it only entered the fray at such a late stage -- six weeks after Rieber's opening bid and six days before the expiry of the offer deadline -- in an attempt to keep Phoenix in Danish hands,</p>
<p>&quot;We would not come limping in so late if we had a deal with Superfos,&quot; managing director Hans C. Andreasen told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Saturday's Icopal offer extends the bid deadline by a further four weeks.</p>
<p>Phoenix on Fridau said that the takeover struggle, launched by Rieber on January 15, had already gone on long enough and further complications would heighten staff insecurity and jeopardise the firm's ability to do business.</p>
<p>Another suitor, Danish building contractor Marius Pedersen said last week that it would not raise its offer of 776 million crowns.</p>
<p>The most-traded Phoenix C-share closed up 10 Danish crowns at 675 on Friday.  </p>
<p>Superfos was up 13 Danish crowns to 788 and Icopal rose 30 Danish crowns to 1,550.</p>
<p>--Steve Weizman, Copenhagen newsroom +45 33969650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
