<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413081" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: U.N.'s Annan said unaware of Iraq oil sales talks.</title>
<headline>U.N.'s Annan said unaware of Iraq oil sales talks.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan is unaware of any Iraqi talks aimed at enabling Baghdad to increase its income from its oil-for-food deal with the United Nations, a U.N. spokesman said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;The secretary-general says there are no discussions that he has had with the Iraqis about raising the ceiling over six months,&quot; Annan's spokesman Fred Eckhard told Reuters.</p>
<p>Eckhard was responding to a statement by Iraqi Oil Minister Amir Muhammad Rasheed, who said in Baghdad on Friday that Iraq was negotiating with the United Nations to increase its income under U.N. resolution 986.</p>
<p>The resolution allows Baghdad $2 billion worth of oil exports over six months to offset the impact of U.N. sanctions imposed after Iraq's invasion of Kuwait in 1990. It went into effect on December 10 last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Under 986 the U.N. secretary-general is to prepare a report after 90 days (of implementation), that is two weeks from now, suggesting an increase in the money which is $1 billion,&quot; Rasheed told a news conference in Baghdad.</p>
<p>Eckhard said Iraq was free to increase or decrease its allotment on its own, without U.N. approval, so long as it remained under a billion-dollar ceiling for any three-month period.</p>
<p>&quot;For example, Iraq wanted to sell more oil last week because prices dropped,&quot; he said, stating it was already allowed to do that.</p>
<p>Rasheed said Iraqi Foreign Minister Mohammed Saeed al-Sahaf was in New York to raise the issue with Annan. &quot;We are asking it should be a very good increase,&quot; he said. Annan, however, was in Paris on Friday and Saturday for talks with French officials.</p>
<p>Rasheed said out of $1 billion worth of exports Iraq is allowed to pump to the outside world over the first 90 days Iraq's share would be $660 million &quot;which is not enough to meet the very miniumum basic needs of its people&quot;.</p>
<p>Some 30 per cent of Iraq's oil money goes to a U.N. fund to compensate the victims of Iraq's 1990 invasion of Kuwait. Iraq has also to meet other U.N. costs.</p>
<p>Rasheed said the value of Iraq's partial oil exports under the U.N. deal had reached $864 million on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;And until March 13 we hope to export what will be worth $1.70 billion,&quot; Rasheed said.</p>
<p>He said that on Thursday Iraq put $611 million in its escrow account in New York. He said about $400 million would remain for Iraq after deducting 30 per cent for the 1991 Gulf War reparations and other U.N. costs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
