<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413009" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fourteen children overdose at Masschusetts dance.</title>
<headline>Fourteen children overdose at Masschusetts dance.</headline>
<dateline>WOBURN, Mass. 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fourteen children aged 12 to 17 were in Boston-area hospitals on Saturday after apparently overdosing on a muscle relaxant late on Friday at a dance, police said.</p>
<p>Ten of the victims, mostly girls, were in critical condition, many of them on life-support systems, according to hospital officials.</p>
<p>Police found some of the muscle relaxants, called baclosen, and an empty bottle at the &quot;Teen Supreme&quot; dance at the Boys and Girls Club in Woburn, Massachusetts, about 20 miles (32 km) north of Boston.</p>
<p>&quot;They were passing out the pills and they just started falling,&quot; Woburn Police officer Paul Lucero told Reuters.</p>
<p>Police were investigating how the children got the drug, which one hospital official said is commonly used to treat multiple sclerosis.</p>
<p>Local reports said that the victims, mostly eighth grade girls from Kennedy Junior High School in Woburn, apparently ingested multiple doses of the drug shortly before going to the dance.</p>
<p>Seven boys and girls aged 12 to 17 were in serious condition and one was in good condition at Children's Hospital in Boston, spokeswoman Cindy Rovelle said.</p>
<p>Two girls were in serious condition and one girl was in stable condition at the Lahey Hitchcock Medical Centre in Burlington, north of Boston, spokeswoman Christine McDonald said.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe the ones we have are around 14,&quot; McDonald said.</p>
<p>Two girls were in fair condition at Winchester Hospital, also located north of Boston, spokeswoman Deb Trask said. Their ages were not released.</p>
<p>One 13-year-old girl was in serious condition at Massachusetts General Hospital in Boston, a spokeswoman there said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WOBURN, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
