<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413067" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Olivetti sells troubled PC firm.</title>
<headline>Italy's Olivetti sells troubled PC firm.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian information technology company Olivetti said on Saturday it had signed the final contracts for the sale of its loss-making personal computer company to newly-formed Piedmont International.</p>
<p>Olivetti said in a statement that the deal with Piedmont, controlled by U.S. lawyer Edward Gottesman's Centenary Group, was worth between 250 billion to 300 billion lire ($159 million to $190 million).</p>
<p>&quot;The contracts have been concluded according to the agreed schedule and confirm the content of the Heads of Agreement signed by the two companies in January,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The contracts provide that the purchase price of the business and operations of Olivetti Personal Computers is equivalent to the net asset value of the business, as it will result from an independent certification,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>&quot;Olivetti will be entitled to receive as additional purchase price a further payment based on a percentage of the company's profits over the next three years.&quot;</p>
<p>The two companies will embark on a long-term partnership. Olivetti will purchase a 12 percent stake in Piedmont and be entitled to name one member of the firm's board of directors, the statement said.</p>
<p>Piedmont will run the Italian side of Olivetti PCs through an Italian subsidiary while its international distribution and marketing activities will be carried out by a Dutch subsidiary.</p>
<p>The new company will use the Olivetti trademark and trade name for its PC products under a licensing agreement that will last for 20 years, with an option to renew it for another 20 years. Olivetti will receive royalties on revenues.</p>
<p>Analysts have said that Piedmont faces an uphill struggle in turning around the ailing fortunes of Olivetti PCs, with the world computer industry consolidating rapidly and the European industry littered with the failures of famous names.</p>
<p>Olivetti PCs has struggled to turn a profit in the 1990s, and analysts have said it was unlikely to have reached annual sales of 800,000 PCs required to break even in 1996. Estimates put sales at only just over 700,000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
