<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413023" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republicans probe Clinton banking fund-raiser - report.</title>
<headline>Republicans probe Clinton banking fund-raiser - report.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the widening controversy over President Bill Clinton's possible exchange of access for campaign contributions, Republicans are now investigating whether Democrats solicited donations from bankers to influence bankruptcy policy, the New York Times reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>Banking officials told the Times that a $1 million Clinton fund-raiser last summer was sold to the banking industry as a chance to talk with Brady Williamson, a bankruptcy lawyer Clinton appointed to head the commission on fixing the bankruptcy system.</p>
<p>Bankers, lawyers and consultants say that veteran Democratic fund-raiser William A. Brandt, who organised the dinner in the posh Chicago suburb of Winnetka, explicitly told them that attendance at the $10,000 a plate dinner was a chance to meet Williamson.</p>
<p>Philip Corwin, a banking consultant, said that Brandt had told him &quot;banks hadn't given enough&quot; and that they could not count on their &quot;Republican friends in Congress&quot; to get what they wanted, the Times reported.</p>
<p>Brandt told the Times that the charges were &quot;utter baloney&quot; and a &quot;tawdry&quot; Washington political scheme aimed at discrediting the commission.</p>
<p>Sen. Charles E. Grassley (R-Iowa) began an investigation on Thursday, the Times said. Grassley heads a judicial oversight subcommittee. He said he was investigating whether the fund-raiser violated the Hatch Act, which prohibits non-elected federal officials from using their titles to raise money, the Times said.</p>
<p>For his part, Williamson said that when he heard a rumour that Brandt was using him as a selling point for the dinner he told Brandt that he could not do that.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
