<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413012" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ex-FBI agent pleads guilty to spying for Russia.</title>
<headline>Ex-FBI agent pleads guilty to spying for Russia.</headline>
<byline>James Vicini</byline>
<dateline>ALEXANDRIA, Va. 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former FBI agent and supervisor Earl Pitts pleaded guilty on Friday to two espionage charges for selling secret U.S. national security security documents to Moscow from 1987 to 1996.</p>
<p>Immediately after the court hearing, U.S. Attorney Helen Fahey held a news conference and announced that a guilty plea would be entered on Monday in a second major espionage case involving accused CIA spy Harold Nicholson.</p>
<p>Fahey declined to give further details about the expected guilty plea by Nicholson, who has been accused of selling secrets to Moscow and was the highest ranking CIA official ever charged with espionage.</p>
<p>Pitts, only the second FBI agent ever to be indicted for espionage in what has been called the most damaging spy case in FBI's 89-year history, admitted his guilt at a court hearing.</p>
<p>Pitts, a 13-year FBI veteran, was arrested on Dec. 18 for passing vital national security secrets to Russian intelligence agencies in exchange for $224,000, betraying some of the FBI's most sensitive operations.</p>
<p>Pitts, said to be motivated by the money, was caught as a result of a 16-month undercover FBI sting operation. He was dismissed by the FBI in January.</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge T.S. Ellis, who has presided over the case, accepted the guilty plea that had been negotiated by federal prosecutors and defence lawyers.</p>
<p>Asked by the judge during the 90-minute hearing how he would plead, Pitts replied in a firm, clear voice, &quot;Guilty, your honour.&quot; He stood before the judge wearing green prison garb.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, your honour, I did,&quot; Pitts said, admitting he provided classified information to persons he believed to be agents of the Soviet Union and Russian governments.</p>
<p>Pitts, who had been in the FBI's New York City unit responsible for catching Russian spies, was charged in a 12-count indictment with attempted espionage, conspiracy to commit espionage, communication of classified information and conveyance of government property without authorisation.</p>
<p>In return for the guilty pleas to the two most-serious espionage charges, prosecutors agreed to drop the remaining 10 charges.    Pitts, 43, faces a maximum punishment of life in</p>
<p>prison, a $500,000 fine and forfeiture of all money gained from his spying.</p>
<p>Judge Ellis set sentencing for June 20 and said to Pitts, &quot;It is uncertain exactly what sentence you will receive.&quot;</p>
<p>Under federal sentencing guidelines defence attorneys said Pitts was expected to receive 15 to 20 years in prison. Justice Department officials had earlier confirmed the 20-year figure.</p>
<p>A trial for Pitts had been scheduled for April 21. Prosecutors will avoid a trial, and the potential disclosure of classified information, because of the plea deal.</p>
<p>According to court documents, Pitts spied for Moscow in New York from 1987 to 1992, and in 1995 and 1996 he dealt with U.S. agents posing as Russian spies in the undercover operation.</p>
<p>His Soviet and Russian handlers paid him $124,000 and set up a $100,000 reserve fund in exchange for U.S. secrets, the FBI said. Pitts also received $65,000 from FBI agents during the sting operation.</p>
<p>Law enforcement officials said Pitts, a lawyer, may have decided to negotiate the best deal possible because of the overwhelming evidence against him. They doubted whether Pitts has any information that would be of value to investigators in assessing the damage from his activities.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the plea deal, Pitts agreed to cooperate with investigators and to submit to government lie-detector tests. If he tells the government all he knows, prosecutors agreed not to bring any further charges, including possible tax violations.</p>
<p>One final condition of the plea agreement required Pitts to have no contact with any foreign government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALEXANDRIA, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
