<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413141" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Mandela kicks off first S.E. Asian tour in Manila.</title>
<headline>Mandela kicks off first S.E. Asian tour in Manila.</headline>
<byline>Raju Gopalakrishnan</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela, accompanied for the first time on a state visit by his Mozambican sweetheart, arrived in Manila on Saturday at the start of his maiden tour of southeast Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;This part of the world has made fantastic achievments economically and politically,&quot; Mandela told reporters. &quot;I have looked forward to coming to this region because of the enormous lessons which we can learn in trying to raise the living conditions of our people.&quot;</p>
<p>Mandela and Graca Machel, the 51-year-old widow of former Mozambican president Somora Machel, were greeted by a 21-gun salute and a welcome with full military honours at the presidential palace in Manila.</p>
<p>Philippine president Fidel Ramos hailed Mandela as &quot;one of the towering figures of the century&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;His struggle changed the face of race relations across the world,&quot; Ramos told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Visiting the Republic of the Philippines is the fulfillment of a long and cherished dream, an unforgettable experience,&quot; Mandela wrote in the visitors book at the palace.</p>
<p>Mandela introduced Graca, dressed in maroon and gold, as his &quot;companion&quot; to Ramos, who smiled and shook hands with her.</p>
<p>Asked by a reporter later if a wedding was in the offing, the 78-year-old Mandela said: &quot;My cultural background does not permit me to discuss this question with people young enough to be my children or grandchildren&quot;.</p>
<p>Ramos, standing next to him, laughed and clapped, and Mandela would not speak more on the subject.</p>
<p>Mandela was divorced from his second wife Winnie last year after a bitter court battle in which he acknowledged she had been unfaithful to him. His first wife Evelyn lives in the rural south coast Transkei, where he has built a retirement home.</p>
<p>Both Mandela and Graca have previously said they have no plans to marry.</p>
<p>South African and Philippine officials also signed an agreement to expand cooperation in trade and investment and to grant each other &quot;Most Favoured Nation&quot; status in trade relations.</p>
<p>Ramos said investment links between the two countries could include projects in the energy, mining and railway sectors but details still had to be worked out.</p>
<p>Mandela was to meet former president Corazon Aquino later on Saturday and attend a state banquet. On Sunday, he will address members of the Makati Business Club, the country's premier group of businessmen.</p>
<p>He leaves for Brunei on Monday and will visit Malaysia and Singapore before returning to South Africa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
